<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Changeset discussion (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Contributor: infeeeee Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Szia! Üdv az OpenStreeetMapen! Nem egyirányú utcákat nem kell jelölni, ha nincs rajta a oneway=yes, akkor az azt jelenti, hogy két irányú. Akkor hasznos ezt jelölni, ha valami miatt más lenne a következetes, pl. korábban egyirányú volt, vagy csak egy szakasz kétirányú, ilyenek. https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Key:oneway#oneway_=_no Ha kérdésed merülne fel, a magyar szerkesztő közösség elérhetőségeit megtalálod ezen az oldalon: https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Hungary/Közösség További jó térképezést! Date: 2024-07-08T14:46:38+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153662334</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153662334#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-08T14:46:38+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: vasony Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Szia! Mi a törlés oka? Földhivatal és a tervek is ezen a néven ismerik ezt a belső utat. Tamás Date: 2024-07-08T13:31:11+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153533770</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153533770#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-08T13:31:11+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: gabro00 Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Szia! A sima Esri néhol frissebb, mint a Bing (tippre 1 éves sincs), ez a mocsár pl. már nincs ott az Esri-n, de a többin látszik: https://www.openstreetmap.org/way/1299892985 Date: 2024-07-08T06:45:11+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153682475</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153682475#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-08T06:45:11+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: vasony Discussion Comment No.: 2 Comment: nincs válasz, leszedtem a házszámot. Date: 2024-07-08T03:46:02+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/152759387</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/152759387#comment_2</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-08T03:46:02+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: vasony Discussion Comment No.: 2 Comment: No answer, reverted modification Date: 2024-07-08T03:43:00+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153292141</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153292141#comment_2</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-08T03:43:00+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: bkil Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: The question is: is there or is there not a path on the ground? If the property owner has not fenced the property away, it is legally &quot;considered private property not closed down from public access&quot; and it should remain as a path on OSM as well. Editors on the ground will eventually resurvey this and redraw this based on whether they see it on the ground or not regardless of how many times you remove it remotely. Date: 2024-07-07T22:53:16+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153666736</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153666736#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-07T22:53:16+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: dueyduey Discussion Comment No.: 4 Comment: Yes, the English version. I don't remember the phrasing, but I definitely looked at 'tap' and decided against it based on the description and the pictures. Note that I did not know that the &quot;classic blue ones&quot; work from the main supply pipes, I actually (wrongly) believed to know otherwise. water_well sample in picture being blue didn't help either :-) Date: 2024-07-07T13:03:52+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153648764</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153648764#comment_4</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-07T13:03:52+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: sugarbotond Discussion Comment No.: 4 Comment: Személyesen láttam igen. Date: 2024-07-05T12:49:29+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153429198</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153429198#comment_4</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-05T12:49:29+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: Hungarian_user Discussion Comment No.: 3 Comment: Ha jól látom, ezt figyelmen kívül lehet hagyni, mert az adat hibás. Date: 2024-07-05T11:19:07+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/69661096</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/69661096#comment_3</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-05T11:19:07+02:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: vasony Discussion Comment No.: 2 Comment: bocs, én néztem be, jó az. Date: 2024-07-03T20:58:27+02:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153514154</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/153514154#comment_2</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-03T20:58:27+02:00</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>