<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Changeset discussion (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Contributor: Faller Gyula Discussion Comment No.: 3 Comment: Párhuzamosan szerkesztettünk, és nem vettük észre, hogy ütközni fogunk. Kiakasztó emiatt elveszteni rengeteg munkát! Ha észrevettem volna, hogy ütközés várható, elkerültem volna. Date: 2023-12-05T06:08:58+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144765138</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144765138#comment_3</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-05T06:08:58+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: Faller Gyula Discussion Comment No.: 3 Comment: Ja, már át is állítottad! Rendben! :) Date: 2023-12-05T06:02:45+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144445331</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144445331#comment_3</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-05T06:02:45+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: Hufkratzer Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Hi, Please tag riding arenas differently from riding centres. https://www.openstreetmap.org/way/1228495467 https://www.openstreetmap.org/way/1228495468 https://www.openstreetmap.org/way/1228495469 are riding arenas and should be tagged leisure=pitch + sport=equestrian (the last one is not really an arena but just round pen, but they are usually also tagged like arenas). iD has a separate preset for riding arenas. https://www.openstreetmap.org/node/11392666605 is for the whole riding centre. This is ok, but there should be only one object (node or way) tagged with leisure=horse_riding for every riding centre. Related information: https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Tag:leisure%3Dhorse_riding https://www.facebook.com/people/Sátorkő-Lovasiskola/100063673595807 https://www.openstreetmap.org/relation/16784595 Date: 2023-12-04T21:51:41+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144730826</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144730826#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-04T21:51:41+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: vasony Discussion Comment No.: 5 Comment: OK. Érdekes, hogy nem adott ütközést ilyen esetben, szerintem kellett volna. Date: 2023-12-03T19:56:14+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144641658</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144641658#comment_5</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-03T19:56:14+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: Spush Discussion Comment No.: 5 Comment: Megnéztem és zárva van, de a tábla valóban kint van. A POI-ból csinálok egy Zöldségest, ami 10 méterrel odébb van. 1 órát sétáltam a környéken. Date: 2023-12-02T17:26:23+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144612889</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144612889#comment_5</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-02T17:26:23+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: bkil Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Ki is van táblázva a terepen a változás? Ha nem, official_name is lehet. Kérjük, hogy mindig szerepeljen az old_name alatt az előző név. Date: 2023-12-02T11:45:26+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144686677</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144686677#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-02T11:45:26+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: bkil Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Do you speak Hungarian? This path was checked recently and still existed back then. It was marked as smoothness=horrible. Maybe it has poor visibility? I have reverted this until you respond. Date: 2023-12-02T11:41:44+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144659392</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144659392#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-02T11:41:44+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: BáthoryPéter Discussion Comment No.: 7 Comment: Sejtettem, hogy ilyesmi lehet a háttérben ;) De ez most egy jó megoldásnak tűnik. Date: 2023-12-01T11:53:40+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144619616</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144619616#comment_7</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-01T11:53:40+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: bkil Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Tisztelt szerkesztő! Ezt visszavontam, mert számtalan objektumot törölt magyarázat vagy csere nélkül, vélelmezhetően véletlenül. Kérem amennyiben még aktuálisak az újonnan felvett itemek, kérem válogassa ki, hogy mi maradjon, és szerkessze fel újra. Date: 2023-12-01T09:33:16+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144650241</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144650241#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-01T09:33:16+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: bkil Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: A Pajzs utca valóban át van nevezve ezen a kis szakaszon arra, hogy Máriahegy tanya, így is van kitáblázva a helyszínen? Date: 2023-11-30T17:30:10+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/94919093</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/94919093#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-30T17:30:10+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: jeslop Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Hi Szerkesztő: Please remember to provide appropriate comments to your changesets. A simple &quot;.&quot; is not very helpful for other users and for those who want to review your edits. Read https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Good_changeset_comments for more information. Regards Fordítson a DeepL segítségével Szia Szerkesztő: Kérlek, ne felejtsd el megadni a megfelelő megjegyzéseket a módosítási készleteidhez. Egy egyszerű &quot;.&quot; nem túl hasznos a többi felhasználó és azok számára, akik át akarják nézni a szerkesztéseidet. További információkért olvasd el a https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Good_changeset_comments címet. Üdvözlettel Jesús López OpenStreetMap Foundation Data Working Group Date: 2023-11-30T16:24:40+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144434582</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144434582#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-30T16:24:40+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: Bálint Discussion Comment No.: 2 Comment: Szia, Fejből most nem emlékszem, hogy van-e elválasztás, ha legközelebb arra járok, megnézem. Date: 2023-11-30T16:24:26+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144618788</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144618788#comment_2</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-30T16:24:26+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: infeeeee Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: It was already mapped: https://www.openstreetmap.org/node/7728669887 Date: 2023-11-30T11:42:56+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144605326</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144605326#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-30T11:42:56+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: infeeeee Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Hello! The exact same text was written in the official_name, I will revert this as well. Date: 2023-11-28T13:48:38+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542802</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542802#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-28T13:48:38+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: infeeeee Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: This was already mapped: https://www.openstreetmap.org/relation/8180339 I will revert this changeset Date: 2023-11-28T13:43:11+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542543</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542543#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-28T13:43:11+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: infeeeee Discussion Comment No.: 4 Comment: And to change the name, it clearly says, you have to change the wikidata page. You can overwrite the name without messing up other tags, if you scroll down a bit under &quot;Tags&quot; in iD, the editor you use. But I think these names should go to official_name tag instead. Common people not necessarily call them this way: https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Key:official_name Do you speak Hungarian? Date: 2023-11-28T13:39:06+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542512</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144542512#comment_4</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-28T13:39:06+01:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Contributor: user_5359 Discussion Comment No.: 1 Comment: Hello! Please have a look on http://www.osm.org/node/11377801733 (one of three objects). What is the mean of the tag Nixbród dűlő = Kertváros? Date: 2023-11-28T09:27:52+01:00</title>
        <link>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144473788</link>
        <guid>https://www.openstreetmap.org/changeset/144473788#comment_1</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-28T09:27:52+01:00</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>