<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Was an eventful and enjoyable #offdem24 and #fossdem24 .... Ranging from intermingling with people operating security-sensitiv helplines using #chatmail to discussing email standards like the evolving openpgp cryptorefresh ... And then several more underground happenings which might lead to even more surprises than are already developing .... with many of us agreeing and appreciating that we are rather engaged with lots interesting communities and folks rather than corporate structures.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 20:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>When you are interacting with this account here you are actually interacting with a bunch of folks involved in various ways in project happenings, who are often following interactions via a deltachat mastodon bot that relays messages into a chat group from where the reply is triggered. Many of the @delta members have an #offlinefirst approach to networking so mostly use the chat group to interact. #DidYouKnowDepartment</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We just refined the user facing &amp;quot;download&amp;quot; page to include instant #chatmail onboarding instructions https://get.delta.chat Did you know there also are first independent #chatmail setups from friendly third parties, eg https://mehl.cloud and https://mailchat.pl/ all nicely interoperable and fast? #chatmail actively develops here https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail/pulse/monthly ....</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Not only are we user-testing app release candidates with various groups ahead of putting it to stores (thanks to the many helpers from across the globe!) but we are also intertwining design decisions with early user-testing with actual groups in risk (big shoutout to @Xeniax !) -- see here for an example which showcases that the question on which &amp;quot;attacker&amp;quot; to focus on is a fundamental question and you can not meaningfully discuss &amp;quot;security&amp;quot; without it. https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-android/pull/2916#issuecomment-1883086981</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111726355777273276</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111726355777273276</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#37c3 was a blast ... Lots of enjoyable and surprising chats and developments and new collabs, affinities and synergies .... Wishing you all happy transitions and phasings into new beginnings with accelerated escape velocities from the many mainsteam catastrophical developments 💜 ( generated image was removed due to fair critique ... Peace :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111676122232845942</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111676122232845942</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The #37c3 delta chat group size is now at 67 members ... Still no glitches except a bit of confusion with someone switching from one account to another and then another :) You can indeed #migrate from a https://nine.testrun.org account to another email address and keep all your guaranteed encrypted chats ....Other will notice and autoaccept your mail adress change ... See https://delta.chat/en/2022-09-14-aeap for how this works. #RightToExit #RightToMigrate</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111666157750901070</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111666157750901070</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 22:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The #37c3 delta chat group has now 48 members, all using guaranteed end to end encryption and several games and apps .... So far without a glitch, no &amp;quot;couldn&amp;#39;t decrypt&amp;quot; errors, everything lightning fast, some people using multiple devices with their account, 30 people joining during live onboarding on day1 and using a editor together in the chat (like cryptpad without a server basically). Seems like all the milestones of 2023 (guaranteed e2ee, web apps, chatmail) are ... Actually playing out ;)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111662918305095365</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111662918305095365</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>More #deltachat folks are arriving at #37c3 today and tomorrow .... We I&amp;#39;ll be around #komona in hall H ... On day 1 we intend to do a #chatmail hands on session probably in the evening. There is usually a #komona billboard with planned sessions .... Anyways, everyone, please have enjoyable travels and a wonderful (as can be these days, for some it&amp;#39;s gruesome) beginnings of 2024 ... See you at 37c3 or elsewhere!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111641006313294038</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111641006313294038</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 12:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#chatmail is not a replacement for Whatsapp in the traditional sense. It&amp;#39;s a small machine that can be tweaked in many ways. The tweakability of the e-mail system is in it&amp;#39;s DNA and practises ... that is the antithesis to WA if you like :) What drives nine.testrun.org, the first public chatmail service, is fully visible at https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail -- a minimalist config and setup, some python modules and tests, standard postfix/dovecot. co-incidentally pretty fast but there is a twist ;) Delta Chat messaging screen with echo-bot: One said says &quot;Hi&quot;, the bot answers &quot;Hi&quot;. One sight says &quot;Oh!&quot; and 0.24 seconds later the bot says &quot;Oh!&quot; One says &quot;That was fast&quot; and the bot answers. All 6 messages were typed, received and seen in 4.16 seconds overall.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111586633840591278</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111586633840591278</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 21:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Today, we are unveiling chatmail services, making onboarding with #deltachat a breeze, with peace of mind. #chatmail marks a major milestone, answering the practical question of &amp;quot;where can i get a deltachat-ready account&amp;quot; for myself and friends? Read more on https://delta.chat/en/2023-12-13-chatmail The chatmail logo, an @ with a speech bubble.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 18:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Seems google/apple&amp;#39;s push notifications services are regularly queried by state authorities for obtaining user data -- see this german @netzpolitik_feed https://netzpolitik.org/2023/push-dienste-behoerden-fragen-apple-und-google-nach-nutzern-von-messenger-apps/ -- #deltachat only uses apple&amp;#39;s push notifications on iOS for &amp;quot;heartbeat&amp;quot; services -- to ensure the app can show messages for their user (and many users are asking for tighter integration). On Android, Desktop and #ubuntutouch platforms currently no push notifications are used or needed, also no heartbeat ones.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 09:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you are looking for alternatives to Android, then #ubuntutouch from https://mastodon.social/@ubports is a mobile platform where @lk108 implemented the nicely working DeltaTouch app which also just released guaranteed end-to-end encryption, being very much on par with the other platforms, see https://social.tchncs.de/@lk108/111517563343219731 Pixel3a phone with UbuntuTouch operating system and running DeltaTouch app showing a chatlist with Lothar, a deltatouch group, a registration chat with ubuntuone, and some other chats.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Some in our communities are apparently having fun ... taking no sides ;) (Credits: @matiu_bidule) Two fighting, one saying &quot;i prefer signal&quot;, the other &quot;i prefer signal&quot; and a third sitting on a chair with popcorn saying &quot;je prefer delta chat&quot;</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111504693729563998</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111504693729563998</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We have reports from people for whom delta chat works while signal shows &amp;quot;no internet&amp;quot; ... Various states are throttling traffic all across the planet and you need to have a robust networking layer to provide service. Delta Chat is offline-first, ignores DNS outages, can be combined with Tor or Tails. It is trying to make live easier for people who are already in stress and need a reliable messenging experience. It is project practise to keep the least wealthily connected in focus.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111471516437632965</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111471516437632965</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 13:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The 1.42 app releases are rolling into the stores, providing a major security upgrade that was long in the brewing and testing: guaranteed end-to-end encryption, protecting against compromised servers or networks (MITM attacks). The releases also enable multi-device synchronization of pinned/accepted/blocked/muted chat states, a new global gallery for desktop and many bug fixes and little improvements .... #deltachat https://delta.chat/en/2023-11-23-jumbo-42 a checkmark on a green background the shape of a flower or cloud.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111460913692845091</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111460913692845091</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 16:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>new heise article (german), with this translated summary: &amp;quot;Delta Chat is definitely worth a longer look. The app harmoniously combines chat as a form of communication with the tried-and-tested medium of email and even offers some features that you won&amp;#39;t find in other messengers, such as small &amp;quot;webxdc&amp;quot; apps that you can embed directly in chats and use with conversation partners. It&amp;#39;s a shame that Delta Chat didn&amp;#39;t exist before WhatsApp and the like.&amp;quot; Paywalled link: https://www.heise.de/ratgeber/Per-E-Mail-chatten-Delta-Chat-als-Messenger-und-Mailsoftware-nutzen-9432335.html Fazit Delta Chat stellt eine interessante Alternative oder Erganzung zu traditioneller Chat- und Mailsoftware dar. Gegeniiber anderen Messengern sind die wichtigsten Vorteile der App ihre Dezentralitiit und dass man per E-Mail praktisch jeden erreicht. Ob Delta Chat Ihre Mail-App ganz oder teilweise ersetzen kann, héngt vor allem davon ab, wie Sie E-Mails nutzen. Einen langeren Blick ist Delta Chat jedenfalls wert. Die App verheiratet die Kommunikationsform Chat und das bewahrte Medium E-Mail harmonisch und bietet sogar einige Features, die man bei anderen Messengern vergeblich sucht, etwa kleine &quot;webxdc&quot;-Apps, die man direkt in Chats einbetten und mit Gesprachspartnern nutzen kann. Schade, dass Delta Chat nicht schon vor WhatsApp und Co. existierte. (syt)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111454694903470186</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111454694903470186</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Apart from the currently 53 #webxdc apps in the &amp;quot;xstore&amp;quot; (say hi to xstore@testrun.org) there are apparently at least double as many in circulation .... people post random little webxdc apps which then get used throughout several chats -- it&amp;#39;s wild out there and no central platforms in sight ;) a screenshot of a Delta Chat community group chat where one user is saying: &quot;| suppose it depends on the size of the app if the app is small the best is just keep the copy of the app inside the app because js-zip is no that small, but if the app it is big then it is better use js-zip. For the poll app | think is it just better the copy way.&quot; and the next message quotes an app icon for the &quot;Delta apps&quot; app and say: &quot;BTW I have like more than 100 apps in that app&quot;.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111291740636114659</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111291740636114659</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you like delta chat and know somebody experienced with iOS developments please send them our way, retoots welcome. With all other platforms.we have at least two devs engaged but would like to up our iOS game .... Even advising on a day-per-week or loose pro-bono basis could be helpful but someone who gets their hand dirty would be even better. Remote paid job available. For more background see https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob and adjacent recent blog posts.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111194512214036910</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111194512214036910</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Last month was cleanup-time with Delta Chat Android and Desktop development -- lots of triaging, resolving and closing of issues and pull requests ... Android: 26 merged PRs, 5 open PRs, 49 closed issues Desktop: 42 merged PRs, 2 open PRs, 25 closed issues, 4 new issues many thanks to @r10s @treefit and @adbenitez who drove the efforts, as well as to all the helpers! rumors have it that we are preparing for some bigger things to arrive in the next couple of months ;) github activity screen for deltachat-desktop showing: - 42 merged pull requests - 2 opened pull requests - 25 closed issues - 4 new issues</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111155262034725904</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111155262034725904</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 17:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We just published the new &amp;quot;Encryption and Security&amp;quot; FAQ section: https://delta.chat/en/help#encryption-and-security We also added more info regarding &amp;quot;verfiied groups&amp;quot; that guarantee safe E2E-encryption even if servers are malfeasant or compromised: https://delta.chat/en/help#verifiedchats #deltachat #security</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111064803824610765</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111064803824610765</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>