<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>We got note of three #deltachat articles from different angles the last days: Roskomvoboda, human rights org in russia, interviewing @Xeniax about our recent interaction with the russian telco authorities. https://roskomsvoboda.org/ru/post/delta-chat-snova-otkazal-roskomnadzoru/ @unixtippse about &amp;quot;do&amp;#39;s and don&amp;#39;ts&amp;quot; after re-engaging with Delta Chat happily. https://binblog.de/2024/06/15/deltachat-first-dos-first-donts/ @durian about Signal and &amp;quot;Delta Chat for anarchists&amp;quot; https://phlanticap.noblogs.org/delta-chat-for-anarchists/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112621284535468799</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112621284535468799</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Back to more interesting matters than these authoritarian #chatcontrol dreams (don&amp;#39;t you bet many &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; companies are lining up to sell automated policing?) ... Thanks to @dvzrv there now is a rather official #deltachat #arch package https://archlinux.org/packages/extra/any/deltachat-desktop 💜</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112609978982660781</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112609978982660781</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 15:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>As you know, governmental forces within the EU, the US, the UK, Russia and others are in a hot competition on who gets to be the first to subvert end-to-end encryption. A few days ago, we got another letter from Roskomnadzor, the #russia telco authority, to help them get at user data or metadata for #deltachat users. But there is no central registry of e-mail addresses, messages or decryption keys. So we declined. Sorry, not sorry. A letter from merlinux GmbH to ROSKOMNADZOR Russian Federal Service for Supervision in the Sphere of Telecom, Information Technologies and Mass Communications per e-mail: 97-fz@rkn.gov.ru Freiburg, June 13th 2024 Your request for registration of Delta Chat regarding provided services in Russia Dear Sirs and Madams, on June 11th 2024 we received your request by e-mail to delta@merlinux.eu to register for provided messaging services in Russia for the application Delta Chat whose developments we indeed facilitate and distribute to app stores and many platforms. If we understand your request correctly, you also requested access to decryption keys and access to user data. However, Delta Chat is an e-mail application which lets users choose their e-mail providers at their own discretion. There is no central registry of e-mail addresses and we have no access to message contents, let alone decryption keys which only exist on user devices. We therefore kindly request that you strike us from your list of service providers. best regards and thanks, holger krekel, managing director, merlinux GmbH</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112608426988613191</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112608426988613191</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 08:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>An enjoyable and fruitful #OpenPGP email 2024 summit closing up .... with many standardization efforts roughly agreed between several players: maximizing metadata protection (IETF header protection effort), ecosystem transition V4-&amp;gt;V6 and PQ-keys (IETF replacement keys), #autocrypt level 2 possibly involving integration of &amp;quot;in-band&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;out of band&amp;quot; key distribution like WKD/HKP which themselves are bound for integration. Believe it or not .... the eco system is moving ;) Flip chart with a rough list of in-band and out-of-band mechanisms and their properties .... Which served as a basis for &quot;replacement key&quot; and &quot;key migration&quot; use cases. Screenshot of toot at https://social.heise.de/@syt/112579950084148138Projector screenshot of header protection session presented and facilitated by dkg (not pictured)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112586666722555707</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112586666722555707</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 12:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The #EUGoingDark 42-point plan for after the election has it all: breaking e2e encryption, &amp;quot;lawful&amp;quot; data retention, prohibiting encrypting metadata, threatening jail to developers for non compliance ..... If we thought authoritarian political currents are moving against privacy then this is an entirely new level ... https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/first-insight-42-key-points-of-the-secret-eugoingdark-surveillance-plan-for-the-new-eu-commission/ P.s. we need more #chatmail servers and contributors so that our #deltachat app-dev conglomerate provides resilience against such authoritarian pipe dreams</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112585131624556931</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112585131624556931</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 05:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Before you ask: communities are massive multi-device setups. Delta&amp;#39;s multi device setup is one of the most robust in the messenger industry. Turns out you can do multi device setups across different people&amp;#39;s devices and #chatmail servers are fine with it. Because why not? Never before did a massive feature like &amp;quot;communities&amp;quot; arrive virtually overnight .... And unlike matrix spaces and discord communities they can be addressed and are not just closed circles where you need to join first.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112573984840006905</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112573984840006905</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 06:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from our direct action R&amp;amp;D #deltalab : Addressable communities. End to end encrypted. No state on servers. Attached: first a chat from deltafans with the hispanohablantes community ... where someone from the Spanish side invites deltafans folks to join it. Second is the Spanish community chatlist where lots of chatting is going on ... Also includes the chat with the deltafans community. Both are independently running and can adress/ be adressed with a messenger UX you already know. A chat from the &quot;deltafans&quot; community with the hispanohablantes community (Spanish speaking ) community .... With an invitation to join it .... All members of both communitirs use guaranteed end to end encryption as the chat has a green checkmark. A chat list of the Spanish speaking community .... It has its own (Spanish speaking) topics and also a chat with &quot;deltafans&quot;</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112573959836159028</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112573959836159028</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 06:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>oopsie! We forgot to mention what is also new with the rolling android 1.46 release: on android you can react with any emoji now. In some real family chats this is more appreciated than all the other news :) Part of a message bubble.wirh two reactions, a heart and a party emoticon</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112560424460902744</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112560424460902744</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 21:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>It&amp;#39;s a crazy property of #chatmail that it practically has zero state: if a Chatmail server is raided, burns to the ground etc but you still have DNS control, you just set it up somewhere and people can continue chatting. In that sense it&amp;#39;s really like a router .... You can turn it off, wipe state, reinstall and turn it on. Theoretically someone might take your address if they arrive first with their login but they would not get readable message content so it would be more annoying than unsafe</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546865028184048</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546865028184048</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 11:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>How to get somewhat sufficient funding remains a question, however economic our approach is. We avoided VC funding and rather went for public tax-based funds because our efforts are driven by what we consider to be in the public interest. It is said that humanity can be morally.judged by how well those are doing who are living through the worst. We often focus on users in imminently dangerous situations but this is not where you can or want to earn money from, let alone surplus.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546239313363496</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546239313363496</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 09:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Delta Chat has &amp;quot;use but minimize&amp;quot; in its DNA when engaging with specs and standards. Autocrypt and #securejoin for guaranteed e2ee, #Chatmail servers with secure chat focus, #webxdc apps with html/css focus .... are the strategic examples of engaging with real internet standards but carefully curating the subset to go for .... Almost all standards are way too complex and unfitting for real world issues ... Our approach is neccessarily pragmatic because we lack resources to be idealism driven</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546158609872476</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112546158609872476</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 08:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A major milestone in our 6+ years long project history: With the rolling 1.46 #deltachat app releases you can start chatting without a pre-existing e-mail address, and benefit from push notifications (instant message delivery) also on Android. We also highlight ways to get in contact with bots and humans, and how #chatmail makes e-mail cheap again https://delta.chat/en/2024-05-31-instant-onboarding</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112542680762630841</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112542680762630841</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Sounds like a bad joke but the EU governing council wants to once again legislate #chatcontrol for it&amp;#39;s 350 million citizens. According to @echo_pbreyer (EU parlamentarian) the legislation wants to force messengers to prevent users from sending images or videos unless they agree them to be scanned, AI-analyzed and potentially reported to police. They apparently want to bring it up for a council vote in June and then negotiate it into a legally binding procedure in the EU https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/let-yourself-be-monitored-eu-governments-to-agree-on-chat-control-with-user-consent/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112485453763175096</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112485453763175096</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A well running de-googled Android system based on and running #FOSS apps? Some are skeptical about Android fundamentally, others point to the existing mass of compatible devices that could participate. Of course Chromium alone makes &amp;quot;de-googling&amp;quot; a tricky effort, as its dependencies on Google run deep. Nevertheless, we are part of the #mobifree effort officially launched today and discussed here from project partners like @microg @NGIZero @daniel @guardianproject https://fosstodon.org/@microg/112480382433515629</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112480820963964489</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112480820963964489</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>While we do have criticisms of its centralized architecture and other choices we highly regard Signal for ushering in a decade of popularizing end-to-end encryption. We particularly appreciate @Mer__edith doing excellent communication work there. It&amp;#39;s disingenuous that tech-billionaires Musk/Dorsey fuel attacks on her and another female colleague, hinting at Telegram as a more secure messenger. Comparing security of Signal with Telegram simply results in &amp;quot;Type Error: incompatible arguments&amp;quot;.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112472201013655160</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112472201013655160</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 07:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>WhatsApp introduces &amp;quot;ask meta ai&amp;quot; in the local chat search bar, and Slack auto-feeds messages to train their LLM robots https://eigenmagic.net/@NewtonMark/112455578857917485 ... Delta Chat is among the shrinking number of messaging applications that does not look at your data except to end-to-end encrypt it and send it over interoperable message transport servers chosen by yourselves and your contacts. #decentralization #security #privacy ftw!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112460581138408023</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112460581138408023</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 06:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The surprising developments in our teams happen &amp;quot;in between&amp;quot; when someone makes an &amp;quot;argument in code&amp;quot; after some inspirational chatting with others, often in cross project and cross-concern manners. Chaotic some might say, not unfittingly. Challenge is to sync it with our release scheduling and reliability discipline. There is this nice saying &amp;quot;you have to become disciplined to be undisciplined&amp;quot; which mirrors practises of how larger #ccc events are arranged in which delta chat grew up :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112456657357156774</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112456657357156774</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#DeltaTouch, the native #UbuntuTouch version of delta chat just announced they are going for full webxdc app support in the summer .... There also is an experimental way to run it on #nixos to get a desktop that is not based on Elektron. Shout-out to @lk108 who is heading this great work even if it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;niche&amp;quot; for now .... DeltaTouch is pretty close to mainline features and arguably the best messenger on that os! https://social.tchncs.de/@deltatouch/112446568813809144</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112446625623024005</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112446625623024005</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 18:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Often overlooked from our &amp;quot;but e-mail!&amp;quot; skeptics: Any sufficiently advanced P2P messenger will eventually re-invent a custom, partial form of e-mail ... because users want to communicate when their apps are offline or not foregrounded and active at the same time. See https://briarproject.org/download-briar-mailbox/ for a recent example. Delta Chat goes the reverse route by providing a secure and interoperable e-mail based messaging experience and then adds P2P tech like https://webxdc.org on top.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112436163856034976</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112436163856034976</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Just to be clear: we value our time and will not engage deeply with people who have a lot of random suggestions and ideas... We don&amp;#39;t have a lack of those on any day :) we are doing continuous user studies, interviews and research with people in repressive, dangerous situations who are using delta chat today. These efforts are usually lead by @Xeniax and entail some scientific rigor as you can expect from a venerable PhD in user research :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427371753153431</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427371753153431</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 09:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>