<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>A major milestone in our 6+ years long project history: With the rolling 1.46 #deltachat app releases you can start chatting without a pre-existing e-mail address, and benefit from push notifications (instant message delivery) also on Android. We also highlight ways to get in contact with bots and humans, and how #chatmail makes e-mail cheap again https://delta.chat/en/2024-05-31-instant-onboarding</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112542680762630841</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112542680762630841</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Sounds like a bad joke but the EU governing council wants to once again legislate #chatcontrol for it&amp;#39;s 350 million citizens. According to @echo_pbreyer (EU parlamentarian) the legislation wants to force messengers to prevent users from sending images or videos unless they agree them to be scanned, AI-analyzed and potentially reported to police. They apparently want to bring it up for a council vote in June and then negotiate it into a legally binding procedure in the EU https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/let-yourself-be-monitored-eu-governments-to-agree-on-chat-control-with-user-consent/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112485453763175096</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112485453763175096</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A well running de-googled Android system based on and running #FOSS apps? Some are skeptical about Android fundamentally, others point to the existing mass of compatible devices that could participate. Of course Chromium alone makes &amp;quot;de-googling&amp;quot; a tricky effort, as its dependencies on Google run deep. Nevertheless, we are part of the #mobifree effort officially launched today and discussed here from project partners like @microg @NGIZero @daniel @guardianproject https://fosstodon.org/@microg/112480382433515629</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112480820963964489</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112480820963964489</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>While we do have criticisms of its centralized architecture and other choices we highly regard Signal for ushering in a decade of popularizing end-to-end encryption. We particularly appreciate @Mer__edith doing excellent communication work there. It&amp;#39;s disingenuous that tech-billionaires Musk/Dorsey fuel attacks on her and another female colleague, hinting at Telegram as a more secure messenger. Comparing security of Signal with Telegram simply results in &amp;quot;Type Error: incompatible arguments&amp;quot;.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112472201013655160</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112472201013655160</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 07:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>WhatsApp introduces &amp;quot;ask meta ai&amp;quot; in the local chat search bar, and Slack auto-feeds messages to train their LLM robots https://eigenmagic.net/@NewtonMark/112455578857917485 ... Delta Chat is among the shrinking number of messaging applications that does not look at your data except to end-to-end encrypt it and send it over interoperable message transport servers chosen by yourselves and your contacts. #decentralization #security #privacy ftw!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112460581138408023</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112460581138408023</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 06:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The surprising developments in our teams happen &amp;quot;in between&amp;quot; when someone makes an &amp;quot;argument in code&amp;quot; after some inspirational chatting with others, often in cross project and cross-concern manners. Chaotic some might say, not unfittingly. Challenge is to sync it with our release scheduling and reliability discipline. There is this nice saying &amp;quot;you have to become disciplined to be undisciplined&amp;quot; which mirrors practises of how larger #ccc events are arranged in which delta chat grew up :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112456657357156774</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112456657357156774</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 13:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#DeltaTouch, the native #UbuntuTouch version of delta chat just announced they are going for full webxdc app support in the summer .... There also is an experimental way to run it on #nixos to get a desktop that is not based on Elektron. Shout-out to @lk108 who is heading this great work even if it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;niche&amp;quot; for now .... DeltaTouch is pretty close to mainline features and arguably the best messenger on that os! https://social.tchncs.de/@deltatouch/112446568813809144</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112446625623024005</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112446625623024005</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 18:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Often overlooked from our &amp;quot;but e-mail!&amp;quot; skeptics: Any sufficiently advanced P2P messenger will eventually re-invent a custom, partial form of e-mail ... because users want to communicate when their apps are offline or not foregrounded and active at the same time. See https://briarproject.org/download-briar-mailbox/ for a recent example. Delta Chat goes the reverse route by providing a secure and interoperable e-mail based messaging experience and then adds P2P tech like https://webxdc.org on top.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112436163856034976</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112436163856034976</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Just to be clear: we value our time and will not engage deeply with people who have a lot of random suggestions and ideas... We don&amp;#39;t have a lack of those on any day :) we are doing continuous user studies, interviews and research with people in repressive, dangerous situations who are using delta chat today. These efforts are usually lead by @Xeniax and entail some scientific rigor as you can expect from a venerable PhD in user research :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427371753153431</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427371753153431</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 09:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>So far, our marketing department is mostly our development coordination department ... And it shows, right ? :) Indeed, we are marketing for early adopters, devs and collaborating experts in neighboring fields and projects to join what we believe is a unique collaborative effort, a fediverse of interactive messengers if you will :) Our project evolves around who shows up, who thinks and does things with us, not on some ideal conception of how things should be and then trying to hire for that.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427314590040572</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112427314590040572</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 09:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Delta Chat may be criticized for not being the most secure messenger in some sense or not the most feature rich. When it comes to interoperability, however, our efforts and collaborations are the biggest game in town, no? The two biggest sets of internet standards revolve and operate at massive scale around E-Mail and the Web. Our approach fully engages and takes up these extremely impactful sets of standards, and reliably rewires them into a modern UI #deltachat #webxdc #chatmail #xkcd927</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112422007157098940</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112422007157098940</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 10:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A quick note as a friendly project follower/user told us they perceived our toot to diminish Signal -- that&amp;#39;s not our intention. Signal has Post-quantum safe algorithms, PFS, Sealed sender -- some pretty advanced mechanisms that have no Delta equivalent. However, Signal&amp;#39;s key distribution is centralized and ours is decentralized which we consider fair game to highlight. Moreover DC has guaranteed e2ee encryption protecting from server compromise, allowing to not overly have to trust server ops.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112418014615996641</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112418014615996641</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 17:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Did you know that Delta Chat is the only mature, cross-platform secure messaging app that does not use or need a key server? Signal, Matrix, Proton, Whatsapp all effectively operate key servers that reveal the cryptographic identity (a very strong identifier) behind an address. Delta Chat uses decentralized specs and protocols that reveal your cryptographic identity only to those you choose to interact with. Nothing can be publically queried. Background link: https://delta.chat/en/help#encryption-and-security</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112416216211151577</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112416216211151577</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The problem with asking the experts about something genuinely new is, according to Heinz von Foerster, that they will only explain to you why it can&amp;#39;t work or why it is a bad idea. We had no shortage of such experts in the past years :) However, common objections like &amp;quot;e-mail is too slow&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;secure e-mail is not possible&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;you can not do a Whatsapp-style interface on top of e-mail&amp;quot; are having an increasingly hard time to be upheld because of the reality of Delta Chat apps working :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112411787878434489</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112411787878434489</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Delta Chat is an in-between project: often ignored as a messenger by e-mail companies/experts and then ignored by messenger companies/experts because of its use and interoperability with e-mail. As Heinz von Foerster once said: &amp;quot;If you are doing something genuinely new then don&amp;#39;t ask the experts. If you do something that has already been done, then, by all means, ask the experts.&amp;quot; FWIW many experts have verified Delta Chat&amp;#39;s security mechanics https://delta.chat/en/help#security-audits :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112411736243400781</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112411736243400781</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The &amp;quot;webxdc evolve&amp;quot; project is now official and was just announced from one of our early followers and advisers, @ansuz , but it&amp;#39;s not just a boilerplate announcement! Ansuz dives deep starting from his yearslong cryptpad maintainership history, his early involvement in #webxdc up to the present and future .... Very good reading if you want to understand some.foundational considerations around evolving an end-to-end encrypted, decentralized web app platform ... https://cryptography.dog/blog/announcing-webxdc-evolve/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112384429386840883</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112384429386840883</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 19:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Seems the french surveillance practises (Hadopi) identifying people behind IP addresses have been legalized by a top EU court. Fwiw #chatmail servers remove any IP address traces after two days and collect no personal data whatsoever. Maybe it&amp;#39;s time for a french themed chatmail server similar to the de,pl,us ones? https://delta.chat/en/chatmail</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112370973721050239</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112370973721050239</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 10:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>See https://mastodon.social/@adbenitez/112355770657658005 and surrounding toots for more info</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112367782647302438</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112367782647302438</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 20:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A wild community experiment that can not but fail? Probably but whatever, welcome to **massive multi-device** usage of #deltachat on #chatmail :) it&amp;#39;s an account not shared between your own devices but between all devices who can import the backup file that is currently circulating .... Bringing you an anonymous e2ee encrypted forum without individual user identities, with autodeletion from server after a week .... also adressable wirh e2ee messaging .... #DepartmentOfCrazy A chat list of an anonymous community with 1-member groups: Futurism Politics and news Photography club Developers Foodies Gnu Linux Meme market Anime and manga Cubans</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112367756634867016</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112367756634867016</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 20:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>For those who like to focus on #security an honest question: which other messenger has, like #deltachat in the last 13 months, received and addressed two independent security audits and one security analysis, all three from renowned auditors and researchers? CC @kuketzblog https://delta.chat/en/help#security-audits</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112345377907246571</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112345377907246571</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 21:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>