<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>en.osm.town/@openstreetmap.rss (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Online voting for the OSMF board elections is open until 19 October at 16:00 UTC. Read this post for all the details: https://blog.openstreetmap.org/2024/10/12/2024-osmf-board-election-online-voting-is-open/</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113295690050605648</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113295690050605648</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 17:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Voting for the 2024 OSMF Foundation board member election is open! Members in good standing, please check your email. A graphic that says &quot;voting is open&quot;</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113294383852920418</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113294383852920418</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Here&amp;#39;s the 2024 report on a year of infrastructure progress for OpenStreetMap. &amp;quot;As the OSM Foundation&amp;#39;s Senior Site Reliability Engineer(SRE), my focus ... has been on driving efficiency, improving resiliency, and scaling our infrastructure to support the continued growth of the #OpenStreetMap project.&amp;quot; --Grant Slater Read the full report here: https://blog.openstreetmap.org/2024/10/08/a-year-of-infrastructure-progress-site-reliability-engineer-2023-2024-update/ a graphic that summarizes the key points from the 2024 report about OSM infrastructure</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113274462505052205</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113274462505052205</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 23:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>📣 Reminder: The OSM Foundation Board election will be open for voting until just before our Annual General Meeting. Join us on October 19 to discuss the future of #OpenStreetMap. For details, visit the link below https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113266262133515721</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113266262133515721</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Happy Birthday WeeklyOSM! 10 years ago today, the Wochennotiz went multilingual and WeeklyOSM was born. 🎂 🎉 It&amp;#39;s a volunteer written, weekly newsletter of everything in #OpenStreetMap available in 15+ languages! Look how amazing and hard-working OSM volunteers are! 👏 Read WeeklyOSM &amp;amp; subscribe https://weeklyosm.eu/ Birthday Post: https://en.osm.town/@weeklyOSM/113264862445917075 How to suggest things for WeeklyOSM: https://weeklyosm.eu/this-news-should-be-in-weeklyosm #WeeklyOSM @weeklyOSM</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113265020021955338</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113265020021955338</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>To quote the old proverb: “The best time to join the OSM Foundation was 5 years ago, the second best time is today” 😁 join now: https://supporting.openstreetmap.org/#Membership-Categories #OpenStreetMap #OSM #OSMF</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113238127227635365</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113238127227635365</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Would you like to vote in the upcoming OpenStreetMap Board election? Alas, if you join today, you cannot vote this year. Sorry! But you&amp;#39;ll be able to vote next year! Join OSMF here: https://supporting.openstreetmap.org/#Membership-Categories #OpenStreetMap #OSM #OSMF #OSMFoundation</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113238127216003378</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113238127216003378</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>That&amp;#39;s the questions. Now, you the OSM community can decide. The OSM Community forum is a great way to discuss these important topics https://community.openstreetmap.org/c/osmf/41</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746402909313</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746402909313</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q14 “The Overture Maps Foundation has been a topic of discussion within the OSM community. What is your position on this initiative and how does it impact the project?“ https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q14_Perspective_on_Overture_Maps</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746394357605</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746394357605</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q13 “In the leadup to the election, the OSMF encountered issues with its open-source membership management system, CivicCRM. This reignited a long-running debate about whether the OSMF should consider using non-open-source third-party software to address such challenges. Is it acceptable for the OSMF to use non-free software if it supports OSM&amp;#39;s goals?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q13_Perspective_on_Open_Source</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746385492518</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746385492518</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q12 “In light of recent vandalism incidents, what if anything should the Board do differently in the area of data protection and quality assurance?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q12_Data_Quality_and_Protection</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746376779086</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746376779086</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q11 “OpenStreetMap relies heavily on technology. How satisfied are you with the current state of the technology that powers OSM? How would you support or encourage technological advancements and innovation within the OSM ecosystem? What technology changes are the most pressing?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q11_Technology_and_Innovation</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746368603964</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746368603964</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q10 “How would you promote diverse voices and perspectives from the global OpenStreetMap community? What steps would you take to attract and retain high-quality volunteers and contributors, especially in underrepresented groups and locations? How would you ensure the OSMF is a safe and welcoming place for all contributors?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q10_Promoting_Community_and_Attracting_Volunteers</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746360204073</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746360204073</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q09 “The OSMF&amp;#39;s primary mission is supporting the global OpenStreetMap community. What specific contributions have you made to OpenStreetMap that reflect your commitment to this mission? Have you participated in cooperative mapping, tagging development, OSM-related software or map style development, or spoken at events or conferences? Have you engaged with the OSM community in your local area or in languages other than English?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q09_Your_Community_Contributions</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746351428708</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746351428708</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q08 “In 2023, the SotM conference was not held. In 2024, the conference was held, however, some community members expressed concern about safety for participants from marginalized groups and pointed to the OSMF&amp;#39;s SotM participant safety policy. How should the OSMF ensure that SotM is held annually, while also being safe and accessible for all members of the global community?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q08_State_of_the_Map</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746342495399</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746342495399</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q07 “The OSMF sometimes receives legal threats or faces political pressure due to controversial topics or disputed territories in the map data. How would you deal with these situations? Are you prepared for potential travel restrictions or government pressure because of the nature of OpenStreetMap data?“ https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q07_Handling_Legal_and_Political_Challenges</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746333673878</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746333673878</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q06 “How important do you think fundraising is for the OSMF, and what experience do you have in this area? Have you participated in direct fundraising, grant writing, or public speaking to raise funds?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q06_Fundraising_and_Resource_Development</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746324768047</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746324768047</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q05 “How do you plan to collaborate with other Board members and Working Groups to make decisions and resolve conflicts? Have you been in touch with current Board members to understand the challenges and responsibilities of the role? Which Working Groups would you like to collaborate with, and which Board Officer role or Committee Chair position interests you most, and why?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q05_Decision-Making_and_Collaboration</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746316062711</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746316062711</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q04 “What are your thoughts on the OSMF’s strategic plan, and what changes would you suggest to ensure OpenStreetMap’s long-term sustainability? If elected, what would be your top priority? Do you think the OSMF should proceed with the planned relocation outside the UK?“ https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q04_Strategic_Vision_and_Sustainability</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746307614976</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746307614976</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Q03 “How would you ensure that the Board’s decisions and actions are transparent and accountable to the OSM community?” https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Foundation/AGM2024/Election_to_Board/Answers_and_manifestos/Q03_Transparency_and_Accountability</title>
        <link>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746298426220</link>
        <guid>https://en.osm.town/@openstreetmap/113227746298426220</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 17:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>