<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Running #chatmail servers is &amp;lt;2h effort per month, according to an ad-hoc poll with 10 operators responding. Some have 10Ks of #deltachat users. Typically 300MB ram is used and max 60gb disc space per server. And all interoperate safely based on high security standards (DKIM and TLS enforced, and only no-metadata #openpgp encrypted messages allowed) .... with typically 0.5 secs end-to-end delivery. Who said again that email is insecure, cumbersome and slow? :) Screenshot of 10 chatmail operators polled about &quot;admin hours spent last month&quot; with two saying &quot;0 hours&quot; and 8 saying &quot;less than 2 hours&quot; with none spending more.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113307519686226505</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113307519686226505</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Maybe the secret why the #deltachat project with &amp;quot;just&amp;quot; a dozen active contributors succeeds in delivering cross-platform apps, instigating the #chatmail server network and spearheading the #webxdc app paradigm, lies in asking the right questions: - Is it really needed? - Can we not do it? - Is there a simpler way that requires less changes? - What is the interesting next impl step that is already interesting itself for users, without requiring first completing a big refactoring project?</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113289411611439719</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113289411611439719</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>@hko rPGP devs created a @rpgp account ... Low traffic mostly with release announces and you can ask questions</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113208278730994480</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113208278730994480</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Our end-to-end encryption engine rPGP just got a big update, fully supporting OpenPGP &amp;quot;cryptorefresh&amp;quot; RFC9850 ... Many thanks to @hko and dignifiedquire for fearlessly pushing ahead in the security machine room ... Please give them a 💜 and also @NGIZero who funded it ! https://fosstodon.org/@hko/113198947595455844</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113199229864580053</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113199229864580053</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Dear @simplex .... Could you elaborate on this tweet? We aim for both censorship resistance and privacy and are curious about your take there .... A screenshot of a tweet from simplex chat reading: Censorship resistance and privacy are in a contradiction - the more censorship resistant a communication solution is, the less private it is, inevitably. SimpleX Chat focus is privacy.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113182526166985853</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113182526166985853</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 18:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We are well aware of the increasing risk of infiltration of our software development, especially as we offer a very high level of privacy. Core Delta contributors know each other personally from many physical week-long gatherings even if we are typically remotely collaborating across thousands of kilometers. Are we immune to infiltration, corruption or bad-faith PRs to our repositories? No, but we value minimalism, work in public and engage with specialists for analysis and audits. #security</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113158011354178891</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113158011354178891</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Did you know that #deltachat does not need and does not use key servers? Most other messengers (wa/signal/matrix/threema/...) actually operate or incorporate a cryptographic key server, managing the cryptographic identities of all users. Delta Chat uses decentralized protocols for key management avoiding a central storage of identities. The SecureJoin protocol is the key (sic!) innovation and was independently analyzed by ETH Zürich researchers earlier this year .... https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-25-crypto-analysis-securejoin</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113153037598329705</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113153037598329705</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Shout out to AccessNow folks and @Xeniax who helped to convince Meta to unblock #deltachat invite URLs in Facebook. Previously delta invite-links on Facebook were marked as &amp;quot;dangerous&amp;quot; and didn&amp;#39;t work. sidenote: if you send someone an invite-link, they can click it directly after they installed Delta Chat because they will be guided through the &amp;quot;create-profile&amp;quot; flow automatically and then be dropped into a chat with the inviter. Screenshot of a Facebook message containing an invite-link. It shows a Delta Chat logo and the &quot;Message privately on Delta Chat&quot; with a &quot;tap the invite link to start&quot; text.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113147751152965469</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113147751152965469</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 14:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Some complain about the lack of PFS but there are good reasons for not employing it and we have a well working &amp;quot;guaranteed end-to-end encryption&amp;quot; system. Others complain about the lack of some Telegram features but Durov&amp;#39;s project keep data of a. biIllion users in cleartext. When shit hits the fan, we want delta chat apps to be mass-ready, provide secure and reliable private messaging service even in authoritarian environments. Easier said than done. Lots of details to care for.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/113104301490882060</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/113104301490882060</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 22:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Open Source spotlight from @ktn -- including an interview with @r10s about past and future challenges with #deltachat and #chatmail ... https://infoservice.heise.de/ct-opensource_vorschau.jsp (german text) Picture of Bjoern Petersen in a hoodie in a little bit of a storm on a river.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112891708114410920</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112891708114410920</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 09:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Phew! If it&amp;#39;s true that some circles in the EU want to cancel #NGI #FOSS funding in favor of &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; then that would be almost as clever as the EU strategically re-orienting Horizon research big money towards Blockchains in 2019. Public money is supposed to be spent on where it is needed and useful for a convivial society and not where big-corporate driven hype already heaps money into, aiming for big profits and layoffs. Doh. more info on NGI/FOSS/AI debacle https://kolektiva.social/@hackstub/112762068812732277</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112767583354362619</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112767583354362619</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 11:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>More ways to connect! Our dear long-term collaborators at Iroh just entered the Fediverse via @n0iroh -- Delta Chat already uses Iroh happily for multi-device setup on all platforms ... stay tuned for more fruits of this ongoing collaboration with some of the best #rust #p2p coders we know :) Latest in their crazy bi-weekly release rhythm is https://iroh.computer/blog/iroh-0-20-more-ways-to-connect</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112761333473270752</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112761333473270752</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 08:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you want to dive deep into guaranteed end-to-end encryption and how green checkmarks protect against compromised servers (&amp;quot;MITM attacks&amp;quot;), the &amp;quot;Cryptographic Analysis of Delta Chat&amp;quot; from Applied Cryptography researchers at ETH Zuerich has been published at https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/918.pdf -- earlier this year we had blogged from our side how we addressed all findings https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-25-crypto-analysis-securejoin #securejoin #deltachat</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112716006329107667</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112716006329107667</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 08:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Third time is a charm! Watch us tirelessly explaining to Roskomnadzor how e-mail works! The three innovations in our third reply are that we a) request the international law their request is grounded on (as if they would care) b) communicate that their assumptions, even according to russian laws, are wrong (as if they would care) c) state explicitly that Delta Chat is unlike WhatsApp, Signal or Telegram (doh!) #chatcontrol-delenda-est A letter from merlinux to Roskomandzor: Regarding registration of Delta Chat provided services in Russia with the following key content: 1) You fail to reference relevant International Law that would give you the authority to request any interaction from us as an organization residing within the legal framework of the European Union. If you don’t reference any international law or treaty, you are required to direct your queries to the german foreign ministry instead, which in turn would get in contact with us. 2) Even if your request was grounded in international law, merlinux is not an „ICO“ or „Information Communication Organizer“ as defined in Section 10.1 of 149-FZ. In particular, we maintain that this base assumption stated in your letter is not correct: „According to the results of the analysis the information resource delta.chat , the owner of which is a foreign organization merlinux GmbH, was found to have the capability to receive, transmit, deliver and (or) process electronic messages of Internet users.“ Unlike Telegram or Whatsapp, the information resource „delta.chat“ does not have the ability to receive, transmit, deliver or process electronic messages. All users of our e-mail client apps choose electronic message processors („e-mail servers“) sovereignly themselves, without our knowledge and without sending their messages through a central server like it happens with Telegram or Whatsapp.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112684132304517685</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112684132304517685</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Delta Chat collabs are carefully cooking new major features by a series of discussion/coding steps with roughly this recipe mix: - one part: discussing a feature and its step wise implementation - three parts: how does it square with usability outcomes (eg avoiding failure modes in the dialogue trees; who really needs this? what do they say themselves?) - one part: how it can be attacked? Focus on real security outcomes. - two parts: how can we avoid maintenance monsters for future us?</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112664966963905029</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112664966963905029</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 08:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Great, so #chatcontrol was not moving forward today thanks also to various interventions from folks around the fediverse .... In particular thanks @Mer__edith for the clear take from Signals side. But it&amp;#39;s clearly not canceled and Hungary will retry getting it through, and France, having elections soon, might drop out of opposing it? Let&amp;#39;s stay vigilant about #chatcontrol and help eg @netzpolitik_feed and @edri and other groups to help us working against authoritarian #chatcontrol fantasies.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112648989842429225</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112648989842429225</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>some news regarding rPGP, the minimal #Rust #OpenPGP implementation that stably provides end-to-end encryption for Delta users since many years: - a new FAQ including questions about IETF specs, Post-Quantum cryptography, Autocrypt, LibrePGP, Seqouia etc. https://github.com/rpgp/rpgp/blob/master/docs/FAQ.md - NLNET just granted #OpenPGP V6 work on rPGP: https://nlnet.nl/project/rPGP-cryptorefresh/ rPGP is an independent and stable project which provides good general #OpenPGP interoperability, see &amp;quot;rpgpie&amp;quot; in https://tests.sequoia-pgp.org/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112638635012948563</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112638635012948563</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 16:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We got note of three #deltachat articles from different angles the last days: Roskomvoboda, human rights org in russia, interviewing @Xeniax about our recent interaction with the russian telco authorities. https://roskomsvoboda.org/ru/post/delta-chat-snova-otkazal-roskomnadzoru/ @unixtippse about &amp;quot;do&amp;#39;s and don&amp;#39;ts&amp;quot; after re-engaging with Delta Chat happily. https://binblog.de/2024/06/15/deltachat-first-dos-first-donts/ @durian about Signal and &amp;quot;Delta Chat for anarchists&amp;quot; https://phlanticap.noblogs.org/delta-chat-for-anarchists/</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112621284535468799</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112621284535468799</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Back to more interesting matters than these authoritarian #chatcontrol dreams (don&amp;#39;t you bet many &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; companies are lining up to sell automated policing?) ... Thanks to @dvzrv there now is a rather official #deltachat #arch package https://archlinux.org/packages/extra/any/deltachat-desktop 💜</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112609978982660781</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112609978982660781</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 15:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>As you know, governmental forces within the EU, the US, the UK, Russia and others are in a hot competition on who gets to be the first to subvert end-to-end encryption. A few days ago, we got another letter from Roskomnadzor, the #russia telco authority, to help them get at user data or metadata for #deltachat users. But there is no central registry of e-mail addresses, messages or decryption keys. So we declined. Sorry, not sorry. A letter from merlinux GmbH to ROSKOMNADZOR Russian Federal Service for Supervision in the Sphere of Telecom, Information Technologies and Mass Communications per e-mail: 97-fz@rkn.gov.ru Freiburg, June 13th 2024 Your request for registration of Delta Chat regarding provided services in Russia Dear Sirs and Madams, on June 11th 2024 we received your request by e-mail to delta@merlinux.eu to register for provided messaging services in Russia for the application Delta Chat whose developments we indeed facilitate and distribute to app stores and many platforms. If we understand your request correctly, you also requested access to decryption keys and access to user data. However, Delta Chat is an e-mail application which lets users choose their e-mail providers at their own discretion. There is no central registry of e-mail addresses and we have no access to message contents, let alone decryption keys which only exist on user devices. We therefore kindly request that you strike us from your list of service providers. best regards and thanks, holger krekel, managing director, merlinux GmbH</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112608426988613191</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112608426988613191</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 08:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>