<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Today, we are unveiling chatmail services, making onboarding with #deltachat a breeze, with peace of mind. #chatmail marks a major milestone, answering the practical question of &amp;quot;where can i get a deltachat-ready account&amp;quot; for myself and friends? Read more on https://delta.chat/en/2023-12-13-chatmail</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 18:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Seems google/apple&amp;#39;s push notifications services are regularly queried by state authorities for obtaining user data -- see this german @netzpolitik_feed https://netzpolitik.org/2023/push-dienste-behoerden-fragen-apple-und-google-nach-nutzern-von-messenger-apps/ -- #deltachat only uses apple&amp;#39;s push notifications on iOS for &amp;quot;heartbeat&amp;quot; services -- to ensure the app can show messages for their user (and many users are asking for tighter integration). On Android, Desktop and #ubuntutouch platforms currently no push notifications are used or needed, also no heartbeat ones.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 09:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you are looking for alternatives to Android, then #ubuntutouch from https://mastodon.social/@ubports is a mobile platform where @lk108 implemented the nicely working DeltaTouch app which also just released guaranteed end-to-end encryption, being very much on par with the other platforms, see https://social.tchncs.de/@lk108/111517563343219731 Pixel3a phone with UbuntuTouch operating system and running DeltaTouch app showing a chatlist with Lothar, a deltatouch group, a registration chat with ubuntuone, and some other chats.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Some in our communities are apparently having fun ... taking no sides ;) (Credits: @matiu_bidule) Two fighting, one saying &quot;i prefer signal&quot;, the other &quot;i prefer signal&quot; and a third sitting on a chair with popcorn saying &quot;je prefer delta chat&quot;</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111504693729563998</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111504693729563998</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We have reports from people for whom delta chat works while signal shows &amp;quot;no internet&amp;quot; ... Various states are throttling traffic all across the planet and you need to have a robust networking layer to provide service. Delta Chat is offline-first, ignores DNS outages, can be combined with Tor or Tails. It is trying to make live easier for people who are already in stress and need a reliable messenging experience. It is project practise to keep the least wealthily connected in focus.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111471516437632965</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111471516437632965</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 13:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The 1.42 app releases are rolling into the stores, providing a major security upgrade that was long in the brewing and testing: guaranteed end-to-end encryption, protecting against compromised servers or networks (MITM attacks). The releases also enable multi-device synchronization of pinned/accepted/blocked/muted chat states, a new global gallery for desktop and many bug fixes and little improvements .... #deltachat https://delta.chat/en/2023-11-23-jumbo-42 a checkmark on a green background the shape of a flower or cloud.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111460913692845091</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111460913692845091</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 16:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>new heise article (german), with this translated summary: &amp;quot;Delta Chat is definitely worth a longer look. The app harmoniously combines chat as a form of communication with the tried-and-tested medium of email and even offers some features that you won&amp;#39;t find in other messengers, such as small &amp;quot;webxdc&amp;quot; apps that you can embed directly in chats and use with conversation partners. It&amp;#39;s a shame that Delta Chat didn&amp;#39;t exist before WhatsApp and the like.&amp;quot; Paywalled link: https://www.heise.de/ratgeber/Per-E-Mail-chatten-Delta-Chat-als-Messenger-und-Mailsoftware-nutzen-9432335.html Fazit Delta Chat stellt eine interessante Alternative oder Erganzung zu traditioneller Chat- und Mailsoftware dar. Gegeniiber anderen Messengern sind die wichtigsten Vorteile der App ihre Dezentralitiit und dass man per E-Mail praktisch jeden erreicht. Ob Delta Chat Ihre Mail-App ganz oder teilweise ersetzen kann, héngt vor allem davon ab, wie Sie E-Mails nutzen. Einen langeren Blick ist Delta Chat jedenfalls wert. Die App verheiratet die Kommunikationsform Chat und das bewahrte Medium E-Mail harmonisch und bietet sogar einige Features, die man bei anderen Messengern vergeblich sucht, etwa kleine &quot;webxdc&quot;-Apps, die man direkt in Chats einbetten und mit Gesprachspartnern nutzen kann. Schade, dass Delta Chat nicht schon vor WhatsApp und Co. existierte. (syt)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111454694903470186</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111454694903470186</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Apart from the currently 53 #webxdc apps in the &amp;quot;xstore&amp;quot; (say hi to xstore@testrun.org) there are apparently at least double as many in circulation .... people post random little webxdc apps which then get used throughout several chats -- it&amp;#39;s wild out there and no central platforms in sight ;) a screenshot of a Delta Chat community group chat where one user is saying: &quot;| suppose it depends on the size of the app if the app is small the best is just keep the copy of the app inside the app because js-zip is no that small, but if the app it is big then it is better use js-zip. For the poll app | think is it just better the copy way.&quot; and the next message quotes an app icon for the &quot;Delta apps&quot; app and say: &quot;BTW I have like more than 100 apps in that app&quot;.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111291740636114659</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111291740636114659</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you like delta chat and know somebody experienced with iOS developments please send them our way, retoots welcome. With all other platforms.we have at least two devs engaged but would like to up our iOS game .... Even advising on a day-per-week or loose pro-bono basis could be helpful but someone who gets their hand dirty would be even better. Remote paid job available. For more background see https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob and adjacent recent blog posts.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111194512214036910</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111194512214036910</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Last month was cleanup-time with Delta Chat Android and Desktop development -- lots of triaging, resolving and closing of issues and pull requests ... Android: 26 merged PRs, 5 open PRs, 49 closed issues Desktop: 42 merged PRs, 2 open PRs, 25 closed issues, 4 new issues many thanks to @r10s @treefit and @adbenitez who drove the efforts, as well as to all the helpers! rumors have it that we are preparing for some bigger things to arrive in the next couple of months ;) github activity screen for deltachat-desktop showing: - 42 merged pull requests - 2 opened pull requests - 25 closed issues - 4 new issues</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111155262034725904</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111155262034725904</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 17:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We just published the new &amp;quot;Encryption and Security&amp;quot; FAQ section: https://delta.chat/en/help#encryption-and-security We also added more info regarding &amp;quot;verfiied groups&amp;quot; that guarantee safe E2E-encryption even if servers are malfeasant or compromised: https://delta.chat/en/help#verifiedchats #deltachat #security</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111064803824610765</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111064803824610765</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We are currently revising the FAQ regarding common questions about E2E-encryption and OpenPGP Security, Metadata protection, verified groups etc. in this PR https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-pages/pull/727/files feedback welcome at best on the PR but here is fine as well. You also can glimpse in this PR some of the security improvements we are aiming for in the next couple months.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111059101594526796</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111059101594526796</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>it&amp;#39;s the year two thousand and 23: happy 42nd birth day, dear Chaos Computer Club! See you all at congress end of the year? illuminated windows on a skyscraper showing a CCC sign</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111051379747898318</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111051379747898318</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 09:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Do you sometimes hesitate to give out your Whatsapp or Signal address for work, project or private uses respectively? Indeed, it&amp;#39;s not always easy to keep social contexts separated but all #deltachat apps offer proven multi-account support. Just create another :) Tired of platform notification mails and having to go to some weird web mail interface with lots of ads? Just create another account in Delta Chat for platform spam/notifications, and receive it all in a convenient chat app.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111013982837256929</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111013982837256929</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 18:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>@ravage just contributed a &amp;quot;snap&amp;quot; version of Delta Chat desktop -- https://snapcraft.io/deltachat-desktop -- confirmation that it works (along with the platform you are using) would be welcome.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111012115753882653</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111012115753882653</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 10:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The T-Rex collage from @jarwski is back on our little 700+ accounts community https://testrun.org/ chat-mail instance ... True to the motto we are plotting new rounds of &amp;quot;experiments with the future of email&amp;quot; using a proven project practise : go back to inflection points of history and try fork into a different reality ... None of what is typically believed about email is neccessarily true or unavoidable :) Maybe we have some surprises to show at #ccc congress end this year in hamburg ... A colorful collage picture with a zepelin, a trex dinosaur, projection of planet earth and a retro style sysadmin setup with the caption &quot;test run.org&quot; and sub caption &quot;experimenting with the future of.email&quot;</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110986996178676024</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110986996178676024</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The talk from @hpk about &amp;quot;Delta Chat and WebXDC&amp;quot; at #cccamp23 is online at https://media.ccc.de/v/camp2023-57191-delta_chat_messenger -- at our camp village a lot of people onboarded from hackspaces around the world and we&amp;#39;ve had many fun discussions with various people, among them Paul and Niklas from @briar , @ninabreznik from wizardamigos and DAT, security trainers from the &amp;quot;Cybersyn&amp;quot; project in latin america, @maxigas from CILAB Amsterdam, @okdistribute to name just a few ... #cccamp23 was wonderful time, thanks everybody! picture of Delta Chat tent at #cccamp23 along with a painted &quot;Delta&quot; picture from Mona</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110973471566588639</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110973471566588639</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 14:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>1.40.1 is available now from inside the @fdroidorg app - this will &amp;quot;unbrick&amp;quot; all devices that had 1.40.0 installed and could not start delta chat, phew! 🥳</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110972698180741306</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110972698180741306</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 11:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We are waiting since 8 days on @fdroidorg to publish a) our disabling of the 1.40.0 release b) our 1.40.1 fdroid release that we did a few hours after users reported crashes. Status is tracked here https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-android/issues/2639#issuecomment-1692416810 .... We had dozens of users reporting that their fdroid #deltachat install became unusable and we are very sorry about it but also can&amp;#39;t do much else than wait. Don&amp;#39;t deinstall anything, please, but wait for fdroid to publish the update after which things will function again.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110954560630376414</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110954560630376414</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 06:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Small update: a few hours later we had tagged a fixing 1.40.1 which is in the pipelines of fdroid while the brown bag release 1.40.0 is marked as invalid and should not get auto-Installed further.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110919460959334898</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110919460959334898</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 01:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>