<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>For those who like to focus on #security an honest question: which other messenger has, like #deltachat in the last 13 months, received and addressed two independent security audits and one security analysis, all three from renowned auditors and researchers? CC @kuketzblog https://delta.chat/en/help#security-audits</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112345377907246571</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112345377907246571</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 21:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Apart from the default #chatmail server advertised on our onboarding page there are at least three other stable open-signup servers whose operators cooperate to ensure stability, see this new page covering background such as funding, trust etc https://delta.chat/en/chatmail</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112336709822889259</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112336709822889259</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Phew, that was a damn short window of dysfunction .... It works.already again.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112322326845849176</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112322326845849176</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 20:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>https://delta.chat is down .... oh no!!!!!.... do you notice any problems with message deliveries? Of course not because DC apps do not depend on this or another single central server :) Anyways, there is a little planned migration ongoing. Well&amp;#39;be back and hugs to our sysadmin/devops folks :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112322308828095186</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112322308828095186</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 20:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Let&amp;#39;s do fun statistics! How many times did you encounter &amp;quot;failed to decrypt&amp;quot; errors in a Delta Chat app in 2024? Maybe add a comment for context if you like. (sidenote: you can send anonymous statistics in advanced settings on Android -- it helps us to assess the state of things and where our efforts are best spent. Thanks!) No failed to decrypt at all Got it but proper multi-device setup fixed it Got it sometimes Get it all the time</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112303586833566219</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112303586833566219</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Within #deltachat teams and with many collaborating experts and projects around us, we somewhat stubbornly cling to &amp;quot;working code wins&amp;quot; .... But don&amp;#39;t forget it&amp;#39;s powerful sibling: &amp;quot;maintenable code wins&amp;quot;, especially in the longer term. Our automated testing culture, our use of #rustlang at the heart of things and our usability-first focus all help maintenanbility. We don&amp;#39;t have the treacherous luxury of vc-funding which means we must be a hundred times more economical in our approaches.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112302281555146925</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112302281555146925</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 07:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>That being said, matrix offers room management like IRC did and fits better, and is developed for corporate environments, whereas delta is focused on private messenging purposes. Evolving delta to have discoverable many-user channels is feasible and there are promising experiments (using good old mailman) but it&amp;#39;s not a primary focus for now. We have a strong focus on stability and improving the base experience to rival WhatsApp ... But we also prepare some surprises for the next release :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282885555599002</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282885555599002</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Messaging transports better be dumb and do the bare minimum to get the job done for end-to-end encrypting apps. Compared to #matrix homeservers #chatmail servers are two orders of magnitude more dumb, consume two orders of magnitude less resources and are blazing fast and don&amp;#39;t require extra (central?!) identity and integration servers. With delta all intelligence, including general purpose https://webxdc.org/apps and protection against compromised networks and servers, lives on the end device.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282803654469654</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282803654469654</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>&amp;quot;but e-mail !1!!!&amp;quot; Is probably still a number one objection from experts and power users who refuse to fathom that e-mail protocols are a viable option for instant messaging even if it demonstrably works, is fast and secure :) We&amp;#39;d be happy if someone engaged in a proper comparison with xmpp and matrix specs and impls, really the only three messenging protocols deployed and implemented at scale. (Can&amp;#39;t compare that with Signal or WhatsApp which don&amp;#39;t have wire specs!). https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core-rust/blob/main/standards.md</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112262757654186464</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112262757654186464</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 07:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>for those interested, there also is a recent hackernews discussion around rpgp: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39961994</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237770175658010</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237770175658010</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 21:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#cryptography news: rpgp, the pure Rust #OpenPGP encryption engine used in all #deltachat apps, got quite some love lately, including a revamp of the main entry point for developers: https://github.com/rpgp/rpgp . You may regard rpgp as an extension of the #rustcrypto effort where a lot of the base code lives and is co-maintained by the wonderful diginifiedquire who also just landed a long awaited sha1-collision detector -- as one of the few people officially allowed to write crypto code :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237664230834484</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237664230834484</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 21:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>How many people do you know that have lost their messaging history on Whatsapp or Signal, photos etc during mobile phone transitions or breakage or through other shenenigans? With #deltachat you can: - export &amp;quot;everything&amp;quot; to a file and import it on any of the many different devices - or just setup a second device through a QR code scan -- which was happily discovered here after an accidental factory reset https://libranet.de/display/0b6b25a8-2066-0695-ca24-081964494389</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112180528987313206</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112180528987313206</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 19:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The last #deltachat 1.44 release round did not only contain a lot of UI/UX milestones but also 20 security fixes based on a deep analysis from Yuanming Song and colleagues of the Applied Cryptography group at ETH Zuerich https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-25-crypto-analysis-securejoin a 3d-picture of a green-checkmark with a chain around it.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112156902140296303</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112156902140296303</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 14:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The default setup of #chatmail is for open signups (anyone can get an address) but some operators implement a private signup protocol and that&amp;#39;s fine and easy enough to do because https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail/ is a small machine. Chatmail addresses should be abundant and safe to use for anyone , and cheap to operate with basic skills .... A few thousand chatmail routers might already cover adresses for 10 billion people, with less resource/energy usage than a single VC funded LLM startup :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112094711706110799</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112094711706110799</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 15:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#deltachat just got four major usability improvements as the 1.44 releases are rolling out 💗 Reactions on all platforms 💗 iOS Push notifications 💗 Multi-account desktop sidebar 💗 share invite links via other messengers. Enjoy :) https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-12-jumbo44</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: our pure #Rust core library underlying all #deltachat apps now has reproducible builds for &amp;quot;deltachat-rpc-server&amp;quot;, used by bots and soon also the Desktop app a screenshot of this chat-message from a core dev: deltachat-rpc-server binaries in the latest release 1.136.2 are actually reproducible. $ nix build . #deltachat-rpc-server-armveklinux § sha256sum result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server 0OefS6ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096fd67e87a469bcabbaase6d54baf9204c result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server This is the same as what GitHub actions built and uploaded to the release: $ curl -sL https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core- rust/releases/download/v1.136.2/deltachat-rpc-server-ar mv6Hinux | sha256sum 0ef56ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096d67e87a469bcabbaaSe6d54baf9204c - — o 4 HOURS</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Given the experiences of the last decade it&amp;#39;s healthy to distrust #decentralized tech if - it&amp;#39;s mainly developed by a centralized power structure - the involved technology is very complex - there is coin or VC funding involved #deltachat has 1/100th, if even that, of what other popular messenging projects have in terms of moneys. But our distributed top-notch expertise in UI, crypto, networking tech and our federated collaborative practises across these concerns, try to make up for it ...</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: the pure #rust end-to-end encryption engine, &amp;quot;rpgp&amp;quot;, saw quite some work and a new release in recent weeks and now @hko released a higher level &amp;quot;rpgpie&amp;quot; interface for application developers ( see https://fosstodon.org/@hko/111997998005869515 ) which also powers running the IETF #OpenPGP #interoperability test suite quite successfully .... Delta Chat&amp;#39;s security-audited encryption engine is in fact used from several other projects and in other contexts these days and we are happy about it!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Quick poll: what would you prefer &amp;quot;delete message(s)&amp;quot; to mean in #deltachat if you only had a choice between these two? delete on all my devices delete only on this device</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 10:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We can neither confirm nor deny that there will be #deltachat stickers tonight ;) https://chaos.social/@techfrombelow/111975040605743748 #berlin</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 12:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>