<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Within #deltachat teams and with many collaborating experts and projects around us, we somewhat stubbornly cling to &amp;quot;working code wins&amp;quot; .... But don&amp;#39;t forget it&amp;#39;s powerful sibling: &amp;quot;maintenable code wins&amp;quot;, especially in the longer term. Our automated testing culture, our use of #rustlang at the heart of things and our usability-first focus all help maintenanbility. We don&amp;#39;t have the treacherous luxury of vc-funding which means we must be a hundred times more economical in our approaches.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112302281555146925</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112302281555146925</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 07:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>That being said, matrix offers room management like IRC did and fits better, and is developed for corporate environments, whereas delta is focused on private messenging purposes. Evolving delta to have discoverable many-user channels is feasible and there are promising experiments (using good old mailman) but it&amp;#39;s not a primary focus for now. We have a strong focus on stability and improving the base experience to rival WhatsApp ... But we also prepare some surprises for the next release :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282885555599002</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282885555599002</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Messaging transports better be dumb and do the bare minimum to get the job done for end-to-end encrypting apps. Compared to #matrix homeservers #chatmail servers are two orders of magnitude more dumb, consume two orders of magnitude less resources and are blazing fast and don&amp;#39;t require extra (central?!) identity and integration servers. With delta all intelligence, including general purpose https://webxdc.org/apps and protection against compromised networks and servers, lives on the end device.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282803654469654</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112282803654469654</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>&amp;quot;but e-mail !1!!!&amp;quot; Is probably still a number one objection from experts and power users who refuse to fathom that e-mail protocols are a viable option for instant messaging even if it demonstrably works, is fast and secure :) We&amp;#39;d be happy if someone engaged in a proper comparison with xmpp and matrix specs and impls, really the only three messenging protocols deployed and implemented at scale. (Can&amp;#39;t compare that with Signal or WhatsApp which don&amp;#39;t have wire specs!). https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core-rust/blob/main/standards.md</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112262757654186464</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112262757654186464</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 07:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>for those interested, there also is a recent hackernews discussion around rpgp: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39961994</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237770175658010</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237770175658010</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 21:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#cryptography news: rpgp, the pure Rust #OpenPGP encryption engine used in all #deltachat apps, got quite some love lately, including a revamp of the main entry point for developers: https://github.com/rpgp/rpgp . You may regard rpgp as an extension of the #rustcrypto effort where a lot of the base code lives and is co-maintained by the wonderful diginifiedquire who also just landed a long awaited sha1-collision detector -- as one of the few people officially allowed to write crypto code :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237664230834484</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112237664230834484</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 21:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>How many people do you know that have lost their messaging history on Whatsapp or Signal, photos etc during mobile phone transitions or breakage or through other shenenigans? With #deltachat you can: - export &amp;quot;everything&amp;quot; to a file and import it on any of the many different devices - or just setup a second device through a QR code scan -- which was happily discovered here after an accidental factory reset https://libranet.de/display/0b6b25a8-2066-0695-ca24-081964494389</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112180528987313206</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112180528987313206</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 19:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The last #deltachat 1.44 release round did not only contain a lot of UI/UX milestones but also 20 security fixes based on a deep analysis from Yuanming Song and colleagues of the Applied Cryptography group at ETH Zuerich https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-25-crypto-analysis-securejoin a 3d-picture of a green-checkmark with a chain around it.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112156902140296303</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112156902140296303</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 14:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The default setup of #chatmail is for open signups (anyone can get an address) but some operators implement a private signup protocol and that&amp;#39;s fine and easy enough to do because https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail/ is a small machine. Chatmail addresses should be abundant and safe to use for anyone , and cheap to operate with basic skills .... A few thousand chatmail routers might already cover adresses for 10 billion people, with less resource/energy usage than a single VC funded LLM startup :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112094711706110799</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112094711706110799</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 15:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#deltachat just got four major usability improvements as the 1.44 releases are rolling out 💗 Reactions on all platforms 💗 iOS Push notifications 💗 Multi-account desktop sidebar 💗 share invite links via other messengers. Enjoy :) https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-12-jumbo44</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: our pure #Rust core library underlying all #deltachat apps now has reproducible builds for &amp;quot;deltachat-rpc-server&amp;quot;, used by bots and soon also the Desktop app a screenshot of this chat-message from a core dev: deltachat-rpc-server binaries in the latest release 1.136.2 are actually reproducible. $ nix build . #deltachat-rpc-server-armveklinux § sha256sum result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server 0OefS6ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096fd67e87a469bcabbaase6d54baf9204c result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server This is the same as what GitHub actions built and uploaded to the release: $ curl -sL https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core- rust/releases/download/v1.136.2/deltachat-rpc-server-ar mv6Hinux | sha256sum 0ef56ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096d67e87a469bcabbaaSe6d54baf9204c - — o 4 HOURS</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Given the experiences of the last decade it&amp;#39;s healthy to distrust #decentralized tech if - it&amp;#39;s mainly developed by a centralized power structure - the involved technology is very complex - there is coin or VC funding involved #deltachat has 1/100th, if even that, of what other popular messenging projects have in terms of moneys. But our distributed top-notch expertise in UI, crypto, networking tech and our federated collaborative practises across these concerns, try to make up for it ...</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: the pure #rust end-to-end encryption engine, &amp;quot;rpgp&amp;quot;, saw quite some work and a new release in recent weeks and now @hko released a higher level &amp;quot;rpgpie&amp;quot; interface for application developers ( see https://fosstodon.org/@hko/111997998005869515 ) which also powers running the IETF #OpenPGP #interoperability test suite quite successfully .... Delta Chat&amp;#39;s security-audited encryption engine is in fact used from several other projects and in other contexts these days and we are happy about it!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Quick poll: what would you prefer &amp;quot;delete message(s)&amp;quot; to mean in #deltachat if you only had a choice between these two? delete on all my devices delete only on this device</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 10:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We can neither confirm nor deny that there will be #deltachat stickers tonight ;) https://chaos.social/@techfrombelow/111975040605743748 #berlin</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 12:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>In whichever area of #deltachat related developments you look, you will find different people and communities -- even if there are several individuals who appear in multiple contexts as key contributors or drivers. There is no single person who gets to decide about everything even if we do have lead roles for particular aspects. Our experimental community approaches respect Convays Law: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law -- meaning: our #decentralization tech will be only as good as our social practises</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111941241080798882</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111941241080798882</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 12:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Reclaiming Peer-to-Peer Web technology with #webxdc out of the ashes of &amp;quot;Web3&amp;quot;: our 2024 opening post on the topic :) https://delta.chat/en/2024-02-15-webxdc-m3 Psst: we are looking for more folks experienced with Web app development with a knack for P2P technology .... #deltachat A snapshot picture of delta chat contributors partying in Kyiv in 2019</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111935038589329716</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111935038589329716</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Was an eventful and enjoyable #offdem24 and #fossdem24 .... Ranging from intermingling with people operating security-sensitiv helplines using #chatmail to discussing email standards like the evolving openpgp cryptorefresh ... And then several more underground happenings which might lead to even more surprises than are already developing .... with many of us agreeing and appreciating that we are rather engaged with lots interesting communities and folks rather than corporate structures.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 20:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>When you are interacting with this account here you are actually interacting with a bunch of folks involved in various ways in project happenings, who are often following interactions via a deltachat mastodon bot that relays messages into a chat group from where the reply is triggered. Many of the @delta members have an #offlinefirst approach to networking so mostly use the chat group to interact. #DidYouKnowDepartment</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We just refined the user facing &amp;quot;download&amp;quot; page to include instant #chatmail onboarding instructions https://get.delta.chat Did you know there also are first independent #chatmail setups from friendly third parties, eg https://mehl.cloud and https://mailchat.pl/ all nicely interoperable and fast? #chatmail actively develops here https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail/pulse/monthly ....</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>