<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Delta Chat 1.38 releases: WebXDC apps can now exchange data with other tools and run on other messengers! We&amp;#39;ve implemented a little Calendar and Draw app to showcase the two new APIs and besides have other good news for the nascent privacy-guaranteeing Next-Generation-Internet ... just a &amp;quot;start&amp;quot; button for chat-shared apps with no GDPR or cookie-consents, no coins, no app or account hosting and thus no logins ;) https://delta.chat/en/2023-06-28-webxdc-import-export</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110621944095573330</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110621944095573330</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We were very happy when we heard that the XMPP-based https://cheogram.com/ experimentally adopted https://webxdc.org -- so that the same web apps run on Cheogram and Delta Chat. We started communicating with Cheogram&amp;#39;s main dev through matterbridge in a group chat about upcoming webxdc improvements ... #interoperability ftw :) A screenshot of the Android Cheogram messenger apps showing the &quot;2048&quot; and &quot;checklist&quot; apps running inside a cheogram conversation.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110577372845834642</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110577372845834642</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 16:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Delta Chat has a pretty wild development model compared to more regular places with VC or Coin or NGO funding. It is partly based on money but also on helping each other out in diverse situations of which there are too many to summarize them, also considering that most countries are in a more or less critical crisis state. This all requires different cooperation practices going far beyond &amp;quot;agile&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;waterfall&amp;quot; dichotomies ... see also our last December UIdev post https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110559792208628884</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110559792208628884</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Earlier this year we got into a surprising and somewhat annoying struggle with Web browser sandboxing failures related to our &amp;quot;web apps shared in a chat&amp;quot; feature. After much background work we released the hardened Delta Chat 1.36 series, also addressing a dedicated fourth independent security audit, and can finally share more of what was going on behind the scenes https://delta.chat/en/2023-05-22-webxdc-security #chromium #deltachat #security #webxdc</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110412649302291193</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110412649302291193</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 13:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>End-to-End encryption is one of the good things we have with the current internet and app ecosystems. But it is under constant threat -- be it from EU&amp;#39;s #chatcontrol, UK&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;online safety bill&amp;quot; or the current renewed &amp;quot;EARN IT&amp;quot; effort in the US: https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2023/04/earn-it-bill-back-again-seeking-scan-our-messages-and-photos .... anyone of these efforts succeeding would be a dangerous dam break. Let&amp;#39;s collectively make sure all these governmental anti-privacy efforts fail!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110242489687290418</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110242489687290418</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 12:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>For programmers who are interested in #Golang and/or #bots , you may checkout https://github.com/deltachat-bot/deltabot-cli-go -- The new statically linked deltachat-rpc-server can run on 32/64 bit and be used from any programming language by calling async RPC requests via stdin/stdout to a deltachat-rpc-server running in a subprocess. As released Desktop uses this jsonrpc-API it&amp;#39;s also pretty complete.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110124628301466341</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110124628301466341</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>And then, some devs are now hell-bound to port the complete Delta Chat Core from #Rust to #Python for the next release https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core-rust/pull/4259 (already works and passes the tests locally but CI is failing -- go figure!)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110123448169364468</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110123448169364468</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 12:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>news from the #hyperbridging frontlines of the currently possible ... why not use your emacs/IRC client to connect to a custom DeltaIRCD server where you can load DC accounts as well? or how about accessing the community channel via ` ssh ssh.masfloss.net -p 2023`? If some entity called &amp;quot;chatbot&amp;quot; crosses your paths and you chat with it: be careful, it&amp;#39;s a gpt-ish intelligence also lingering in some channels :) README.md Minimal IRC server which integrates with Delta Chat ¢ Features * support direct messages / private channels « auto-join/leave to same channels as on Delta Chat « reconnects with backoff on Delta Chat restarts « support multiple users « support channel/direct message backlog (messages when you're disconnected from IRC/Delta Chat) * WHOIS, WHO, JOIN, LEAVE, NICK, LIST, ISON, PRIVMSG, MODE, TOPIC, LUSERS, AWAY, KICK, INVITE support « support TLS (ssl) * support unix sockets</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110123144835733191</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110123144835733191</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We hardly talked about #security audits but there is nothing to hide! #DeltaChat received three security audits in total, covering core networking #encryption as well as SMTP/IMAP protocol and end-to-end encryption, and also including an audit on our recent secure server setup guide: https://delta.chat/en/2023-03-27-third-independent-security-audit</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110096123048962714</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110096123048962714</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 16:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>A little chatgpt-bot for Delta https://github.com/deltachat-bot/chatbot -- you need to instantiate it yourselves on some e-mail address but then it&amp;#39;s very easy to use e.g. for your family or partners via regular Delta Chat chatting. Btw please be warned: we likely will quickly ban accounts who post AI-generated posts to our support forum. If you are curious ask your favorite chat-bot for an argument why posting machine-generated content to a user support forum is unethical ;)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/110078064653607402</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/110078064653607402</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 11:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#hyperbridging This mastodon post brought to you by a deltachat-mastodon-bot with a screenshare into a deltachat community mailing list (hacked mailman) , ... And that screenshare points to https://pluralistic.net/2022/11/14/luxury-surveillance/#liar-liar ....</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109920062987816519</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109920062987816519</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Five of us were going around Bruxelles the last week, for OFFDEM and server-setup happenings mostly ... and almost none had mobile data and rather relied on random WIFIs .... personally testing our own app&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;offline-first&amp;quot; approach and features for real :) The server-setup workshops generally went very well and some attendees now aim to give sessions themselves in Strasbourg and other places -- and next one is at LAG in Amsterdam this friday ... https://delta.chat/en/2023-01-27-upcoming-mail-server-workshops</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109823760694772297</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109823760694772297</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 13:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Wondering what the best e-mail server is out there? How about rolling one for your friends and communities? Here is a new setup guide for &amp;quot;automatic accounts&amp;quot; e-mail servers --- and an announcement of upcoming hands-on workshops in Brussels, Amsterdam, Montpellier and Gent ... all in the next 8 weeks! https://delta.chat/en/2023-01-27-upcoming-mail-server-workshops</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109761861452626888</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109761861452626888</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 15:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you want to gift all Delta Chat users something you may boost or forward https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob to somebody who might be interested to help with Android/iOS or other developments. We wish you all some good last days of this year! A cute painted greek delta in a with green twigs, some xmas balls and presents</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109563888540930680</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109563888540930680</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Decentralization Unchained -- diverse backgrounds of Delta Chat developments that you probably didn&amp;#39;t know about ... https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob -- note that our twitter presence is fading further, has shifted to the fediverse for more than a year already #leavingtwitter</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109524017082518172</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109524017082518172</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 15:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Decentralization Unchained -- here is a lot of background what&amp;#39;s happening with Delta Chat, serving as background for our job offers to experienced UI devs https://delta.chat/en/2022-12-15-uidevjob #fossjobs #deltachat</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109517627964019902</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109517627964019902</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Some of our users report that missing an attachment happens more rarely with delta chat 😉</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109426263005054161</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109426263005054161</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 08:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Before scheduling a meeting, ask yourself ....</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109420666198536833</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109420666198536833</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 09:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>thanks to @adbenitez (maintainer of that mastodon bot) for pointing out that OAUTH2 is available too -- so no need to provide your password to the bot. Of course it still sees you interacting which still requires some trust to be put into the operator of the bot.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109371919429758159</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109371919429758159</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 18:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>This @delta account is mediated in a chat group where anyone in the group can reply and see interactions, or follow the &amp;quot;home&amp;quot; chat with posts from the accounts we follow. For implementation see https://github.com/simplebot-org/simplebot_mastodon (also on PyPI) -- the bot needs your credentials so it&amp;#39;s best to run this bot in an environment you trust.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/109371136436367780</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/109371136436367780</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>