<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos.social/@delta (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>#deltachat just got four major usability improvements as the 1.44 releases are rolling out 💗 Reactions on all platforms 💗 iOS Push notifications 💗 Multi-account desktop sidebar 💗 share invite links via other messengers. Enjoy :) https://delta.chat/en/2024-03-12-jumbo44</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112084571969847132</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: our pure #Rust core library underlying all #deltachat apps now has reproducible builds for &amp;quot;deltachat-rpc-server&amp;quot;, used by bots and soon also the Desktop app a screenshot of this chat-message from a core dev: deltachat-rpc-server binaries in the latest release 1.136.2 are actually reproducible. $ nix build . #deltachat-rpc-server-armveklinux § sha256sum result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server 0OefS6ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096fd67e87a469bcabbaase6d54baf9204c result/bin/deltachat-rpc-server This is the same as what GitHub actions built and uploaded to the release: $ curl -sL https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-core- rust/releases/download/v1.136.2/deltachat-rpc-server-ar mv6Hinux | sha256sum 0ef56ccd194ed68673d75cca38b56096d67e87a469bcabbaaSe6d54baf9204c - — o 4 HOURS</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112047758353026678</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 08:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Given the experiences of the last decade it&amp;#39;s healthy to distrust #decentralized tech if - it&amp;#39;s mainly developed by a centralized power structure - the involved technology is very complex - there is coin or VC funding involved #deltachat has 1/100th, if even that, of what other popular messenging projects have in terms of moneys. But our distributed top-notch expertise in UI, crypto, networking tech and our federated collaborative practises across these concerns, try to make up for it ...</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/112025677314593608</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>News from the machine room: the pure #rust end-to-end encryption engine, &amp;quot;rpgp&amp;quot;, saw quite some work and a new release in recent weeks and now @hko released a higher level &amp;quot;rpgpie&amp;quot; interface for application developers ( see https://fosstodon.org/@hko/111997998005869515 ) which also powers running the IETF #OpenPGP #interoperability test suite quite successfully .... Delta Chat&amp;#39;s security-audited encryption engine is in fact used from several other projects and in other contexts these days and we are happy about it!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111998115487596818</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Quick poll: what would you prefer &amp;quot;delete message(s)&amp;quot; to mean in #deltachat if you only had a choice between these two? delete on all my devices delete only on this device</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111980276952505581</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 10:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We can neither confirm nor deny that there will be #deltachat stickers tonight ;) https://chaos.social/@techfrombelow/111975040605743748 #berlin</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111975054092445076</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 12:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>In whichever area of #deltachat related developments you look, you will find different people and communities -- even if there are several individuals who appear in multiple contexts as key contributors or drivers. There is no single person who gets to decide about everything even if we do have lead roles for particular aspects. Our experimental community approaches respect Convays Law: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law -- meaning: our #decentralization tech will be only as good as our social practises</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111941241080798882</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111941241080798882</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 12:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Reclaiming Peer-to-Peer Web technology with #webxdc out of the ashes of &amp;quot;Web3&amp;quot;: our 2024 opening post on the topic :) https://delta.chat/en/2024-02-15-webxdc-m3 Psst: we are looking for more folks experienced with Web app development with a knack for P2P technology .... #deltachat A snapshot picture of delta chat contributors partying in Kyiv in 2019</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111935038589329716</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111935038589329716</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Was an eventful and enjoyable #offdem24 and #fossdem24 .... Ranging from intermingling with people operating security-sensitiv helplines using #chatmail to discussing email standards like the evolving openpgp cryptorefresh ... And then several more underground happenings which might lead to even more surprises than are already developing .... with many of us agreeing and appreciating that we are rather engaged with lots interesting communities and folks rather than corporate structures.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111880788029950808</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 20:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>When you are interacting with this account here you are actually interacting with a bunch of folks involved in various ways in project happenings, who are often following interactions via a deltachat mastodon bot that relays messages into a chat group from where the reply is triggered. Many of the @delta members have an #offlinefirst approach to networking so mostly use the chat group to interact. #DidYouKnowDepartment</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111855645754971836</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 10:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>We just refined the user facing &amp;quot;download&amp;quot; page to include instant #chatmail onboarding instructions https://get.delta.chat Did you know there also are first independent #chatmail setups from friendly third parties, eg https://mehl.cloud and https://mailchat.pl/ all nicely interoperable and fast? #chatmail actively develops here https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail/pulse/monthly ....</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111773270512978381</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Not only are we user-testing app release candidates with various groups ahead of putting it to stores (thanks to the many helpers from across the globe!) but we are also intertwining design decisions with early user-testing with actual groups in risk (big shoutout to @Xeniax !) -- see here for an example which showcases that the question on which &amp;quot;attacker&amp;quot; to focus on is a fundamental question and you can not meaningfully discuss &amp;quot;security&amp;quot; without it. https://github.com/deltachat/deltachat-android/pull/2916#issuecomment-1883086981</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111726355777273276</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111726355777273276</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#37c3 was a blast ... Lots of enjoyable and surprising chats and developments and new collabs, affinities and synergies .... Wishing you all happy transitions and phasings into new beginnings with accelerated escape velocities from the many mainsteam catastrophical developments 💜 ( generated image was removed due to fair critique ... Peace :)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111676122232845942</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111676122232845942</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The #37c3 delta chat group size is now at 67 members ... Still no glitches except a bit of confusion with someone switching from one account to another and then another :) You can indeed #migrate from a https://nine.testrun.org account to another email address and keep all your guaranteed encrypted chats ....Other will notice and autoaccept your mail adress change ... See https://delta.chat/en/2022-09-14-aeap for how this works. #RightToExit #RightToMigrate</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111666157750901070</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111666157750901070</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 22:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>The #37c3 delta chat group has now 48 members, all using guaranteed end to end encryption and several games and apps .... So far without a glitch, no &amp;quot;couldn&amp;#39;t decrypt&amp;quot; errors, everything lightning fast, some people using multiple devices with their account, 30 people joining during live onboarding on day1 and using a editor together in the chat (like cryptpad without a server basically). Seems like all the milestones of 2023 (guaranteed e2ee, web apps, chatmail) are ... Actually playing out ;)</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111662918305095365</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111662918305095365</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>More #deltachat folks are arriving at #37c3 today and tomorrow .... We I&amp;#39;ll be around #komona in hall H ... On day 1 we intend to do a #chatmail hands on session probably in the evening. There is usually a #komona billboard with planned sessions .... Anyways, everyone, please have enjoyable travels and a wonderful (as can be these days, for some it&amp;#39;s gruesome) beginnings of 2024 ... See you at 37c3 or elsewhere!</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111641006313294038</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111641006313294038</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 12:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>#chatmail is not a replacement for Whatsapp in the traditional sense. It&amp;#39;s a small machine that can be tweaked in many ways. The tweakability of the e-mail system is in it&amp;#39;s DNA and practises ... that is the antithesis to WA if you like :) What drives nine.testrun.org, the first public chatmail service, is fully visible at https://github.com/deltachat/chatmail -- a minimalist config and setup, some python modules and tests, standard postfix/dovecot. co-incidentally pretty fast but there is a twist ;) Delta Chat messaging screen with echo-bot: One said says &quot;Hi&quot;, the bot answers &quot;Hi&quot;. One sight says &quot;Oh!&quot; and 0.24 seconds later the bot says &quot;Oh!&quot; One says &quot;That was fast&quot; and the bot answers. All 6 messages were typed, received and seen in 4.16 seconds overall.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111586633840591278</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111586633840591278</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 21:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Today, we are unveiling chatmail services, making onboarding with #deltachat a breeze, with peace of mind. #chatmail marks a major milestone, answering the practical question of &amp;quot;where can i get a deltachat-ready account&amp;quot; for myself and friends? Read more on https://delta.chat/en/2023-12-13-chatmail The chatmail logo, an @ with a speech bubble.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111574517097362272</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 18:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Seems google/apple&amp;#39;s push notifications services are regularly queried by state authorities for obtaining user data -- see this german @netzpolitik_feed https://netzpolitik.org/2023/push-dienste-behoerden-fragen-apple-und-google-nach-nutzern-von-messenger-apps/ -- #deltachat only uses apple&amp;#39;s push notifications on iOS for &amp;quot;heartbeat&amp;quot; services -- to ensure the app can show messages for their user (and many users are asking for tighter integration). On Android, Desktop and #ubuntutouch platforms currently no push notifications are used or needed, also no heartbeat ones.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111538544523935897</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 09:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>If you are looking for alternatives to Android, then #ubuntutouch from https://mastodon.social/@ubports is a mobile platform where @lk108 implemented the nicely working DeltaTouch app which also just released guaranteed end-to-end encryption, being very much on par with the other platforms, see https://social.tchncs.de/@lk108/111517563343219731 Pixel3a phone with UbuntuTouch operating system and running DeltaTouch app showing a chatlist with Lothar, a deltatouch group, a registration chat with ubuntuone, and some other chats.</title>
        <link>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</link>
        <guid>https://chaos.social/@delta/111532647776044900</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>