<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: I took a look at the AOSP information at https://source.android.com/docs/securit ... 2024-09-01 and it looks a lot like out of bounds write fixes aplenty in the Quallcomm WLAN code for September. Similar for August patches - https://source.android.com/docs/securit ... 2024-08-01 I'm not smart enough to know if any of that would impact what we are seeing, but maybe someone else has a nose for the news in the of the details. -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12368#p12368</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12368#p12368</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-10-03T23:04:13+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: it's not even a major version release - I don't even know that this is a documented Android change / something we can code around. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12365#p12365</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12365#p12365</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-10-03T15:41:44+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: Hey @arkasha does this give any leads for a code-solution to the Pixel issues, or do we just need a user advisory to enable “Keep screen on” for best results? -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12360#p12360</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12360#p12360</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-10-02T23:53:46+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: i can confirm now that &quot;screen on&quot; solves the problem. How usable that is, is another topic... Data from a short run, all 3 phones on the dashboard from a car: S10: Wifi: 2250 Cells: 25 S20: Wifi: 2542 Cells: 28 P9: Wifi: 2737 Cells: 48 (Bluetooth i post once the upload is done, quite a backlog right now) so the Pixel 9 holds now 1st place in my phone fleet, but only when i can let the screen on. Plot with the data shows how many more scans the P9 makes: -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12359#p12359</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12359#p12359</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-10-02T17:32:34+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: Appreciate you guys, we really do! -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12353#p12353</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12353#p12353</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T21:48:52+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: we're doing some backfill calculation - the queue will catch up! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12352#p12352</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12352#p12352</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T21:35:41+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: Not dumb at all! The app only has so much real-estate to show what's going on, so 'unprocessed' just means &quot;waiting for the kittens&quot; generally. It is curious though, watching the Upload/trilateration queue continue to grow here on the website, my waiting files keep moving farther back (was #974, now #986). I was thinking files would hold their location in the queue. The waiting, it's the hardest part -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12349#p12349</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12349#p12349</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T14:54:00+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: Ok, gotcha. Its just not obvious to some (ie me or Google) that a CSV error on my local device is due to a server backlog. As I said, first time in 10 years seeing it. Sorry for being dumb. Thanks, -thebaldgek</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12348#p12348</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12348#p12348</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T14:42:07+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: There are about 2300 files in the Trilateralization queue right now. I'm sure the WigleKittens are working furiously to clear things, and that the admins are keeping them well fed along the way. Hopefully it's not the external goobers attacking the site and causing issues again... https://wigle.net/stats#processing -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12347#p12347</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12347#p12347</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T14:14:39+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Android app error: CSV not processed. Trilaterating...: Been wardriving for about 10 years (longer before WIgle) and never ever seen this error. Google is returning zero results. Here is a screenshot of one of the Androids showing the error. https://imgur.com/a/aY65VmV Both Android phones (Pixel 8 and Pixel 5) show the last two files with the same error. I have rebooted one of the phones and it made no change. Pulling down and refreshing the list makes no change. EDIT: It's been this way on both phones for about 14 hours. (ie overnight) How can I get the files to finish and upload? (A few hours driving specific routes in there!) Thanks. -thebaldgek</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12346#p12346</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12346#p12346</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T13:39:48+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: Good find, I will have to run some tests with the screen set to stay on. The Pixel 6 is still beast-mode for BlueTooth, so it's a bummer Google busted something in the past couple updates. There's very little detail on what was fixed -- would we be able to suss out any of the changes in the ASOP release code? I've never gone spelunking there before... -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12345#p12345</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12345#p12345</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-29T04:14:13+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: that does not sound good But i might have found a little hope today Did the same thing again (with some more phones), and on the last bit i enabled &quot;keep screen active&quot; on the p9. That had a effect Right at the start the P9 is faster, then it goes into sleep or something, some sort of battery safer? Lastly with the screen on it starts catching up to the S20 Thats it so far, will continue in the next days -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12338#p12338</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12338#p12338</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-27T20:02:50+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: The last 2 security updates from Google have effected many Pixel phones. You are not the only person that had a pixel go from their best performer to their worst. August 5, 2024 first update turned my pixel 6 into the worst performing phone in my setup. September 5, 2024 second security update that many people started to notice pixel performance drops. Haven't heard of any resolutions to the problem. Aside from downgrading to previous versions of Android on unlocked phones, Verizon still locks the phones and the process to get them unlocked is a tedious one. Or installing grapheneOS which I'm told resolves those issues. -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12337#p12337</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12337#p12337</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-26T17:08:23+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: Hello, i compared some phones in the past and so far the Samsung S20 is &quot;the best&quot; for me, see here: viewtopic.php?t=2498#p11121 Now i have the Pixel 9 Pro and its so bad im wondering if i do something wrong, or the phone is broken A comparison between the S20 and the P9Pro, both on the dashboard from a car, driving a bit around. List showing the total found items for Wifi, Bluetooth and Cells: S20 W: 3359 B: 1544 C: 100 P9Pro W: 550 B:1628 C: 100 The Pixel 9 Pro is about 6x worse than the S20, thats a difference i have never seen before comparing phones. Bluetooth and Cells look good. Yes i have the developer options active and scan throttle off, is there anything else i can do? Does somebody here also have a P9? or other Pixel with good results? -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12336#p12336</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12336#p12336</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-26T15:47:04+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for something that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers?For a low-cost Android phone with good GPS performance, I'd recommend looking at older models like the Moto G series or Samsung Galaxy S5. They usually have reliable GPS and decent battery life, and you can find them for a good price on eBay. As for the CDMA/GSM world phones, yes, they should be able to detect both types of towers, which could enhance your Wigle experience. Just make sure GPS performance is solid on the model you choose! -husnain11221</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12303#p12303</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12303#p12303</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-07T04:49:18+00:00</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>