<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Top 8 secret tips of writing a perfect essay nobody told you about: Top 8 secret tips of writing a perfect essay nobody told you about It is not easy to write a perfect essay. It takes time, effort, discipline to do this. And if you are struggling with it, then you are not alone. Most students have to deal with this problem at least once during their academic career to write my essay. There are several tips and tricks that can help you become a better writer and make your essays more interesting for the reader. These tips can be divided into two groups: first group is about the content of your essay; second group is about how you should take care of writing process itself. This article is a list of 8 secret tips of writing a perfect essay. It will help you overcome these obstacles and finally produce an essay that will get you the grade you deserve in your assessment. However let&amp;amp;rsquo;s discuss some key tips before: 1) When it comes to essays, the most important thing is to stay organized. You can use various methods for this: from making a rough outline to writing down all the points on small pieces of paper and shuffling them around until they make sense to write an essay. 2) A lot of people think that it is a good idea to start with the conclusion in mind, but I disagree with this approach because it forces you to spend most of your time proving what has already been established. 3) Whenever possible, try coming up with something personal about yourself when brainstorming topics. This is because when you write about something, your personal relevant experience cannot only boost the level of confident writing but also increase the level of quality content. If we provide a crux of tips then there are some eight tips can be find extremely guiding.&amp;amp;nbsp; Secret tips to write a perfect essay: Keep a dictionary by your side and use it as often as possible. Read as much as you can, from novels to newspapers or magazines, from history to science. Write with the most straightforward language possible, and delete all unnecessary words from your sentences to write thebest assignment service for your essay. Never be afraid of making mistakes! Read everything aloud before you send it off - if anything sounds wrong, then change it before submitting it for final approval! Proofread the essay twice before submitting it for final approval - one a day after you have written a rough draft and one just before submitting it for final approval! Do not ever plagiarize anything - unless you are working on an assignment and you cannot help yourself from using key concepts of theories from books and journals. Never doubt your writing and always check from authentic tools to eradicate grammatical errors and other related issues. You should also include following points: - You should start your essay with an attention-grabbing intro that will make the reader want to read further; - It's important to refrain from using clich&amp;amp;eacute;s in your writing; - Try not Writing an argumentative essay is not easy. It takes time, patience, and creativity to come up with an essay that will impress the reader. This article will provide you with some tips on how to write your essay the right way. These are; - Research your topic and read books on it - Make sure to use a good font and font size - Always proofread your work before submitting it - Try to use a variety of sentence structures in your essays for better flow - Start every paragraph with a sentence that is easy to understand When it comes to writing a perfect essay, we all know that there are no secrets. It is not like magic where you can enter a secret password and get the desired output. But when it comes to writing an essay, there are some things that others may not have told you about which can help improve your essay writing skills. We have tried to portray the essential tips in our essay. Likewise, also take care of somethings too; Use active voice: This is one of the most important tips in an essay and in any type of text for that matter. It improves readability and makes your sentences more powerful and effective. Not only this but it also makes your sentences shorter and clearer to understand. You should use active voice in all essays or any other type of texts . More Related Resources: Narrative Essay - A Complete Writing Guide with Examples Citation Styles: APA, MLA, Chicago, Turabian How to Write a Persuasive Essay - Step by Step Guide -danielanderson</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2002&amp;p=11079#p11079</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2002&amp;p=11079#p11079</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-09T04:53:59</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>BLE scanning rig: I'm trying to use a Cyprus Bluetooth board in my setup and although it seems to work, it only reports about half the number of Bluetooth devices compared to the Wigle app. I was wondering if this is due to the window and interval sizes in my code - being a newbie I don't have much idea what these should be set to. The default in the example code I'm using is '96' for the scan interval and '48' for the scan window (which I think is times 0.625ms, so 60ms and 30ms respectively). Does anyone know if these are a good starting point? (I'm not concerned about battery life at this point). Many thanks. -sd4664</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-20T17:40:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: This is not my original idea, it's my practical implementation of the Ez-10 corner reflector. It makes omnis directional like a dish would but it's less picky about conditions. You can make this thing in 15 minutes, it costs nothing and it folds for storage. I got a 10 dBm signal difference to a faraway access point. Materials: Your favorite USB wifi adapter + USB extension cable I recommend a Terow ROW02CD (MediaTek MT7612U) with CD driver https://smile.amazon.com/dp/B086L6TR6G/ Boxcutter Rectangular box, as big as you can feasibly make and use recommended: used USPS 1095 sized box approx: 15&quot; (L) x 12&quot; (W) x 3-1/8&quot;(H) Shipping Tape Aluminum Foil Warning: Exceeding EIRP limits is generally illegal 1. Make two cuts into your box to chop off one of the short sides. Your box should now open like a trifold. 2. Cut off the folding flaps from the top of the box. Save them. 3. You will make slots and thread a cardboard flap through for structural support. Cut slots near the top of the box. 4. As neatly as you can, grab your reel of aluminum foil. Tape aluminum foil on the two inside walls of the box. 5. Take off your antennas if they are removable. Make a hole and jam your adapter through. Hook the antennas back up. Hook the adapter to the USB extension cable. 6. Thread flap through slots 7. If you have a two antenna adapter, deploy them in a V shape. You may hang the top antenna off the flap for support. Adjustments: -Connect to the AP and run &quot;watch -n0 iwconfig&quot; in Linux. Steer your antenna towards the AP. Stop steering when bit rate, link quality and signal level look good. -Indoors = Signals will bounce. If you do not have direct line of sight sometimes pointing slightly away from the AP works better. -Beamforming may affect results -Making the walls bigger will improve gain with diminishing returns -My reflector is probably incomplete since I don't have any foil in the middle. I don't know if putting it that close to the adapter causes interference, will test later. References: http://www.freeantennas.com/projects/Ez-10/ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corner_reflector_antenna -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-14T03:50:10</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I recommend the Samsung S5. I use one as my personal phone. Stock Android supports VOLTE, custom roms don't. You might not be able to make calls with it past 2022. It's had continuous LineageOS support for about half a decade. Street value $50-$100, cheap OEM batteries, has all the radios. The only model you should get in North America is the SM-G900T. All of them have unlocked bootloaders and it generally has the most useful 4G bands. &quot;A&quot; model is locked and &quot;V&quot; model is 50/50 depending on whether the phone came with exploitable hardware. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-28T02:16:13</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: My little Samsung Core Prime will run 8+ hours as long as it doesn't get too warm. It is slow to GPS lock, but not more than 2 minutes usually. My S7 Edge easily runs for 4-5 hours on battery, have to keep the screen off on that one for better life. It'll get a GPS lock in my basement office in less than 10 seconds, very quick! -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10985#p10985</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10985#p10985</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T16:41:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: generally its pretty battery friendly - most &quot;new&quot; phones I have can use it for hours on end, and the pixel 5 can run it all day. Have you changed the settings to scan as quickly as possible? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10984#p10984</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10984#p10984</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T16:14:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for something that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers? I'm looking for something as well.. But it seems whatever I use it drains the battery really quick. Is this normal or not? -showline</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10983#p10983</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10983#p10983</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T13:42:38</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Wigle mobile rig for scanning odd Frequencies: Indeed, the wifi standard before 2012, allowed 802.11g to use so called &quot;quarter- and half-clocked channels&quot; (5MHz and 10MHz respectively). They carry multiple advantages, including improved noise immunity (delay spread due to up to 4x the symbol length), higher allowed transmit power (up to 2x due to power spectral density regulations) and less problems with exposed nodes and neighboring BSS's. Many good chipsets and drivers still support it even for 802.11n, including Atheros on OpenWrt (they have their own debug patches to enable it). Too bad scanning, channel steering, channel raster allocation and neighbor coexistence would have been such a pain so they simply gave the whole thing up. I agree that it is quite useful for P2P links or to penetrate foliage. Using such modes are not complying to the standard according to 802.11 (except for emergency response at certain frequencies), but they should still be legal according to the various ISM regulations in most countries. I am using a Mikrotik outdoor antenna and radio from home and it can be set up to look at 5 MHz steps which can see in between the standard channels. There are usually WiFi links on 5 GHz band people have set on non standard frequencies, presumably to avoid detection and minimise interference from other devices. I dont think its just my area that it occurs either, i have seen others. -kurz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2860&amp;p=10982#p10982</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2860&amp;p=10982#p10982</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-19T11:59:28</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Pixel 4as aren't too bad, but if you want a real budget pick, and older Pixel used on ebay might be a good purchase! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10972#p10972</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10972#p10972</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-08T16:26:34</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for somet https://9apps.ooo/ hing that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers? https://9apps.ooo/ -mikipetri74</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10971#p10971</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10971#p10971</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-07T10:55:40</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: @arshasa no the gps does not depend on the system clock time. From what I have understood, but it may differ from device to device, may be ? I had problem with u-blox 7 based mouse usb gps, and I had to use A-gps, and finally sometimes not working so I bought on ebay a new one with ublox-8 chip called BN-808. It's cheap but it took a long time to come from china. Now, with that new gps, no more worries, and it has a fix in a minute (or less) without even needing a-gps. @SkywardLark I have forked a github project to get A-GPS data in linux with a simple python script: it's there https://github.com/solsticedhiver/ublox-agps yes. solsTicedhiver that's me too And the wooden box was too heavy to carry so now I am using a mask box, the one very popular now during covid times. -zebul666</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10970#p10970</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10970#p10970</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-06T19:57:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: The main issue is the gps taking a long time for a first fix on cold boot. Could take 10 minutes with a clear sky.Your VK-172 seems like it has a u-blox (7?) chipset. You can warm start the GPS by getting assist data from the internet, it's saved in storage. The company offers a Windows-only software called &quot;U-Center&quot; for GPS management. 1. Get a token here: https://www.u-blox.com/en/assistnow-ser ... quest-form 2. Plug your GPS into a computer and start U-Center 3. Receiver &amp;gt; Connection &amp;gt; Select ComX (your GPS) 4. Tools &amp;gt; AssistNow Online &amp;gt; AssistNow Online, GPS Only (u-blox 5 - 7) Put the token you got in &quot;Server Token.&quot; Most of the fields are self-explanatory. Click &quot;Download &amp;amp; Transfer Now&quot; when you're done. Now you can unplug your GPS and put it back into your rig. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10964#p10964</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10964#p10964</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-03T22:51:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: nice - I did that with my pi w zero rig! The thing I'm not clear on is whether GPS fix time is chicken/egg with the clock -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10963#p10963</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10963#p10963</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-03T16:17:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: @arkasha you could update the system clock from the gps one it has a fix. So you don't need a RTC clock. I failed to set it up with ntpd so I am using chrony instead. It is jsut a simple line to add to the config file -zebul666</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10962#p10962</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10962#p10962</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-03T15:43:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: godspeed and good hunting! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10960#p10960</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10960#p10960</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-03T01:42:51</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>