<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: Much love &amp;amp; respect to all who created/work on and those who continue to work on this amazing project/love of mine! Such projects are rare, which is a shame, but allows me to appreciate WiGLE even that much more. It's allowed me to dive into an area I was only somewhat familiar with and become much more knowledgeable (and intrigued, as always) THANKS and congrats on 23 years!!! Thanks also for the hard work! tz222zt -TZz222zZT</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12314#p12314</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12314#p12314</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-13T23:00:14+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: 19 years here and it's been a blast. Amazing how much the WiFi density has grown in that time. -mark571</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12310#p12310</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12310#p12310</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-09T11:39:14+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: Are you sure you missed some? *chuckles* -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12308#p12308</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12308#p12308</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-09T03:20:10+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: Beers all around. I've got some more APs I need to go find. -ccie4526</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12307#p12307</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12307#p12307</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-09T01:19:22+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: Congrats! I have had a ton of fun these past 20 years of participation, and it's been so cool to see the community and the technology grow and prosper! #allTheWifi -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12306#p12306</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12306#p12306</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-08T15:10:09+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: 23 years of WiGLE: Congratulations! -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12305#p12305</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12305#p12305</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-07T19:23:12+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>23 years of WiGLE: Somehow this hobby project has lasted for 23 years - a truly epic run. We owe that run in no small part to this amazing community of hobbyists, security researchers, and tireless walkers/runners/drivers/skaters/riders. Thank you for being a part of a delightfully weird and creative community, and for making this project a success - give yourselves a round of applause! Skidoo, -ark and the WiGLE team -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12304#p12304</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12304#p12304</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-07T18:27:38+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: Mine are working again too. My failure the other day was 20240722-00444 using Wigle 2.86 on Android, but I resubmitted the file a few days later once the queue numbers were a bit lower and it went through fine. -mrmalkovich</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12264#p12264</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12264#p12264</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-26T01:07:32+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: I also had a failed upload when the Q was very full, first time ever since the age of dinosaurs when I first joined Wigle.net. 20240722-00736 It was successful after resubmitting it later. It was just a single device small run which surprised me when I saw the failure. S24 Ultra with Wigle WiFi 2.86. Upload showed successful on the phone, but showed failed status on wigle.net later. -mark571</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12260#p12260</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12260#p12260</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-24T11:22:49+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: things are queueing just fine - otherwise the queue wouldn't be full! we've processed an absolutely unprecedented number of files in the last week. regarding a failed upload, does it happen when you retry? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12259#p12259</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12259#p12259</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-23T17:13:51+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: Server(s) seems to be swamped - nothing actually seems to queue, so there's almost 3000 trilaterating right now. Upload failed last night and at this rate it looks like it might be a few days before things are back to normal. -mrmalkovich</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12258#p12258</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12258#p12258</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-23T02:31:36+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: ahhh so that's why the queue times are insane. -Xenokilla</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12256#p12256</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12256#p12256</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-22T02:31:55+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: oh no! how could we have provided better notice? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12255#p12255</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12255#p12255</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-21T16:16:46+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: So so bummed that I essentially missed this! Was really looking forward to it too! Well it will be interesting to see what happens regardless. -TZz222zZT</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12254#p12254</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12254#p12254</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-21T16:10:22+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: that'a US/Pacific &quot;DEF CON&quot; time. uploads go from noon today to the last second of Sunday night in that timezone. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12252#p12252</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12252#p12252</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-19T13:56:19+00:00</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>