<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Sex Toy Security and WiGLE popularity: thank you - there should be one if you're logged in -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11369#p11369</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11369#p11369</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-11-03T14:34:19</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Sex Toy Security and WiGLE popularity: We still don't have a Report button in this area, but the last two comments were spam! -kurz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11368#p11368</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11368#p11368</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-11-03T10:03:59</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Google Pie and Wifi Wardriving: All releases 10 through 13 (so far!) allow de-throttling. If you don't de-throttle on those releases, they'll still work, but they'll only be able to scan twice per-minute. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11326#p11326</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11326#p11326</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-09-11T16:59:03</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Google Pie and Wifi Wardriving: It seems to me that the Google pixel 6 running Android 13 is capable of war driving. Even before I Disabled &quot; Wi-Fi scan throttling &quot; in developer settings It seemed to work properly, I have not actually tried war diving yet hopefully I can test it against my working phone sometime in the future -scottthepainter</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11325#p11325</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11325#p11325</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-09-11T04:32:29</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 30: Hi! See you all there! -bobzilla</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11307#p11307</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11307#p11307</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-10T12:12:55</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>DEF CON 30: DC30 is happening this week, and bobzilla and arkasha will be there! Find us and say &quot;hi&quot; for swag! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11306#p11306</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11306#p11306</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-10T06:01:25</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Highway to the...: nvm, you'd just registered, we were able to back it out. you're clear to re-register. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11304#p11304</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11304#p11304</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-04T21:39:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Highway to the...: email us at WiGLE-admin[at]wigle.net from your account's email address -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11303#p11303</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11303#p11303</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-04T21:36:47</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Highway to the...: How do I get my block reset? I was trying to set it up and some how it selected a pretty much impossible to drive area. I was trying to create a rectangle that was not vertically orientated and instead did done that was super vertical. -i_do_dew</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11302#p11302</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11302#p11302</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-04T21:31:50</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Highway to the...: ... #WWWD2022 AS A REMINDER: the clock is ticking and as of now we are keeping score. It's still anyone's game, it's early. Join in at https://wigle.net/wwwdintro/DC30 -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11299#p11299</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11299#p11299</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-03T04:25:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: wireless signals are strange, and phones and driver software even stranger! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11295#p11295</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11295#p11295</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-31T16:22:11</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: I noticed that while scanning with the APK in the background, there have been some cases where networks are recorded way far away from their true source, most likely my weird configs but is accountable to the random outliers? I'm sure other travellers with better setups can eventually &quot;correct&quot; it in someway but I wouldn't think a random house has a gas pump. -CabinetVCase</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11294#p11294</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11294#p11294</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-31T06:33:55</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>World-Wide War Drive, RFHS and DEF CON 30: Greetings WiFriends! The fine folks at the RFHS have invited us to hold a World-Wide War Drive in conjunction with the DEF CON 30 RFHS, and we have answered the call. Registration is now open at the DC30 WWWD landing page Since DEF CON and the RFCTF will be in-person this year, we've elected to host the WWWD from August 1st through the 7th. Your score WILL have a bearing on your RFCTF score.... BUT WAIT, there's MORE! Since we'll be able to compete in-person at DEF CON, there will a SECOND PART to the WWWD in Las Vegas during DEF CON 30. Watch this space, Twitter, and the RFHS contest page for further details. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11293#p11293</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11293#p11293</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-29T21:51:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel update RQ3A.210905.001 breaks GPS: This is a great note - we've gotten a lot of questions from Xiaomi users, but don't have any test devices to figure this out on. Thanks! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11292#p11292</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11292#p11292</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-25T16:27:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel update RQ3A.210905.001 breaks GPS: When I started with WiGLE, I had a similar problem with my Xiaomi Redmi Note 8 Pro. Same problem also with the Note 11 Pro. WiGLE stopped working when it was not in the foreground, i.e. on screen. Problem is that Xiaomi has implemented some powersaving measures, one of them being giving background processes none, or little, processing time. I solved that by browing the settings: Privacy_protection-&amp;gt;Special_permissions-&amp;gt;Battery_optimization-&amp;gt;WiGLE_WiFi_Wardriving, and select &quot;Don't optimize&quot; there. This allows the app to stay active in the background. Also check this: long press the 'Wigle WiFi' icon, select 'App info' there, Select 'Batteru saver', and select 'No restrictions' there. Now my WiGLE always runs as it should do. This will probably be so on most Xiaomi phones, and even most phones running the MIUI user interface. -josn</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11291#p11291</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11291#p11291</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-25T15:47:20</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>