<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: You shouldn't need to re-run every time, but installing updates MAY require it. Keep us posted about your results? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11765#p11765</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11765#p11765</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-10T15:50:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: Well, if you're sophisticated enough to install a new OS: first: try the adb trick to remove the throttle on 9; it doesn't work on every model/os. if it works, no need to resort to anything extreme. ( Code: adb shell settings put global wifi_scan_throttle_enabled 0) second: https://lineageos.org/ is pretty niceThanks a! It seems to have worked really well, I'm getting 1 scan every 1-30ms at worst! Considering the human eye takes around 13-400x that to blink, I'd call that a win! It'll absolutely slaughter my battery life, I presume, but I imagine I'll pick up a lot more now! In case you need it for any statistics on who it works/doesn't work for, I'm using a Samsung Galaxy S8 SM-G950U running Android 9 (Also, do I need to rerun that command every time I restart? Will security patch updates affect it?) -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11764#p11764</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11764#p11764</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-10T09:25:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: It is still possible to use Samsung Galaxy S4 for wifi scanning?: yes the S4 is ok, i use it with LOS18.1 (Android 11) https://wiki.lineageos.org/devices/jfltexx/ Here is a comparison against the S7 and S20: viewtopic.php?t=2498#p11121 -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11761#p11761</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11761#p11761</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-08T16:36:52</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: Well, if you're sophisticated enough to install a new OS: first: try the adb trick to remove the throttle on 9; it doesn't work on every model/os. if it works, no need to resort to anything extreme. ( Code: adb shell settings put global wifi_scan_throttle_enabled 0) second: https://lineageos.org/ is pretty nice -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11753#p11753</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11753#p11753</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:06:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Maybe phone models, but not necessarily OS versions. Just remember to disable throttling on 10 and up. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11752#p11752</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11752#p11752</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:04:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: ESP32 or ESP8266 Wigle and Lora - Tracker: You can locate individual MAC addresses using the API (without using the whole packet), but we don't provide a networked geolocation service at this time, since we want to avoid knowing where anyone is at any given time. https://api.wigle.net for the API options, you're probably most interested in &quot;network search&quot; we do have an embedded location system for which we publish regular extracts, but it's probably no precise enough to locate stolen property, it's more for providing terrestrial assistance for embedded/non-networked devices in getting a GPS lock. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=78z5H0rv-wE -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11751#p11751</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11751#p11751</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:01:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: It's a pile of things: Old radios/drivers/OSes might just not tune as fast (and so don't scan as quickly) Driver versions can have a huge impact, making previously slow phones fast and vice versa on upgrade Android 9 throttles WiFi scan speed (and is hard to de-throttle) Android 10 and up also throttle scanning, but if you activate developer mode, you can turn that off. Cheers, -aThanks for that, Arkasha. Besides Android 9 and assuming that the throttle (if present) was disabled, is there any &quot;best&quot; Android version for wardriving? Or would the actual impact of the version itself be mostly minimal, and it is the internal drivers and age of the Wi-Fi module primarily affecting things? -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11750#p11750</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11750#p11750</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T11:32:29</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Custom ROMs for wardriving?: Hi all, I picked up a Samsung Galaxy S8 from eBay for 50 bucks. I picked it up solely for wardriving with the official Wigle app. Unfortunately, after ordering it I've realised that the highest Android version the S8 can support is Pie (9), which I recall has such strict and undisableable throttles on Wi-Fi scans, it's basically impossible to wardrive with. Are there any custom ROMs I could flash which would get along well with Wigle? I've never rooted/jailbroken a phone before, but I'm sure with a few guides from XDA I'll be able to figure it out. Thanks -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11749#p11749</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11749#p11749</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T11:24:48</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>ESP32 or ESP8266 Wigle and Lora - Tracker: Hi, and apols - i usually search for previous answers more but... Wigle seems perfect for geolocating, and im after a bike theft tracker - are there any projects around that use 1. low cost low power ESP8266 or ESP32 ($3 and $9) 2. Lora or similar free longish range comms (works well in nz and free for low volume anywhere) 3. Send packet of Wifi strengths to server - which allows stolen tracker locater like functionality ?? If not - can i submit a packet from a scan and get back a geoolocation say anywhere in my country (nz) ?? Thanks and keep up the great work -kiwifirsty</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11748#p11748</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11748#p11748</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T01:30:47</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: It's a pile of things: Old radios/drivers/OSes might just not tune as fast (and so don't scan as quickly) Driver versions can have a huge impact, making previously slow phones fast and vice versa on upgrade Android 9 throttles WiFi scan speed (and is hard to de-throttle) Android 10 and up also throttle scanning, but if you activate developer mode, you can turn that off. Cheers, -a -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11742#p11742</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11742#p11742</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-25T17:42:02</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Apologies for necro'ing this post, but if I may ask a perhaps silly question, is it the Android version or hardware limitations that generally cause slow scan times for Wi-Fi/BT? -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11741#p11741</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11741#p11741</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-23T12:47:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: It is still possible to use Samsung Galaxy S4 for wifi scanning?: If you upgrade to Android 5 (and you really should), you'll be able to side-load older (2.67 will be the last) versions of the app. The Google Play Store won't allow us to keep our listing and support devices that old, sadly. We'll be signing and releasing an &quot;Oldroid&quot; branch as well, but I don't know if the community has an appetite for backporting features and updates - we'll see! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11739#p11739</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11739#p11739</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-16T15:33:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>It is still possible to use Samsung Galaxy S4 for wifi scanning?: Hi, I bought two Samsung Galaxy S4 phones at a good price. Are they still usable for Wigle scanning? are they still supported by the app? I think yes, but I'd rather ask here, thanks. -lukaskicz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11738#p11738</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11738#p11738</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-16T05:29:39</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: iOS App for Wardriving: we continue to push, but the API isn't supported and we can't list on the app store. If anyone manages to get anything through apple. don't hesitate to let us know! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11721#p11721</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11721#p11721</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-04T23:41:59</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: iOS App for Wardriving: Apple never opened up the APIs necessary to build a war driving app for iOS after squashing attempts to keep WiFiFoFum alive via fun hacks. Kismet worked/works on MacBooks with the right USB adapter, I haven't messed around with that for a long time... -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11720#p11720</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11720#p11720</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-04T22:28:55</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>