<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: that does not sound good But i might have found a little hope today Did the same thing again (with some more phones), and on the last bit i enabled &quot;keep screen active&quot; on the p9. That had a effect Right at the start the P9 is faster, then it goes into sleep or something, some sort of battery safer? Lastly with the screen on it starts catching up to the S20 Thats it so far, will continue in the next days -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12338#p12338</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12338#p12338</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-27T20:02:50+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: The last 2 security updates from Google have effected many Pixel phones. You are not the only person that had a pixel go from their best performer to their worst. August 5, 2024 first update turned my pixel 6 into the worst performing phone in my setup. September 5, 2024 second security update that many people started to notice pixel performance drops. Haven't heard of any resolutions to the problem. Aside from downgrading to previous versions of Android on unlocked phones, Verizon still locks the phones and the process to get them unlocked is a tedious one. Or installing grapheneOS which I'm told resolves those issues. -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12337#p12337</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12337#p12337</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-26T17:08:23+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Pixel 9 (Pro) its so bad, wow...: Hello, i compared some phones in the past and so far the Samsung S20 is &quot;the best&quot; for me, see here: viewtopic.php?t=2498#p11121 Now i have the Pixel 9 Pro and its so bad im wondering if i do something wrong, or the phone is broken A comparison between the S20 and the P9Pro, both on the dashboard from a car, driving a bit around. List showing the total found items for Wifi, Bluetooth and Cells: S20 W: 3359 B: 1544 C: 100 P9Pro W: 550 B:1628 C: 100 The Pixel 9 Pro is about 6x worse than the S20, thats a difference i have never seen before comparing phones. Bluetooth and Cells look good. Yes i have the developer options active and scan throttle off, is there anything else i can do? Does somebody here also have a P9? or other Pixel with good results? -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12336#p12336</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12336#p12336</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-26T15:47:04+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for something that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers?For a low-cost Android phone with good GPS performance, I'd recommend looking at older models like the Moto G series or Samsung Galaxy S5. They usually have reliable GPS and decent battery life, and you can find them for a good price on eBay. As for the CDMA/GSM world phones, yes, they should be able to detect both types of towers, which could enhance your Wigle experience. Just make sure GPS performance is solid on the model you choose! -husnain11221</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12303#p12303</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12303#p12303</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-07T04:49:18+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: BU 353N not working on PI: I was only able to get my unit working by applying the &quot;-b&quot; to GPSD.conf gps options. Ive tested several times, and unless this option is in place, which is basically a type of read only mode from the sensor, GPSD doesn't communicate with it properly. I am replacing the unit in any case because it was just one I used temporarily, and it only has access to US GPS constellation vs a GNSS model. I also had to restart gpsd.service, and gpsd.socket each time I unplugged the unit. Linux was creating a /dev/ttyUSB1 at times instead of the /dev/ttyUSB0 I have entered into the config files for everything. When I notice /dev/tty1 instead of ttyUSB0, I unplug/plug again and recheck to make sure it has reverted back. -chronos7</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12296#p12296</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12296#p12296</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-03T13:04:47+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WarFlying: Hopping in to re-invigorate a newly necro'd thread, but just today I started putting together the bag of parts to go warflying with a small fixed wing drone, hauling not much more than a Pi Zero W, GPS, and a LoRa link. If I get anywhere at all, I'll be improving the antenna later.How did this work out for you? Also toying with he idea of using a toy quad and a phone or pi0 -mdkFree</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12295#p12295</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12295#p12295</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-09-03T07:42:12+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: USB C antenna for phones: Thanks for the answer. I was searching for something simple and effective. Rooting my phone is not what i had in mind I will continue having it in my pocket then! -Thor3333</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12289#p12289</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12289#p12289</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-08-27T15:29:20+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: USB C antenna for phones: It's not possible to attach an external antenna to most (all?) phone WiFi chips, nor is it necessary or advisable for stumbling. Most of us just use our phones in our pockets/backpacks/running armbands. If you're talking about external radios, it's possible to do this, but requires rooting your phone and installing an OS that allows you to use the USB OTG connector to act as host for that device - again, not necessary or advisable unless your phone is supported by one of those OSes and you don't really care to use it as a phone any longer. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12287#p12287</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12287#p12287</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-08-27T15:22:34+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>USB C antenna for phones: Hi, I’m happy to contribute to this project, but only with my phone in my pocket. Does anyone knows of a USB C wifi antenna compatible with android? 15-20€ would be a nice price range. Thanks! -Thor3333</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12285#p12285</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12285#p12285</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-08-27T14:55:43+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Raspberry Pi for drone and car: I might make a Python script. Right now i can only test it with a rpi 3b+ and 5 (rpi4 will probably work too). It should be pretty easy as the csv format is simple as described here: [url]https://api.wigle.net/csvFormat.html/url] and it could be uploaded via api. So stay tuned -Laqua</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12257#p12257</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12257#p12257</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-22T17:40:52+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet files for upload: only the WiGLE .csv file can or should be uploaded. The .kismet file contains additional information we can't use and don't want (for privacy and safety reasons) -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12214#p12214</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12214#p12214</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-05-24T15:14:56+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Kismet files for upload: In the 'wardriving' mode of Kismet, it generates 2 files. A .kismet and .wiglecsv Last drive the .kismet file was 195.5MB and the .wiglecsv was 8.5MB. The .kismet file doesn't seem to want to upload, but do I need to? Or is the .wiglecsv file all that's needed? -clickwir</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12213#p12213</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12213#p12213</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-05-23T14:00:51+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WarFlying: Hopping in to re-invigorate a newly necro'd thread, but just today I started putting together the bag of parts to go warflying with a small fixed wing drone, hauling not much more than a Pi Zero W, GPS, and a LoRa link. If I get anywhere at all, I'll be improving the antenna later. -brockhold</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12161#p12161</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12161#p12161</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-26T23:29:48+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet drone on wireless router? (e.g. Linksys WRT54GL): I built one 10+ years ago. Recently found that digital signage PCs are more suitable. I've rescued three Giada VM23 boxes from the e-waste. Add a cheap USB GPS and you are good as bluetooth and wifi is built in. Three additional USB ports for more wifi adapters. Runs of 12v with a barrel plug. Easy to make a cigarette power plug adapter. I see many go for about $20. Many was sold with only 1 year Windows 10 IOT, so quickly EOL. Kali runs well on it, even with three radios, two gps and graphical user interface.It's impressive how you repurposed older hardware effectively for digital signage. The Giada VM23 boxes, coupled with USB GPS and additional WiFi adapters, offer versatile functionality. Kali Linux's compatibility breathes new life into these devices, extending their utility beyond their original scope. -Sunnyle</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12143#p12143</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12143#p12143</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-19T20:23:37+00:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Supports WPS: you can click (as a logged in user), or you can use the Basic and Advanced search functionality to get al the information regarding the point. WPS will be listed in the capabilities, which aren't part of the site rendering - check out the API for more details. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12112#p12112</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12112#p12112</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-04T16:57:44+00:00</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>