<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>GPS accuracy: Hello, when I watch the map with only my data, I can see that there are little dots in place I never went. Also some strings of points in linear alignment in odd places. Also I have data points in the middle of a ponds. Do you know if there is something that can be made to fix that and filter odd data ? -FredR</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11099#p11099</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11099#p11099</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-11-14T15:10:44</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: I think putting a small reflector behind each antenna would look the least ugly. It's also what the Ez-10 guide shows on the website. You might get away with taping foil to the wall if the router is next to it. Made a v3 for another adapter, an old 802.11b/g ALFA AWUS036H. I had a feeling old faithful would get good results. Single antenna design so no need to mount inside reflector. I eyeballed where everything should've been. You can probably ignore the min signal reading it's always bad when the adapter starts up. ~20dBm difference in software but this chipset is old so take these readings with a grain of salt. Alfa w/ only 9dBi antenna, AP nearby in unknown location: Latest Signal -58 dbm Min. Signal -71 dbm Max. Signal -48 dbm Alfa w/ 9 dBi antenna + reflector steered vaguely in the right direction: Latest Signal -38 dbm Min. Signal -74 dbm Max. Signal -30 dbm Alfa w/ 9dBi antenna + reflector perfectly steered. AP a few meters away, same room. No before photo but signal was between -10 and -20 dBmReflector: USPS 1095 almost entirely clad in foil with only a tiny gap near the top for slots/flaps AWUS036H: TX Power: Antenna: Ridiculously tall 2.4 GHz tuned dipole, probably rated 7-9 dBi. I don't remember where I got this. Stats: Kismet Research topics: -Apparently grounding the reflector can improve gain. For something this MacGyvered maybe you'd alligator clip the RP-SMA connector to a part of the reflector. If you're using a USB adapter that probably leads to ground. -How important is the thickness of the material? Would foiling the other side help? I noticed when you use this setup with the adapter in AP mode it's still possible to get a weak signal directly behind the reflector. I'm sure some of it is due to signal bounce but I'm not entirely convinced. I think some of the signal is wasted going through the single layer of foil. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11086#p11086</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11086#p11086</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-25T00:20:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: My WiFi router sits to one side of my house, on an outside wall, leaking signal into the neighbors lot. Curious how putting one of these behind the router, or each of the four antenna, would boost my signal in the farther areas of the house. Next Amazon box I receive might just have to launch a few experiments... -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11085#p11085</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11085#p11085</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-23T22:13:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: I did some internet digging. I managed to find a real commercial product that uses the same trifold reflector idea along with dimensions and photos from a guy called SkootS It is called the Hawking Tech &quot;HAI15SC 2.4GHz Hi-Gain Wireless Corner Antenna.&quot; The claimed rating is 15 dBi. The product has a 5 dBi dipole encased in plastic and a trifold corner reflector made of aluminum. They probably assumed the reflector was 10 dBi and did funky math. Seems like retail price was around $30. Well now you know, if you don't mind a flimsy product you can just build it yourself. https://web.archive.org/web/20211023100 ... fi-ant.php (Scroll down to L. Hawking Tech., 15 dBi. They are using a free web host, I don't want to kill their website) https://www.hawkingtech.com/product/hai ... -specs_tab I've attached some of the photos because I think this is hilarious. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11084#p11084</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11084#p11084</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-23T12:38:02</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: BLE scanning rig: There's a lot to learn about when this sort of thing is seen. It might be helpful to setup an environment (maybe out in the countryside) where you know exactly how many devices are in range ... but then what's the range? Your phone may simply have a greater range/better sensitivity. Good Luck - the testing environment will need to be socially distanced ... LOL. -ecramp</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11082#p11082</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11082#p11082</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-19T18:11:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>BLE scanning rig: I'm trying to use a Cyprus Bluetooth board in my setup and although it seems to work, it only reports about half the number of Bluetooth devices compared to the Wigle app. I was wondering if this is due to the window and interval sizes in my code - being a newbie I don't have much idea what these should be set to. The default in the example code I'm using is '96' for the scan interval and '48' for the scan window (which I think is times 0.625ms, so 60ms and 30ms respectively). Does anyone know if these are a good starting point? (I'm not concerned about battery life at this point). Many thanks. -sd4664</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-20T17:40:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: This is not my original idea, it's my practical implementation of the Ez-10 corner reflector. It makes omnis directional like a dish would but it's less picky about conditions. You can make this thing in 15 minutes, it costs nothing and it folds for storage. I got a 10 dBm difference in software to a faraway access point. Materials: Your favorite USB wifi adapter + USB extension cable I recommend a Terow ROW02CD (MediaTek MT7612U) with CD driver https://smile.amazon.com/dp/B086L6TR6G/ Boxcutter Rectangular box, as big as you can feasibly make and use Recommended: Used USPS 1095 priority box Approx: 15&quot; (L) x 12&quot; (W) x 3-1/8&quot;(H) Shipping Tape Aluminum Foil Warning: Exceeding EIRP limits is generally illegal. Warning 2: Highly directional equipment may skew Wigle data. Use good judgement. Instructions: 1. Make two cuts into your box to chop off one of the short sides. Your box should now open like a trifold. Save this flap. 2. You will make slots and thread the cardboard flap through for structural support. Cut slots near the top of the box on the two side walls. 3. As neatly as you can, grab your reel of aluminum foil. Tape aluminum foil on the two inside side walls of the box. 4. Take off your antennas if they are removable. Make a hole and jam your adapter through, either just the USB bits (easier to get a tight fit) or the whole thing if you need to adjust antenna/reflector distance. 5. Hook the adapter to the USB extension cable. 5. Thread flap through top slots. 6. Hook antennas back up. 7. If you have a two antenna adapter, deploy them completely parallel or in a V shape, see which one works better. You can hang the adapter from flaps, use string, zip ties for tight fit if you think it's necessary. Use MacGyver skills. Optional (?): Cover the middle panel with aluminum foil, either on the inside or the outside of the box. Try to leave no gaps but it shouldn't matter that much. Adjustments: -Connect to the AP and run &quot;watch -n0 iwconfig&quot; in Linux or equivalent stat panel. Steer your antenna towards the AP. Stop steering when bit rate, link quality and signal level look good. -Indoors = Signals will bounce and make consistent testing difficult. If you do not have direct line of sight sometimes pointing slightly away from the AP works better. -Beamforming may affect results -Making the side walls bigger will improve gain with diminishing returns -My (v1) reflector is probably incomplete since I don't have any foil in the middle. I don't know if putting it that close to the adapter causes interference, will test later. References: http://www.freeantennas.com/projects/Ez-10/ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corner_reflector_antenna Edit: Added picture of a v2 I made. I did not chop off the flaps so the box is taller and I added foil to the middle section. I've slightly updated the instructions to make them simpler. &quot;The spacing of the rods D should not be more than 0.06 (6%) of the wavelength.&quot; -Wikipedia I'm not sure if that instruction is properly cited but it would suggest you want continuous foil if possible with no gaps. The wavelength of 2.4 GHz is about 12 cm and 5 GHz is about 6 cm. 6% of those lengths is extraordinarily tiny. v2 achieved best performance with the antennas deployed parallel, while v1 seemed to like the V pattern. In terms of performance both reflectors work, I didn't compare them very hard. Someone more knowledgeable should chime in. Edit 2: Tips from an antenna design book I couldn't completely verify: -The angle of the reflector should vaguely be 90 degrees. A more narrow corner supposedly improves gain and directivity but may require larger side walls. I experimented but couldn't come up with a good conclusion. Since this contraption is kind of flimsy I found the 90 degree angle to cause least problems. -The antenna(s)' distance from the reflector's center should be between 25% and 75% of the intended wavelength, with a suggested value of 50%. So in theory: 2.4 GHz: antennas ~6.2455 cm from center 5 GHz: antennas ~2.998 cm from center This does seem to matter somewhat and could explain why I found differences from arranging the antennas full parallel vs V pattern. But even if your antennas are really far away you still get some gain. I recommend sliding your USB adapter around to see what works. Try your luck getting good clearance with your MacGyver skills. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-14T03:50:10</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I recommend the Samsung S5. I use one as my personal phone. Stock Android supports VOLTE, custom roms don't. You might not be able to make calls with it past 2022. It's had continuous LineageOS support for about half a decade. Street value $50-$100, cheap OEM batteries, has all the radios. The only model you should get in North America is the SM-G900T. All of them have unlocked bootloaders and it generally has the most useful 4G bands. &quot;A&quot; model is locked and &quot;V&quot; model is 50/50 depending on whether the phone came with exploitable hardware. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-28T02:16:13</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: My little Samsung Core Prime will run 8+ hours as long as it doesn't get too warm. It is slow to GPS lock, but not more than 2 minutes usually. My S7 Edge easily runs for 4-5 hours on battery, have to keep the screen off on that one for better life. It'll get a GPS lock in my basement office in less than 10 seconds, very quick! -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10985#p10985</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10985#p10985</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T16:41:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: generally its pretty battery friendly - most &quot;new&quot; phones I have can use it for hours on end, and the pixel 5 can run it all day. Have you changed the settings to scan as quickly as possible? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10984#p10984</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10984#p10984</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T16:14:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for something that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers? I'm looking for something as well.. But it seems whatever I use it drains the battery really quick. Is this normal or not? -showline</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10983#p10983</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10983#p10983</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-21T13:42:38</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Wigle mobile rig for scanning odd Frequencies: Indeed, the wifi standard before 2012, allowed 802.11g to use so called &quot;quarter- and half-clocked channels&quot; (5MHz and 10MHz respectively). They carry multiple advantages, including improved noise immunity (delay spread due to up to 4x the symbol length), higher allowed transmit power (up to 2x due to power spectral density regulations) and less problems with exposed nodes and neighboring BSS's. Many good chipsets and drivers still support it even for 802.11n, including Atheros on OpenWrt (they have their own debug patches to enable it). Too bad scanning, channel steering, channel raster allocation and neighbor coexistence would have been such a pain so they simply gave the whole thing up. I agree that it is quite useful for P2P links or to penetrate foliage. Using such modes are not complying to the standard according to 802.11 (except for emergency response at certain frequencies), but they should still be legal according to the various ISM regulations in most countries. I am using a Mikrotik outdoor antenna and radio from home and it can be set up to look at 5 MHz steps which can see in between the standard channels. There are usually WiFi links on 5 GHz band people have set on non standard frequencies, presumably to avoid detection and minimise interference from other devices. I dont think its just my area that it occurs either, i have seen others. -kurz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2860&amp;p=10982#p10982</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2860&amp;p=10982#p10982</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-19T11:59:28</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Pixel 4as aren't too bad, but if you want a real budget pick, and older Pixel used on ebay might be a good purchase! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10972#p10972</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10972#p10972</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-08T16:26:34</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Best Android for WigleWifi: I have a Motorola Droid 2 that I was using just for Wigle (no cell service), but lately it won't get a GPS lock. Are there any recommendations for low cost Android phones that could be picked up on eBay that work great with Wigle. I'm looking for somet https://9apps.ooo/ hing that doesn't take a year to get GPS lock and has serious battery life. Also if you had one of the CDMA/GSM world phones would that detect both towers? https://9apps.ooo/ -mikipetri74</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10971#p10971</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10971#p10971</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-07T10:55:40</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: portable home-made war-driving gear: @arshasa no the gps does not depend on the system clock time. From what I have understood, but it may differ from device to device, may be ? I had problem with u-blox 7 based mouse usb gps, and I had to use A-gps, and finally sometimes not working so I bought on ebay a new one with ublox-8 chip called BN-808. It's cheap but it took a long time to come from china. Now, with that new gps, no more worries, and it has a fix in a minute (or less) without even needing a-gps. @SkywardLark I have forked a github project to get A-GPS data in linux with a simple python script: it's there https://github.com/solsticedhiver/ublox-agps yes. solsTicedhiver that's me too And the wooden box was too heavy to carry so now I am using a mask box, the one very popular now during covid times. -zebul666</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10970#p10970</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2751&amp;p=10970#p10970</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-06T19:57:41</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>