<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: yes arkasha this is tricky to do, as the devices idealy are in the same place. Even when the phone is closer to the A pillar or centered in the windscreen it gets different results kurz, the rpi(4) is running kali linux with kismet and 2 usb wifi dongles in monitoring mode (TP-Link Archer T9UH AC1900, ALFA AWUS036NEH). Another comparison, all the RSSI values in a histogram:Both RPI wifi dongles can be seen with the 2 RSSI lines. And it gets the strongest signals by far. The S4 seems to fetch most wifi´s with very low RSSI The script i used to generate the data from above and the plot: https://gist.github.com/designer2k2/417 ... 9b0895e039 -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11124#p11124</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11124#p11124</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T19:12:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: Did you use any USB wifi dongle with an external antenna on the Raspberry or only the internal one? I think you could find even more in monitor mode, not sure whether the linked OS image contains it: https://github.com/seemoo-lab/nexmon The RPI is this: https://www.designer2k2.at/de/mods/elek ... ving-setup Found only by RPI: 2662 -kurz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11123#p11123</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11123#p11123</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T16:08:18</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: This insight is super-valuable! Side-by-side comparisons are really expensive/hard to do (same time, same route, more than 2-3 devices), but it would be great to get a ranking of the &quot;best&quot; net detecting phones. (maybe at a conference or public event where we can get people to travel the same route together?) We're careful not to embed any analytics/tracking stuff in the app so it would require community organization! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11122#p11122</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11122#p11122</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T15:12:30</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: with a s20 now i am surprised by how much it finds, so i made a run with &quot;all the gear&quot; to compare it: about 1 hour driving, all devices behind the windscreen: S4 W: 5783 B: 711 C: 24 S7 W: 4897 B: 1890 C: 104 S20 W: 7420 B: 2684 C: 78 RPI W: 8809 B: 1352 C: 0 Samsung phones run Wigle 2.63 The RPI is this: https://www.designer2k2.at/de/mods/elek ... ving-setup So yes, the S20 is quite a beast for wifi and even more on bluetooth. Celltowers it’s a bit lower than the S7. Looking a bit deeper, how do the individual datasets match? Found by all: 2995 (this wifi´s where in all 4 devices) Found only by S4: 981 Found only by S7: 616 Found only by S20: 2195 Found only by RPI: 2662 The S20 is fetching quite a lot. So far the &quot;best&quot; wigle phone I’ve seen. -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11121#p11121</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11121#p11121</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T09:51:35</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: mostly - we also do cluster detection - points should &quot;snap&quot; not drift in a perfect world. When you se things in weird places, it generally means: 1. they were reported there, improbable though it may be 2. they're PRECISELY POISED between two clusters, or have a very small number of observations. 3. they haven't been seen in a while and were last trilaterated before cluster detection was implemented. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11120#p11120</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11120#p11120</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T01:00:37</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: Another major factor that causes odd locations to appear on the map is also due to trilateration, but it isn't GPS accuracy that is to blame. I have several small clusters of points in countries that I have never been to! Usually in major cities. The explanation is simple. I discover a mobile hot-spot. It is recorded at my location. The tourist carrying the mobile then returns home and someone else logs the hot-spot. The point is now modified to be halfway(*) between the first and second sightings and could well be in a river or mid-ocean. Over time, as more data comes in, the point will shift closer to where the hot-spot actually spends most of its time. There will be an increasing amount of this as there is a huge growth of mobile hotspots, especially on public transport, cars and mobile phones. (*) Probably not exactly halfway as I believe trilateration also uses things like signal strength for improved accuracy. -TROMOS</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11119#p11119</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11119#p11119</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-08T00:32:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: these issues happen because of several reasons: 1. the long lines sound like GPS issues - these are (unfortunately) common in older devices. 2. points are trilaterated - the centers of the signal are estimated according to an algorithm. Bad GPS coordinates can contribute to points being located in odd spots, as can other users observing them in conflicting places. The short version of how to fix it: 1. observe the points from multiple places and at multiple times, and they'll snap to the right locations 2. if you discover a particular device has GPS problems, you might consider replacing it. this can be diagnosed by turning on &quot;display routes&quot; in the WiGLE WiFi Android app, or mapping your results before uploading with other packages! Cheers -a -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11100#p11100</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11100#p11100</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-11-14T21:28:36</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>GPS accuracy: Hello, when I watch the map with only my data, I can see that there are little dots in place I never went. Also some strings of points in linear alignment in odd places. Also I have data points in the middle of a ponds. Do you know if there is something that can be made to fix that and filter odd data ? -FredR</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11099#p11099</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2904&amp;p=11099#p11099</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-11-14T15:10:44</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: I think putting a small reflector behind each antenna would look the least ugly. It's also what the Ez-10 guide shows on the website. You might get away with taping foil to the wall if the router is next to it. Made a v3 for another adapter, an old 802.11b/g ALFA AWUS036H. I had a feeling old faithful would get good results. Single antenna design so no need to mount inside reflector. I eyeballed where everything should've been. You can probably ignore the min signal reading it's always bad when the adapter starts up. ~20dBm difference in software but this chipset is old so take these readings with a grain of salt. Alfa w/ only 9dBi antenna, AP nearby in unknown location: Latest Signal -58 dbm Min. Signal -71 dbm Max. Signal -48 dbm Alfa w/ 9 dBi antenna + reflector steered vaguely in the right direction: Latest Signal -38 dbm Min. Signal -74 dbm Max. Signal -30 dbm Alfa w/ 9dBi antenna + reflector perfectly steered. AP a few meters away, same room. No before photo but signal was between -10 and -20 dBmReflector: USPS 1095 almost entirely clad in foil with only a tiny gap near the top for slots/flaps AWUS036H: TX Power: Antenna: Ridiculously tall 2.4 GHz tuned dipole, probably rated 7-9 dBi. I don't remember where I got this. Stats: Kismet Research topics: -Apparently grounding the reflector can improve gain. For something this MacGyvered maybe you'd alligator clip the RP-SMA connector to a part of the reflector. If you're using a USB adapter that probably leads to ground. -How important is the thickness of the material? Would foiling the other side help? I noticed when you use this setup with the adapter in AP mode it's still possible to get a weak signal directly behind the reflector. I'm sure some of it is due to signal bounce but I'm not entirely convinced. I think some of the signal is wasted going through the single layer of foil. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11086#p11086</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11086#p11086</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-25T00:20:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: My WiFi router sits to one side of my house, on an outside wall, leaking signal into the neighbors lot. Curious how putting one of these behind the router, or each of the four antenna, would boost my signal in the farther areas of the house. Next Amazon box I receive might just have to launch a few experiments... -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11085#p11085</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11085#p11085</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-23T22:13:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: I did some internet digging. I managed to find a real commercial product that uses the same trifold reflector idea along with dimensions and photos from a guy called SkootS It is called the Hawking Tech &quot;HAI15SC 2.4GHz Hi-Gain Wireless Corner Antenna.&quot; The claimed rating is 15 dBi. The product has a 5 dBi dipole encased in plastic and a trifold corner reflector made of aluminum. They probably assumed the reflector was 10 dBi and did funky math. Seems like retail price was around $30. Well now you know, if you don't mind a flimsy product you can just build it yourself. https://web.archive.org/web/20211023100 ... fi-ant.php (Scroll down to L. Hawking Tech., 15 dBi. They are using a free web host, I don't want to kill their website) https://www.hawkingtech.com/product/hai ... -specs_tab I've attached some of the photos because I think this is hilarious. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11084#p11084</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11084#p11084</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-23T12:38:02</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: BLE scanning rig: There's a lot to learn about when this sort of thing is seen. It might be helpful to setup an environment (maybe out in the countryside) where you know exactly how many devices are in range ... but then what's the range? Your phone may simply have a greater range/better sensitivity. Good Luck - the testing environment will need to be socially distanced ... LOL. -ecramp</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11082#p11082</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11082#p11082</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-10-19T18:11:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>BLE scanning rig: I'm trying to use a Cyprus Bluetooth board in my setup and although it seems to work, it only reports about half the number of Bluetooth devices compared to the Wigle app. I was wondering if this is due to the window and interval sizes in my code - being a newbie I don't have much idea what these should be set to. The default in the example code I'm using is '96' for the scan interval and '48' for the scan window (which I think is times 0.625ms, so 60ms and 30ms respectively). Does anyone know if these are a good starting point? (I'm not concerned about battery life at this point). Many thanks. -sd4664</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2895&amp;p=11063#p11063</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-20T17:40:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: This is not my original idea, it's my practical implementation of the Ez-10 corner reflector. It makes omnis directional like a dish would but it's less picky about conditions. You can make this thing in 15 minutes, it costs nothing and it folds for storage. I got a ~10 dBm difference in software to a faraway 2.4 GHz access point. That represents about a tenfold difference in received signal power. Materials: -Your favorite USB wifi adapter + USB extension cable Recommended: $16 Terow ROW02CD AC1200M (MediaTek MT7612U) with CD driver. No CD version causes annoyances in Windows. https://smile.amazon.com/dp/B086L6TR6G/ The Terow is similar to the Alfa AWUS036ACM but 3x cheaper, lacks any accessories and has poorer construction. I own both and they're functionally almost the same. MT76 adapters are infamous for being more hassle free. Linux: Drivers already there. Supports pentesting features on both bands. Do not try to go directly from monitor to AP mode, needs to be in managed first. This is the only quirk I can think of. Windows: Use NetGear A6210 drivers. Few extra settings compared to the ones on MediaTek's website. -Boxcutter -Rectangular box, as big as you can feasibly make and use Recommended: Used USPS 1095 priority box Approx: 15&quot; (L) x 12&quot; (W) x 3-1/8&quot;(H) -Shipping Tape -Aluminum Foil Warning: Exceeding EIRP limits is generally illegal. Warning 2: Highly directional equipment may skew Wigle data. Use good judgement. Instructions: 1. Make two cuts into your box to chop off one of the short sides. Your box should now open like a trifold. Save this flap. 2. You will make slots and thread the cardboard flap through for structural support. Cut slots near the top of the box on the two side walls. 3. As neatly as you can, grab your reel of aluminum foil. Tape aluminum foil on the two inside side walls of the box. 4. Take off your antennas if they are removable. Make a hole and jam your adapter through, either just the USB bits (easier to get a tight fit) or the whole thing if you need to adjust antenna/reflector distance. 5. Hook the adapter to the USB extension cable. 5. Thread flap through top slots. 6. Hook antennas back up. 7. If you have a two antenna adapter, deploy them completely parallel or in a V shape, see which one works better. You can hang the adapter from flaps, use string, zip ties for tight fit if you think it's necessary. Use MacGyver skills. Optional (?): Cover the middle panel with aluminum foil, either on the inside or the outside of the box. Try to leave no gaps but it shouldn't matter that much. Adjustments: -Connect to the AP and run &quot;watch -n0 iwconfig&quot; in Linux or equivalent stat panel. Steer your antenna towards the AP. Stop steering when bit rate, link quality and signal level look good. Note: Also try &quot;watch -n0 iw dev wlanX station dump&quot; it has a lot of useful info! -Indoors = Signals will bounce and make consistent testing difficult. If you do not have direct line of sight sometimes pointing slightly away from the AP works better. -Beamforming may affect results -Making the side walls bigger will improve gain with diminishing returns -My (v1) reflector is probably incomplete since I don't have any foil in the middle. I don't know if putting it that close to the adapter causes interference, will test later. References: http://www.freeantennas.com/projects/Ez-10/ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corner_reflector_antenna Edit: Added picture of a v2 I made. I did not chop off the flaps so the box is taller and I added foil to the middle section. I've slightly updated the instructions to make them simpler. &quot;The spacing of the rods D should not be more than 0.06 (6%) of the wavelength.&quot; -Wikipedia I'm not sure if that instruction is properly cited but it would suggest you want continuous foil if possible with no gaps. The wavelength of 2.4 GHz is about 12 cm and 5 GHz is about 6 cm. 6% of those lengths is extraordinarily tiny. v2 achieved best performance with the antennas deployed parallel, while v1 seemed to like the V pattern. In terms of performance both reflectors work, I didn't compare them very hard. Someone more knowledgeable should chime in. Edit 2: Tips from an antenna design book I couldn't completely verify: -The angle of the reflector should vaguely be 90 degrees. A more narrow corner supposedly improves gain and directivity but may require larger side walls. I experimented but couldn't come up with a good conclusion. Since this contraption is kind of flimsy I found the 90 degree angle to cause least problems. -The antenna(s)' distance from the reflector's center should be between 25% and 75% of the intended wavelength, with a suggested value of 50%. So in theory: 2.4 GHz: antennas ~6.2455 cm from center 5 GHz: antennas ~2.998 cm from center This does seem to matter somewhat and could explain why I found differences from arranging the antennas full parallel vs V pattern. But even if your antennas are really far away you still get some gain. I recommend sliding your USB adapter around to see what works. Try your luck getting good clearance with your MacGyver skills. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11034#p11034</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-09-14T03:50:10</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I recommend the Samsung S5. I use one as my personal phone. Stock Android supports VOLTE, custom roms don't. You might not be able to make calls with it past 2022. It's had continuous LineageOS support for about half a decade. Street value $50-$100, cheap OEM batteries, has all the radios. The only model you should get in North America is the SM-G900T. All of them have unlocked bootloaders and it generally has the most useful 4G bands. &quot;A&quot; model is locked and &quot;V&quot; model is 50/50 depending on whether the phone came with exploitable hardware. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2881&amp;p=10992#p10992</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-08-28T02:16:13</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>