<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: I registered my account last year and verified my email. But I cannot use the service. I tried to use the database just for a couple of minutes but was limited. Now I see Daily Limit. I have never used any bots or other automation but was limited. -xamax</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12054#p12054</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12054#p12054</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-08T15:24:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: It was more than one account, though. You're welcome to contact us via the support email address at the bottom of the page to explain the situation. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12053#p12053</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12053#p12053</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-07T17:20:19</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Yesterday, I attempted to set up an account and successfully received and clicked on the verification link. However, when I tried to log in today, I encountered issues and didn't receive an email to reset my password. Consequently, I had to register for a new account, but I'm yet again not receiving the verification email. I'm using my Gmail for this, and my internet connection is through a 4G modem with a shared IP address. Could this connectivity setup be causing the problem? -jamers5</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12052#p12052</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12052#p12052</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-07T15:00:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: for a start, don't register multiple accounts - that will get you flagged permanently. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12043#p12043</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12043#p12043</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-04T00:13:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: That makes a lot of sense. Unfortunately I am trying to learn how to use the platform and couldn't even understand how to try one query before being told my daily limit expired. Is there a way I could practice without costing anyone? I really want to understand this, but I also see how reasonable it would be that queries would be limited. -Sainere</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12042#p12042</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12042#p12042</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-03T19:05:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: I launch API test from sample of that &quot;curl -i -H 'Accept:application/json' -u AID237*****************4e7a31d:4f6a0d5******************1a0c2c --basic https://api.wigle.net/api/v2/profile/user&quot;, and see at answer that my email is not verified. How to verify it now? {&quot;userid&quot;:&quot;wauzzz&quot;,&quot;email&quot;:&quot;***********ff@gmail.com&quot;,&quot;donate&quot;:&quot;Y&quot;,&quot;joindate&quot;:&quot;2023-04-07T01:45:37.000Z&quot;, &quot;lastlogin&quot;:&quot;2024-01-14T10:32:02.000Z&quot;,&quot;flags&quot;:0,&quot;emailVerified&quot;:false,&quot;session&quot;:null,&quot;success&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&quot; -wauzzz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12014#p12014</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12014#p12014</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-14T10:43:42</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: no-one will lose their account - not to worry. This is just an added test for new accounts. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12013#p12013</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12013#p12013</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-14T05:02:39</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: can old accounts proactively verify? I dont want to lose my account or all the work. Thank you, -wiggler81</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12009#p12009</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12009#p12009</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-12T23:07:43</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: id love to register, i think this is a cool spot and id like to support it. But i didnt see a field for email when i made the account. -backendcli</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11998#p11998</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11998#p11998</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-07T04:10:45</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: We're not currently requiring older accounts to verify. If the abuse attempts continue, we may revisit that decision, but if we do, we'll provide a clear path for verification. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11995#p11995</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11995#p11995</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-02T16:08:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Who tf uses throwaway email accounts? This isn't r/confessions or the dating app you're hiding from your significant other. By the way, I don't see it mentioned, is this something that ONLY affects new account registration, or are you sending verification emails to existing accounts as well? -vsa77</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11994#p11994</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11994#p11994</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-02T08:53:30</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Hello, Using valid, non-throwaway email and not receiving verification email. Password reset emails comes, so I’m sure I used the right address. -harrisonmattr</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11989#p11989</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11989#p11989</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-31T14:00:10</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: they require a valid email address -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11988#p11988</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11988#p11988</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-29T23:20:21</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Verification emails are not being sent? -Rene2305</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11987#p11987</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11987#p11987</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-29T19:28:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: as an aside (not a direct response): registering multiple accounts is never the answer. it looks like abuse to our automation. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11984#p11984</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11984#p11984</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-29T00:42:08</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>