<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: I also had a failed upload when the Q was very full, first time ever since the age of dinosaurs when I first joined Wigle.net. 20240722-00736 It was successful after resubmitting it later. It was just a single device small run which surprised me when I saw the failure. S24 Ultra with Wigle WiFi 2.86. Upload showed successful on the phone, but showed failed status on wigle.net later. -mark571</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12260#p12260</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12260#p12260</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-24T11:22:49</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: things are queueing just fine - otherwise the queue wouldn't be full! we've processed an absolutely unprecedented number of files in the last week. regarding a failed upload, does it happen when you retry? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12259#p12259</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12259#p12259</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-23T17:13:51</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: Server(s) seems to be swamped - nothing actually seems to queue, so there's almost 3000 trilaterating right now. Upload failed last night and at this rate it looks like it might be a few days before things are back to normal. -mrmalkovich</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12258#p12258</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12258#p12258</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-23T02:31:36</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: ahhh so that's why the queue times are insane. -Xenokilla</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12256#p12256</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12256#p12256</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-22T02:31:55</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: oh no! how could we have provided better notice? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12255#p12255</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12255#p12255</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-21T16:16:46</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: So so bummed that I essentially missed this! Was really looking forward to it too! Well it will be interesting to see what happens regardless. -TZz222zZT</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12254#p12254</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12254#p12254</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-21T16:10:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: that'a US/Pacific &quot;DEF CON&quot; time. uploads go from noon today to the last second of Sunday night in that timezone. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12252#p12252</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12252#p12252</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-19T13:56:19</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: can you explain the upload times? Contest uploads must be received between 2024-07-19T12:00:00.000-07:00 and 2024-07-22T00:00:00.000-07:00 to be included in scoring. What time zone is that? And there are 2 timeslots each between midnight and 0700 morning on the 19 and on the 22? -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12251#p12251</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12251#p12251</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-19T10:59:09</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: 24 hours to go! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12249#p12249</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12249#p12249</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-18T18:28:21</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>DEF CON 32 RFHS World Wide War Drive: OK folks, it's GO time. Registration for the @defcon 32 RF Hacker Sanctuary is now OPEN. if you're already a WiGLE user: https://wigle.net/contest/DC32 or to get started: https://wigle.net/wwwdintro/DC32 Be safe, have fun, and happy stumbling! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12245#p12245</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12245#p12245</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-07-10T16:23:57</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>6M Files Parsed!: Somehow over our 22+ years WiGLE has parsed 6M uploads! We literally couldn't have done it without this amazing community - thank you all for being a part of this wild ride. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12201#p12201</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12201#p12201</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-04-29T22:00:39</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Billion Mapped WiFi Networks: Congrats! -ampando</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12137#p12137</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12137#p12137</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-15T14:16:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: arkasha wrote: &amp;gt; Hey, apparently folks need to hear this again: every WiGLE user has a daily &amp;gt; query limit associated with their account. &amp;gt; This keeps the service available for everyone without costing &amp;gt; $ALL_THE_MONEY. If you deploy code that REALLY doesn't respect your daily &amp;gt; limit, we'll disable your account. If you try and register multiple of &amp;gt; accounts to circumvent the limit, bad things will also happen. &amp;gt; Also, if you're trying to use WiGLE data for commercial purposes, maybe &amp;gt; contact us and help support the project. &amp;gt; &amp;gt; hugs, the WiGLE team Hello, how can I contact you to support the project and remove the limits? -scottbrand</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12089#p12089</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12089#p12089</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-28T11:49:35</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: Hey everyone. About the daily use, completely understand and agree. But as an example I created my account few days ago. Like many other, got the limit before researching anything as I tried to familiarize myself with the site. But today I was laser focused, I opened the site, clicked in basic search and put an address, the map showed the address with the daily limit exceeded message. Not criticizing, really, just trying to understand if this is intended or maybe i`m still doing something wrong, just found it weird that i haven`t actually been able to do a single research. Oh and I haven`t created multiple accounts or anything. Anyways keep up the good work, i`m working on setting up an old phone to start collaborating aswell. -fernandocarvalho</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12088#p12088</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12088#p12088</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-26T17:44:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: Wouldn't it make sense, for example, to add a button on the phone to the map to generate wifi points on the map and indicate somewhere the number of available commands before the limit expires? It would make things a lot easier, thanks for a reply. -lukaskicz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12062#p12062</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12062#p12062</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-02-09T08:00:22</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>