<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Increasing accuracy after scan: in the centralized database, we apply the trilateration techniques described elsewhere in this forum to the network record you see in the search interface/maps/APIs. We don't modify the individual observations. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11811#p11811</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11811#p11811</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:08:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Huawei P20 Android 10: The throttling option may still be available via ADB command too - but considering the divergence of Hauwei/Redmi from core Android, that may not remain true. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11810#p11810</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11810#p11810</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:06:57</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: Thank you - worth noting that no &quot;legacy ties&quot; now survive cluster trilateration - we redid everything. Anything weird you see was either reported there or perfectly-balanced. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11809#p11809</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11809#p11809</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:05:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: mostly - we also do cluster detection - points should &quot;snap&quot; not drift in a perfect world. When you se things in weird places, it generally means: 1. they were reported there, improbable though it may be 2. they're PRECISELY POISED between two clusters, or have a very small number of observations. 3. they haven't been seen in a while and were last trilaterated before cluster detection was implemented.Perfect explanation -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11806#p11806</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11806#p11806</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:17:29</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Increasing accuracy after scan: Does accuracy get improved by other users observations? -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11805#p11805</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11805#p11805</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:13:38</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Hak5 WiFi Coconut: The coconut appears to have an IPEX (IPX) connector where all the radios come together into a top patch antenna near the fan, so in theory, one could remove that and add an IPX to female SMA bulkhead with an external antenna and be off to the races. It's unknown if there are additional amplifiers in-line with each radio, as a 1:14 splitter will reduce the signal strength by around 12dB in losses with one input antenna. There are also 14 smaller Rf test ports/switches for each radio, however these RF connectors do not appear to be IPX and maybe Murata. Be carefully pulling up the one main antenna off the board, as I accidentally ripped the IPX female connector off the board while attempting to gently pull up the IPX male connector out of the female soldered socket with equal pressure from both sides. An old salty dog friend said it might have been a cold solder joint, as the connector should have popped off the connector before ripping the solder joint, so be careful if you go this method. Some flux and hot air might be able to re-attach it. Now if only dragorn or mkershaw come out with a Win x64 Coconut binary that support a generic GPS/NMEA GPS input, then anyone could Wardrive in style with Windows and 14 radios. I bet it would be the fastest setup for a multi-radio war-driving rig ever.... Hopefully by now we should have some performance reports... anyone? -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11804#p11804</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11804#p11804</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:06:58</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: ESP32 or ESP8266 Wigle and Lora - Tracker: OP I've had some ideas for building a bike tracker using GPS and LTE. Let us know what you find please, very keen on this topic -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11803#p11803</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11803#p11803</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:00:51</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Huawei P20 Android 10: If you still can't find the Developer Options or the specific Wi-Fi scan throttling setting, it's possible that your device's manufacturer or ROM might not have included this option in their customized software. In such cases, you might need to check for custom ROMs or firmware that support this feature, but keep in mind that modifying system settings can have risks, and it might void your warranty. Bitlife -victorpatrick</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11799#p11799</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11799#p11799</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T04:56:01</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: You shouldn't need to re-run every time, but installing updates MAY require it. Keep us posted about your results? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11765#p11765</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11765#p11765</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-10T15:50:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: Well, if you're sophisticated enough to install a new OS: first: try the adb trick to remove the throttle on 9; it doesn't work on every model/os. if it works, no need to resort to anything extreme. ( Code: adb shell settings put global wifi_scan_throttle_enabled 0) second: https://lineageos.org/ is pretty niceThanks a! It seems to have worked really well, I'm getting 1 scan every 1-30ms at worst! Considering the human eye takes around 13-400x that to blink, I'd call that a win! It'll absolutely slaughter my battery life, I presume, but I imagine I'll pick up a lot more now! In case you need it for any statistics on who it works/doesn't work for, I'm using a Samsung Galaxy S8 SM-G950U running Android 9 (Also, do I need to rerun that command every time I restart? Will security patch updates affect it?) -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11764#p11764</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11764#p11764</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-10T09:25:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: It is still possible to use Samsung Galaxy S4 for wifi scanning?: yes the S4 is ok, i use it with LOS18.1 (Android 11) https://wiki.lineageos.org/devices/jfltexx/ Here is a comparison against the S7 and S20: viewtopic.php?t=2498#p11121 -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11761#p11761</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11761#p11761</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-08T16:36:52</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Custom ROMs for wardriving?: Well, if you're sophisticated enough to install a new OS: first: try the adb trick to remove the throttle on 9; it doesn't work on every model/os. if it works, no need to resort to anything extreme. ( Code: adb shell settings put global wifi_scan_throttle_enabled 0) second: https://lineageos.org/ is pretty nice -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11753#p11753</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11753#p11753</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:06:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Maybe phone models, but not necessarily OS versions. Just remember to disable throttling on 10 and up. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11752#p11752</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11752#p11752</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:04:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: ESP32 or ESP8266 Wigle and Lora - Tracker: You can locate individual MAC addresses using the API (without using the whole packet), but we don't provide a networked geolocation service at this time, since we want to avoid knowing where anyone is at any given time. https://api.wigle.net for the API options, you're probably most interested in &quot;network search&quot; we do have an embedded location system for which we publish regular extracts, but it's probably no precise enough to locate stolen property, it's more for providing terrestrial assistance for embedded/non-networked devices in getting a GPS lock. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=78z5H0rv-wE -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11751#p11751</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11751#p11751</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T20:01:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: It's a pile of things: Old radios/drivers/OSes might just not tune as fast (and so don't scan as quickly) Driver versions can have a huge impact, making previously slow phones fast and vice versa on upgrade Android 9 throttles WiFi scan speed (and is hard to de-throttle) Android 10 and up also throttle scanning, but if you activate developer mode, you can turn that off. Cheers, -aThanks for that, Arkasha. Besides Android 9 and assuming that the throttle (if present) was disabled, is there any &quot;best&quot; Android version for wardriving? Or would the actual impact of the version itself be mostly minimal, and it is the internal drivers and age of the Wi-Fi module primarily affecting things? -Wigler-0283819</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11750#p11750</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11750#p11750</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-06-29T11:32:29</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>