<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Highway to the...: ... #WWWD2022 AS A REMINDER: the clock is ticking and as of now we are keeping score. It's still anyone's game, it's early. Join in at https://wigle.net/wwwdintro/DC30 -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11299#p11299</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11299#p11299</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-03T04:25:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: wireless signals are strange, and phones and driver software even stranger! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11295#p11295</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11295#p11295</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-31T16:22:11</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: I noticed that while scanning with the APK in the background, there have been some cases where networks are recorded way far away from their true source, most likely my weird configs but is accountable to the random outliers? I'm sure other travellers with better setups can eventually &quot;correct&quot; it in someway but I wouldn't think a random house has a gas pump. -CabinetVCase</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11294#p11294</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11294#p11294</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-31T06:33:55</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>World-Wide War Drive, RFHS and DEF CON 30: Greetings WiFriends! The fine folks at the RFHS have invited us to hold a World-Wide War Drive in conjunction with the DEF CON 30 RFHS, and we have answered the call. Registration is now open at the DC30 WWWD landing page Since DEF CON and the RFCTF will be in-person this year, we've elected to host the WWWD from August 1st through the 7th. Your score WILL have a bearing on your RFCTF score.... BUT WAIT, there's MORE! Since we'll be able to compete in-person at DEF CON, there will a SECOND PART to the WWWD in Las Vegas during DEF CON 30. Watch this space, Twitter, and the RFHS contest page for further details. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11293#p11293</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11293#p11293</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-29T21:51:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel update RQ3A.210905.001 breaks GPS: This is a great note - we've gotten a lot of questions from Xiaomi users, but don't have any test devices to figure this out on. Thanks! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11292#p11292</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11292#p11292</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-25T16:27:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pixel update RQ3A.210905.001 breaks GPS: When I started with WiGLE, I had a similar problem with my Xiaomi Redmi Note 8 Pro. Same problem also with the Note 11 Pro. WiGLE stopped working when it was not in the foreground, i.e. on screen. Problem is that Xiaomi has implemented some powersaving measures, one of them being giving background processes none, or little, processing time. I solved that by browing the settings: Privacy_protection-&amp;gt;Special_permissions-&amp;gt;Battery_optimization-&amp;gt;WiGLE_WiFi_Wardriving, and select &quot;Don't optimize&quot; there. This allows the app to stay active in the background. Also check this: long press the 'Wigle WiFi' icon, select 'App info' there, Select 'Batteru saver', and select 'No restrictions' there. Now my WiGLE always runs as it should do. This will probably be so on most Xiaomi phones, and even most phones running the MIUI user interface. -josn</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11291#p11291</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11291#p11291</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-25T15:47:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: That's good to hear, for years now I've noticed locations appearing in areas that seemed unlikely (deep in swamps), trilateration is not an easy calculation so it was not too surprising given all the variables in everyone's &quot;measurements&quot;. This will be very nice to see, thank you! -ecramp</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11276#p11276</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11276#p11276</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-09T12:24:01</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Massive re-trilateration effort in progress: Big changes in network positions are sweeping the globe! For weeks now, we've been cleaning up data that our previous trilateration algorithm had incorrectly judged as a &quot;tie.&quot; The southern hemisphere is complete, and we're working through some of the most densely-observed areas in the northern hemisphere, which will take a while. This will manifest as sharp &quot;bars&quot; working across Europe/Northern Africa and the halves of North/Central America. We're proud of the data improvements we're making in the face of a great increase in mobile access points since we devised our original algorithm, and will continue to improve our system! -a -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11272#p11272</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11272#p11272</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-03T19:39:30</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet Wardriving Mode: arkasha wrote: &amp;gt; holy wardriving, batman: &amp;gt; [url]https://www.kismetwireless.net/docs/readme/wardriving/[/url] &amp;gt; &amp;gt; The incomparable dragorn has released a special wardriving overlay config &amp;gt; for wardriving! YAY!! How did I miss this. I can't wait to get this configured. *happy dance* -kmfdmk</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11247#p11247</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11247#p11247</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-05-25T23:33:49</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Beware Facebook Scammers: gonna get rid of that. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11200#p11200</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11200#p11200</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-03-19T18:52:34</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Beware Facebook Scammers: bonheurrosa4 wrote: &amp;gt; Bob, all of Facebook is a scam now with meta it's nothing but authcookies &amp;gt; best I only use it for you maybe. The PGP part is down recall Virginia &amp;gt; Wolff letters to a young patriot yet we hear Putin call out NAZI. It's all &amp;gt; about Us now. You are all I got in this world. Two strangers in the bright &amp;gt; lights. What? -anothersomething</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11198#p11198</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11198#p11198</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-03-18T17:08:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Beware Facebook Scammers: Note that this is our official Facebook page (@wiglenet), anything else is a scam: https://www.facebook.com/wiglenet/ -bobzilla</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11193#p11193</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11193#p11193</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-03-09T13:23:09</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet Wardriving Mode: Awesome news, at last an easy way to strip it down for the underpowered SBCs. -strasharo</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11166#p11166</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11166#p11166</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-08T17:03:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Kismet Wardriving Mode: holy wardriving, batman: https://www.kismetwireless.net/docs/readme/wardriving/ The incomparable dragorn has released a special wardriving overlay config for wardriving! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11155#p11155</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11155#p11155</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-20T23:36:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Reminder: Query Limits and responsible use: Hey, apparently folks need to hear this again: every WiGLE user has a daily query limit associated with their account. This keeps the service available for everyone without costing $ALL_THE_MONEY. If you deploy code that REALLY doesn't respect your daily limit, we'll disable your account. If you try and register multiple of accounts to circumvent the limit, bad things will also happen. Also, if you're trying to use WiGLE data for commercial purposes, maybe contact us and help support the project. hugs, the WiGLE team -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11118#p11118</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11118#p11118</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-07T20:26:07</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>