<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Rasberry Pi: Kali is now running a kismet version high enough to have the wardriving mode, so i updated everything and gave it a go. Yes thats a big improvement and simple to use change is online here: https://github.com/designer2k2/warpi With this i think its worth to test it on a Zero again. Memory consumption was 450mb for kismet with 13k devices in the logfile. -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11183#p11183</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11183#p11183</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-20T12:10:52</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Rasberry Pi: Woot, completely missed the overlay news, will check it out on the RPI Zero and report back, it was a real struggle to strip it down until now. -strasharo</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11167#p11167</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11167#p11167</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-08T17:04:50</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Rasberry Pi: Hello, yes, as the rpi3 died on me its now running with a rpi4: https://github.com/designer2k2/warpi I will soon check out the latest Kismet wardriving overlay, that should simplify it even further viewtopic.php?p=11155 -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11165#p11165</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11165#p11165</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-08T16:40:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Rasberry Pi: im running a headless rpi-setup: Raspberry Pi 3b with Kali 64 Bit OSRTC hatGPS module on UARTOLED screensome WLAN sticksrpi3b setup: and before that, my try with a rpi0w: full guide on how its made: https://www.designer2k2.at/de/mods/elek ... ving-setupHave you updated this setup? Wondering what you are using now. -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11164#p11164</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=1916&amp;p=11164#p11164</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-05T15:45:53</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Redneck Warflying: How effective is this? Awesome!! -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11163#p11163</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11163#p11163</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-05T15:41:23</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: DIY Box Reflector - sick gainz!: Reflector works alright for 5 GHz connections too. Not a huge difference in usability for this test since the test AP is easily reachable without it (~15m distance.) I used two mostly similar adapters so I wouldn't need to re-point the reflector afterwards. Terow AC1200M (no reflector) BSS -- associated freq: 5805 signal: -64 [-66, -64] dBm signal avg: -63 [-66, -63] dBm beacon signal avg: -62 dBm tx bitrate: 390.0 MBit/s VHT-MCS 4 80MHz short GI VHT-NSS 2 rx bitrate: 390.0 MBit/s VHT-MCS 4 80MHz short GI VHT-NSS 2 expected throughput: 61.980Mbps Hosted by...: 25.241 ms Download: 125.43 Mbit/s Upload: 96.17 Mbit/s PING 1.1.1.1 (1.1.1.1) 56(84) bytes of data. 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=1 ttl=59 time=8.29 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=2 ttl=59 time=9.76 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=3 ttl=59 time=14.5 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=4 ttl=59 time=6.95 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=5 ttl=59 time=5.00 ms Alfa AWUS036ACM (reflector) BSS -- associated freq: 5805 signal: -57 [-61, -57] dBm signal avg: -56 [-59, -56] dBm beacon signal avg: -55 dBm tx bitrate: 780.0 MBit/s VHT-MCS 8 80MHz short GI VHT-NSS 2 rx bitrate: 585.0 MBit/s VHT-MCS 7 80MHz VHT-NSS 2 expected throughput: 68.389Mbps Hosted by...: 26.488 ms Download: 143.72 Mbit/s Upload: 131.18 Mbit/s PING 1.1.1.1 (1.1.1.1) 56(84) bytes of data. 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=1 ttl=59 time=7.26 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=2 ttl=59 time=8.50 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=3 ttl=59 time=10.3 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=4 ttl=59 time=9.73 ms 64 bytes from 1.1.1.1: icmp_seq=5 ttl=59 time=9.06 ms -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11162#p11162</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2893&amp;p=11162#p11162</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-04T22:57:44</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Redneck Warflying: That's a much more climate friendly option than driving around everywhere! -ecramp</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11159#p11159</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11159#p11159</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-28T20:27:24</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Redneck Warflying: Red Bull, it gives you wings! Or quad-props, ya know, whichever.... -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11150#p11150</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11150#p11150</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-11T01:44:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Redneck Warflying: thats cool -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11149#p11149</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11149#p11149</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-10T19:40:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Redneck Warflying: LOVE IT! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11145#p11145</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11145#p11145</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-06T23:55:40</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Redneck Warflying: I know Warflying isn't anything new but this redneck implementation just worked out great. My old LG V30+ has always had pretty poor battery life but that made it an advantage in this case here. Weighing in at just 156 grams the Mavic Air 2 handled it great. The way it's mounted left the downward sensors functional and it can also get a unique camera perspective of the flight. -Johnnokomis</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11144#p11144</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2912&amp;p=11144#p11144</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-01-06T23:54:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: The sleep when hopping between channels might not correlate well with the gain of the antenna, the noise within the LNA chain, the sensitivity of the radio, the selectivity of the tuner and its noise rejection characteristics. There is no substitute for predicting how well a given device will perform when scanning given a certain path &amp;amp; mobility choice - just count how many each of them gather. Retrace the exact same path multiple times (at least 3-5) while shuffling the position of the devices within the vehicle and then correlate between them to see repeatability. What might be also interesting to track is how much juice each of those consumes while scanning both in absolute terms (W, to predict heating) and in relative terms (% of battery/hour). By the way, could we perhaps have a button for reporting abuse on every forum? That fits quite well the numbers I've observed on the devices. but it does not directly match as the S4 is a bit slower than the S7, but still gets more wifi... -kurz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11131#p11131</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11131#p11131</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-17T19:07:54</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: i was looking at the Wigle app, and this scan time is jumping a bit around, so i took the data from above and looked into that: As every scan result gets the same timestamp, i used now only the unique timestamps. That gives a timestamp for every finished scan. And now plotting this unique timestamps:Basically, the higher the count, the more complete scans it made. The RPI is a bit different, as it reports at the time when it finds something, therefore gets a lot more timestamps. The chart above can also be shown as numbers: total time: 5060s unique S4 timestamps: 973, average intervall: 5.20s unique S7 timestamps: 1319, average intervall: 3.84s unique S20 timestamps: 1500, average intervall: 3.37s unique RPI timestamps: 2313, average intervall: 2.19s That fits quite well the numbers ive observed on the devices. but it does not directly match as the S4 is a bit slower than the S7, but still gets more wifi... -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11129#p11129</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11129#p11129</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-17T17:38:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: Can you post your devices' scan speeds for comparison? My S5/SM-G900T can do a scan in about 3.9s with throttle off. It runs LineageOS 18.1. Internet says its chipset is a Broadcom BCM4354. I think I can explain some of OP's findings. Here are the wifi chipsets as far as I can research: S4 BCM4335 LG G3 BCM4339 S7 Edge BCM4359 Each mfg. probably uses a different antenna setup but maybe you can assume the newer chipsets are better. If you have root &quot;iw&quot; actually works on Android. You can use &quot;iw list&quot; to examine chipset capabilities. &quot;iw dev wlan0 get power_save&quot; and &quot;iw dev wlan0 set power_save off&quot; worked on my device but didn't affect scanning speed. It probably only affects station mode. The vendor's firmware files suggest my phone is meant to use country code &quot;GB&quot; ruleset. &quot;iw reg get&quot; shows &quot;00&quot; which usually means unset/most restrictive and I couldn't change it. -SkywardLark</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11128#p11128</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11128#p11128</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-15T02:22:35</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: the S20 runs stock Android 11 (One-Ui 3.1) Just developer mode active to turn off the wifi scan throttling. Only the S4 runs LineageOs to have a more current system on it -d2k2</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11127#p11127</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?t=2498&amp;p=11127#p11127</guid>
        <pubDate>2021-12-12T13:54:33</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>