<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Hak5 WiFi Coconut: The coconut appears to have an IPEX (IPX) connector where all the radios come together into a top patch antenna near the fan, so in theory, one could remove that and add an IPX to female SMA bulkhead with an external antenna and be off to the races. It's unknown if there are additional amplifiers in-line with each radio, as a 1:14 splitter will reduce the signal strength by around 12dB in losses with one input antenna. There are also 14 smaller test ports for each radio, however these RF connectors do not appear to be IPX and maybe Murata. Be carefully pulling up the one main antenna off the board, as I accidentally ripped the IPX female connector off the board while attempting to gently pull up the IPX male connector out of the female soldered socket with equal pressure from both sides. An old salty dog friend said it might have been a cold solder joint, as the connector should have popped off the connector before ripping the solder joint, so be careful if you go this method. Some flux and hot air might be able to re-attach it. Now if only dragorn or mkershaw come out with a Win x64 Coconut binary that support a generic GPS/NMEA GPS input, then anyone could Wardrive in style with Windows and 14 radios. I bet it would be the fast setup for a multi-radio war-driving rig ever.... -power64</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11316#p11316</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11316#p11316</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-20T00:31:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Hak5 WiFi Coconut: Looks like a nice compact device for a semi-portable car-setup, combined with a Raspberry Pi or notebook with GPS Only internal antenna(s), I wonder how it will perform in the car. https://shop.hak5.org/products/wifi-coconut Currently using a Kali Notebook with latest Kismet connected to an GPS antenna/USB-Hub/4 USB Alfa WiFi adapters. Adapters connected to 4 flat panel directional antennas positioned in the cat behind the rear side windscreens, stationcar 2 left 2 right 3 adapters set to fixed channels 1,6,11 nr 4 hopping 5 Ghz -larsnl</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11315#p11315</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11315#p11315</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-08-18T21:45:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Posting file via cURL: NVM that worked... must have been a network issue. -Binary_Buddha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11283#p11283</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11283#p11283</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-16T04:32:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Posting file via cURL: You need the @ symbol even with full path. Code: curl -i -H Accept:application/json -u &amp;lt;api name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;api token&amp;gt; --basic -F file=@/home/hal/.kismet/logs/active/Kismet-20220715-08-06-07-1.wiglecsv -F donate=true https://api.wigle.net/api/v2/file/uploadHTTP/1.1 400 Bad RequestServer: nginx/1.20.0Date: Fri, 15 Jul 2022 08:43:48 GMTContent-Type: application/jsonContent-Length: 45Connection: keep-alive{&quot;code&quot;:400,&quot;message&quot;:&quot;HTTP 400 Bad Request&quot;} -Binary_Buddha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11279#p11279</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11279#p11279</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-07-15T08:46:49</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Car antenna mount position suggestions?: Hi At one moment, I was putting the gps on the roof of my car; I was closing the door on the cable. There is rubber to make joint. So it is not too much compressed. But it is a little anyway. I coulnd't have done that too often without damaging the cable I guess. but this is a USB cable. May be your antenna cable is thinner and would sustain less damaged when taken in the door joint.May be try with a diffrent cable too see how it goes first... but not I never mounted a wifi antenna on the roof. as it is not a very discrete setup Hey! Thanks for the reply. Yeah, I had an idea that it could maybe be done like this. And yes, you're right, it isn't that discrete. I don't want to go around looking like an unmarked police car. haha. I guess I could have a look to see if I can mount them inside near the back window inside the car. Cheers! -T100</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11264#p11264</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11264#p11264</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-06-13T19:59:46</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Car antenna mount position suggestions?: Hi At one moment, I was putting the gps on the roof of my car; I was closing the door on the cable. There is rubber to make joint. So it is not too much compressed. But it is a little anyway. I coulnd't have done that too often without damaging the cable I guess. but this is a USB cable. May be your antenna cable is thinner and would sustain less damaged when taken in the door joint.May be try with a diffrent cable too see how it goes first... but not I never mounted a wifi antenna on the roof. as it is not a very discrete setup -zebul666</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11263#p11263</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11263#p11263</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-06-13T12:23:48</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Car antenna mount position suggestions?: Hey guys! So I have gotten the wardriving bug. I've had a lot of fun with it, and I've bought some 7db omni directional antennas which have a magnetic base. The question I had, was where have many of you mounted the antennas? Also, how did you deal with the cables, other than running them through the window? I would like to mount them and have the windows closed, but not have to drill holes in my car. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated! Cheers! -T100</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11262#p11262</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11262#p11262</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-06-13T08:32:54</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Raspberry PI: I'm using this pi (Zero 2 W) and i use GPS2IP on Iphone as GPS. I connect all in WiFi and i use AWUS036NHA card in USB.And how is the Zero 2 W handling that, Im just going to use the internal wifi for now but think a 5g dongle would be better. Almost as easy to use a phone but I have a spare 2W abotu so might as well us it for something fun. -wpa3</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11253#p11253</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11253#p11253</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-06-03T19:09:20</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: WiGLE WiFi for Android phone performance comparison: Excellent info! I've been gauging performance of a few android phones over the past few years. A Galaxy Express 3, Note 3, Note 5, two S7's, S7 Edge, and now adding a Note 20 Ultra to the fleet. What would you happen to be running for scan interval settings on the androids? -Ninemeister</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11250#p11250</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11250#p11250</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-05-28T23:45:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Raspberry PI: I'm using this pi (Zero 2 W) and i use GPS2IP on Iphone as GPS. I connect all in WiFi and i use AWUS036NHA card in USB. -asajdbajbda</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11245#p11245</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11245#p11245</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-05-19T12:19:01</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Raspberry PI: What setups are people using in 2022 lets see some images? I'm thinking of using a PI02 just because there small and are pretty powerful, I have seen https://github.com/designer2k2/warpi which seems a cool project anybody else made one? -wpa3</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11232#p11232</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11232#p11232</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-05-01T18:22:47</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have recently brought brand new xiaomi not 5 pro.GBWhatsApp I think it is the most suitable android phone for Wiglewifi with advanced connectivity and processor. -Mac4353</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11212#p11212</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11212#p11212</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-04-14T19:05:43</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Kismet drone on wireless router?: Update: I gave up on trying to get 20y old hardware running with 10y old software... However, I'm still looking for Kismet drone options with a price tag in the lower two digits, i.e. comparable to a Raspberry Pi plus wifi adapter. And while the Pi would definititely be an option, I'd naively assume that hardware specialized in radio communication might be more sensitive, e.g. a wireless router. Can anybody shed some light on whether this assumption is naive or actually true, possibly even with some hardware recommendation? Thanks. -qascnjzd</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11208#p11208</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11208#p11208</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-04-07T21:44:09</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Kismet drone on wireless router? (e.g. Linksys WRT54GL): I've just dusted off two Linksys WRT54GL, and noticed some older posts enthusiastic about their radio capabilities. However, for setting up Kismet on this hardware, I only found decade-old instructions and Kismet MIPS binaries from 2004... Has anybody recently set up a WRT54GL as a Kismet drone and could give me some pointers? Thanks. -qascnjzd</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11207#p11207</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11207#p11207</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-04-05T21:33:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Has anyone run WiGLE inside the windows 11 android subsystem?: I was afraid of that. Thanks for responding. -blackbirdactual</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11188#p11188</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11188#p11188</guid>
        <pubDate>2022-02-23T17:51:15</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>