<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE Frontpage (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Same here. -mvdswaluw</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11972#p11972</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11972#p11972</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-22T07:15:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: as disposable email providers get used in attempts to abuse the system, they'll cease to work for registration. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11967#p11967</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11967#p11967</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-16T21:59:58</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: lthompson38 wrote: &amp;gt; Verification email isn't being sent to mail so can't verify new account. &amp;gt; Email entered correctly as password reset sent to correct email but not &amp;gt; verification email. Same issue here -appaz8dm</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11966#p11966</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11966#p11966</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-16T21:36:32</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: Verification email isn't being sent to mail so can't verify new account. Email entered correctly as password reset sent to correct email but not verification email. -lthompson38</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11961#p11961</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11961#p11961</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-12T16:59:49</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Email verification changes: thanks for looking after Wigle for us :) -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11956#p11956</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11956#p11956</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-09T04:21:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Email verification changes: Due to extensive abuse, we've had make changes, including switching to an email-verification model on registration. This isn't our preferred solution, recent events have made it necessary. As always, if you have a specific use in mind, reach out to us, and please understand that the EULA applies to every user and exists entirely so that we can continue to make this project work. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11954#p11954</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11954#p11954</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-03T08:48:08</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Billion Mapped WiFi Networks: Congrats!! -Rouregre</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11790#p11790</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11790#p11790</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-26T03:00:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: RF Hacker Sanctuary DEF CON 31 World Wide Wardrive: details in the interview here: https://www.twitch.tv/videos/1858572275 -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11780#p11780</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11780#p11780</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-19T20:44:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: RF Hacker Sanctuary DEF CON 31 World Wide Wardrive: Can we get some sort of clarification or further explanation on how the scoring works? It says that it is based on &quot;coverage&quot;. Can we have more detail on what that means please. My inference is that the data submitted during the contest time frame will be compared with existing data that has already been submitted and our score will be based on how much of a percentage of our data matches to the existing data. Is this correct? -K0R41</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11779#p11779</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11779#p11779</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-19T17:56:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: RF Hacker Sanctuary DEF CON 31 World Wide Wardrive: If you actually mean &quot;price&quot; - no, it's free to join! perhaps you meant &quot;prize?&quot; -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11778#p11778</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11778#p11778</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-17T16:22:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: RF Hacker Sanctuary DEF CON 31 World Wide Wardrive: I know this might be a dumb question. but since this is a contest, would there be a price? -KevinKid4738</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11776#p11776</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11776#p11776</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-17T08:18:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>RF Hacker Sanctuary DEF CON 31 World Wide Wardrive: registration for the WWWD is open - see https://wigle.net/wwwdintro/DC31 if you're new and https://wigle.net/contest/DC31 if you're already a user. The contest begins at midnight, July 24th and end at noon July 30th (defcon standard time, even though we’re just DC-adjacent) -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11770#p11770</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11770#p11770</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-07-13T21:48:04</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Billion Mapped WiFi Networks: It grows \o/ GG user -CabinetVCase</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11713#p11713</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11713#p11713</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-05-27T13:11:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Billion Mapped WiFi Networks: Thats outstanding, awesome job to all involved. -wpa3</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11563#p11563</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11563#p11563</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-02-19T18:11:35</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Billion Mapped WiFi Networks: Congrats to the project and the whole famdamily that make all these #dotsOnMaps appear! -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11562#p11562</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11562#p11562</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-02-19T16:36:17</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>