<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: File Formats: KML vs CSV vs Magic8Ball vs SQLite: KML commonly used for visualizing spatial data such as maps, 3D models, and other geospatial information. CSV is a plain text file that separates values with commas and lines with newlines. CSV files can be easily opened and edited in a text editor or spreadsheet program. getting over it SQLite is commonly used in mobile apps, web browsers, and other applications that require a lightweight, file-based database system. -DeshaunBruen</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11936#p11936</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11936#p11936</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-26T10:35:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Need advice on building a full spectrum wifi wardriving rig: Does Vistumbler allow for this? Why can't I just plug in two USB Wifi adapters and let Vistumbler do the rest? -pretenda</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11909#p11909</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11909#p11909</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-08T00:47:32</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Hak5 WiFi Coconut: Yah I'm super curious on this also. How can I get Vistumbler to get more APs with Hak5 technology? Is it just as easy as plug it in and drive away? -pretenda</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11908#p11908</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11908#p11908</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-08T00:01:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: File Formats: KML vs CSV vs Magic8Ball vs SQLite: Kml is keyhole markup language it's kinda like xml it's the format that Googlemaps uses Csv comma separated values is kinda the standard for transferring data between different databases and spreadsheets. You can view this one alot of different ways as is in a text editor in most spreadsheet programs excel ,Google sheets ,libre office calc idk what apple uses but that to or it can be uploaded natively into many SQL databases Magic8ball idk I'll look it up ok wiggle made kinda location anomyzor so exact location and exact time are not displayed I'm not 100%on this Sqlite3 least I assume it's 3 is a on disk or embedded db so there is no server it's just a file like another but you can use SQL language to search it and do other things -Space-$hoot088</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11901#p11901</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11901#p11901</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-02T11:04:03</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: My RPi Setup: Looks like the wardriving mode docs for Kismet moved - https://www.kismetwireless.net/docs/rea ... /wardrive/ is the new locationNearly a year on, hows the rig and your goals coming along? -HolidayGuy</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11877#p11877</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11877#p11877</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-09-25T14:52:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet drone on wireless router? (e.g. Linksys WRT54GL): I built one 10+ years ago. Recently found that digital signage PCs are more suitable. I've rescued three Giada VM23 boxes from the e-waste. Add a cheap USB GPS and you are good as bluetooth and wifi is built in. Three additional USB ports for more wifi adapters. Runs of 12v with a barrel plug. Easy to make a cigarette power plug adapter. I see many go for about $20. Many was sold with only 1 year Windows 10 IOT, so quickly EOL. Kali runs well on it, even with three radios, two gps and graphical user interface. -Tech^CF</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11864#p11864</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11864#p11864</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-09-14T19:38:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet drone on wireless router? (e.g. Linksys WRT54GL): I've just dusted off two Linksys WRT54GL, and noticed some older posts enthusiastic about their radio capabilities. However, for setting up Kismet on this hardware, I only found decade-old instructions and Kismet MIPS binaries from 2004...mini crossword Has anybody recently set up a WRT54GL as a Kismet drone and could give me some pointers? Thanks.An outdated wireless router with only 4M/32M (ram/flash) might host a kismet drone instead of a Raspberry Pi + wifi card. If you can get Kismet running on your WRT54GL, you could theoretically try cross-compiling a drone for it. -originamidships</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11842#p11842</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11842#p11842</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-29T08:36:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>BU 353N not working on PI: Has anybody tried using the 353-S4 replacement 353N? It works fine in Windows but can not seem to get gpsd to take the input. -superfan321</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11841#p11841</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11841#p11841</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-26T20:55:10</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: I have an android phone, it's a five year old model and when it gets hot it shuts down the apps I'm using on its own, even it can't turn on location now, is there a way to fix this? I need navigation badly when I'm out and about. And I can't replace my phone at the moment. https://yowhatsapp.org Thanks in advance, and sorry for the intrusion. -yowhatsapp</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11824#p11824</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11824#p11824</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-11T02:25:52</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Just remember to disable throttling on 10 and up.This is how I found out my phones been throttling my scans. I knew it wasnt getting as many as I thought there were but at least I know now hundreds of miles down the roads rather than thousands. Thanks arkasha! -ziggyshenene</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11823#p11823</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11823#p11823</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-09T17:53:06</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Increasing accuracy after scan: in the centralized database, we apply the trilateration techniques described elsewhere in this forum to the network record you see in the search interface/maps/APIs. We don't modify the individual observations. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11811#p11811</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11811#p11811</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:08:07</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Huawei P20 Android 10: The throttling option may still be available via ADB command too - but considering the divergence of Hauwei/Redmi from core Android, that may not remain true. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11810#p11810</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11810#p11810</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:06:57</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: Thank you - worth noting that no &quot;legacy ties&quot; now survive cluster trilateration - we redid everything. Anything weird you see was either reported there or perfectly-balanced. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11809#p11809</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11809#p11809</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T16:05:27</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: GPS accuracy: mostly - we also do cluster detection - points should &quot;snap&quot; not drift in a perfect world. When you se things in weird places, it generally means: 1. they were reported there, improbable though it may be 2. they're PRECISELY POISED between two clusters, or have a very small number of observations. 3. they haven't been seen in a while and were last trilaterated before cluster detection was implemented.Perfect explanation -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11806#p11806</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11806#p11806</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:17:29</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Increasing accuracy after scan: Does accuracy get improved by other users observations? -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11805#p11805</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11805#p11805</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-08-02T10:13:38</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>