<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Has anyone run WiGLE inside the windows 11 android subsystem?: I was afraid of that. Thanks for responding.redactleIt's the first time I've tried to launch WiGLE within the Windows 11 Android emulation layer.And does it work well? -ragfighting</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11655#p11655</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11655#p11655</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-04-26T07:15:59</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Best Android for WigleWifi: Any suggestions on Samsung A73? I'm thinking of buying it and wodering how much hours can it spend while using wiglewifi.GBWhatsApp APK -Monicana</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11650#p11650</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11650#p11650</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-04-20T06:54:18</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pwnagotchi plugin: Using the pwnagotchi is what got me back into messing around with WiFi. I'm currently experimenting with the plugin; it's possible it may only send files with associated location data. I'm not sure yet. This might be why *I* can't get it to work either. I'll bring this up with a few people over the next week and get some feedback. There have been a number of interesting recent developments regarding the Pwnagotchi. https://github.com/DrSchottky/pwnagotchi https://github.com/aluminum-ice/nexmon-pi-zero-2w 1.) Aluminum-Ice has been working with DrSchottky on an update to the nexmon drivers for the raspberry Pi Zero 2W. This will improve the hardware behavior to more closely match what is expected. This work is not finished yet, and a &quot;1.7.0&quot; build is expected to be released int he near future with all of the changes finally rolled into one image (including Waveshare v3 support!). Aluminum-Ice has been doing most of the work, with the good doctor helping with the nexmon update. For the time being, the build that works for me (isn't blind to WiFi) on my Zero 2W is here-includes all he nexmon fixes up until last year: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QBCgTC ... share_link As I only use a Pi Zero 2W for my Pwnagotchi now, this is a big deal. The added speed of the 2W compared to the 1W is immediately noticeable. 2.) There has been a fix posted to reddit related to pwnagotchi locality not being set properly and therefore being limited to the channels available to whatever region the device is set to. It's basically a matter of changing your country/region code in console. See here: https://www.reddit.com/r/pwnagotchi/com ... de_the_us/ There is also active discussion going on in the Unofficial Pwnagotchi discord which is posted on the subreddit. Hope this helps someone since the information seems so scattered. -BPinard</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11644#p11644</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11644#p11644</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-04-18T01:28:18</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Kismet drone on wireless router?: Update: I gave up on trying to get 20y old hardware running with 10y old software... penalty kick online However, I'm still looking for Kismet drone options with a price tag in the lower two digits, i.e. comparable to a Raspberry Pi plus wifi adapter. And while the Pi would definititely be an option, I'd naively assume that hardware specialized in radio communication might be more sensitive, e.g. a wireless router. Can anybody shed some light on whether this assumption is naive or actually true, possibly even with some hardware recommendation? Thanks.I think it was the right decision. Radio communication will connect much easier and more stable. -achooibm</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11642#p11642</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11642#p11642</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-04-18T01:21:14</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Desktop software to view observations ?: You can also turn on Settings &amp;gt; Map Settings &amp;gt; Log routes for execution, and then use the Database &amp;gt; Saved Routes screen to export GPX to export files that can be viewed in a variety of GPX apps on the desktop. -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11610#p11610</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11610#p11610</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-16T01:43:31</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Has anyone run WiGLE inside the windows 11 android subsystem?: I was afraid of that. Thanks for responding. slope gameIt's the first time I've tried to launch WiGLE within the Windows 11 Android emulation layer. -achooibm</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11592#p11592</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11592#p11592</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-09T07:44:24</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: How to delete wigle data collected in certain time frame: Assuming you mean data stored on your local phone/device, you can erase all data on the &quot;Database&quot; item in the 3-horizontal-lines &quot;hamburger&quot; menu. On the &quot;Database&quot; screen scroll to the bottom and you can click &quot;CLEAR DB&quot; to erase all locally-stored data. If you want to be more surgical and really just remove a certain timeframe you would need to export the local sqlite database the app is using, either with android development tools or the &quot;BACKUP DATABASE&quot; button on the &quot;Database&quot; screen. Then use an sqlite database editor to remove the records you no longer want, and then put that file back on your device with android development tools. -bobzilla</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11590#p11590</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11590#p11590</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-08T15:42:04</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Desktop software to view observations ?: That's not what you asked but here is a solution to your problem. I have made a simple python script that convert a wigle csv file to a kml or gpx file. Then, you can use google maps to visualize the resulting kml file, or any gpx viewer like gpxsee to visualize the resulting gpx file. -zebul666</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11589#p11589</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11589#p11589</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-08T01:35:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>How to delete wigle data collected in certain time frame: title -R5ph4</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11588#p11588</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11588#p11588</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-07T18:58:00</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Should I merge database from different phones or keep them seperate ?: merging databases will slow performance - bigger databases are slower. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11582#p11582</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11582#p11582</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-02T01:34:47</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: What is &amp;quot;Maxout DB Marker&amp;quot; in Android App ?: it sets the last-uploaded marker to the end of the list - you can use this to skip uploading things in your database -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11581#p11581</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11581#p11581</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-02T01:33:40</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pwnagotchi plugin: Sorry - we're not the maintainers of the pwnagotchi - you'll have to use the information on your device and in their source repository to debug. By all means, please post findings here! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11580#p11580</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11580#p11580</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-01T23:33:19</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pwnagotchi plugin: I would imagine the same advice as above applies - check your uploads page and see if the pwnagotchi is sending files (correlate it with the logs on your pwnagotchi).As i said everything shows it being sent but nothing in my uploads. -wpa3</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11579#p11579</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11579#p11579</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-01T17:45:18</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pwnagotchi plugin: I would imagine the same advice as above applies - check your uploads page and see if the pwnagotchi is sending files (correlate it with the logs on your pwnagotchi). -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11578#p11578</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11578#p11578</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-01T17:33:53</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Pwnagotchi plugin: looking at https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotch ... gle.py#L84, it looks like it expects the &quot;Encoded for use&quot; value from your https://wigle.net/account page This is probably uploading anonymously by default.Thats a shame i have since changed to the Encoded for use value is there anyway to check things are getting uploaded then? I guess it would be better to change the value in the script. -wpa3</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11577#p11577</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11577#p11577</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-03-01T17:06:07</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>