<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Net Hugging Hardware and Software (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Soft for collecting full beacon frames: check out kismet (https://www.kismetwireless.net/) They're pretty darn good at that.Yes, this is what I need, it remains only to master that and screw the hardware)) -wauzzz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12010#p12010</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12010#p12010</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-13T16:50:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Soft for collecting full beacon frames: check out kismet (https://www.kismetwireless.net/) They're pretty darn good at that. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12007#p12007</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12007#p12007</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-12T16:01:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Soft for collecting full beacon frames: is there a software that collects complete beacon frames as seen by wireshark on wifi card at monitor mode only with geodata also? -wauzzz</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12006#p12006</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12006#p12006</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-12T11:28:18</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Master list of WiFi AuthMODES?: Yep AuthMode is the thing! Working on the AtomGPS with Luke and trying to homogenize various approaches and naming. Will take a closer look at your info, thanks! -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11992#p11992</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11992#p11992</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-02T03:20:39</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Master list of WiFi AuthTypes?: A couple of things: 1. there is no AuthType field - I think you mean AuthMode? 2. There is not a master list, nor is there likely to be: per https://api.wigle.net/csvFormat.html and https://api.wigle.net/csvFormat-1_6.html: https://developer.android.com/reference ... pabilities describes but does not enumerate the accepted values. https://github.com/wiglenet/wigle-wifi- ... java#L193 (the whole file, but that's how we decide which icon to show) shows you how we use the values client-side -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11991#p11991</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11991#p11991</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-02T03:06:26</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Master list of WiFi AuthTypes?: Hi guys, I asked privately and then thought to search the Board, but found nothing. Q: Is there a list of ‘standard’ naming for AuthType entries that Wigle expects or tolerates for inputs in the wigle.csv? Comparing code from JHewitt, LyndLabs, and other efforts there are some variations and also some items in &amp;lt;wifi.h&amp;gt; that aren’t in anyone's code yet. I have browsed the WigleWiFi Android app GIT but am not smart enough to find the fountain of truth. Any pointers? And so as to not be obtuse, this is the stuff I'm talking about: const char* getAuthType(uint8_t wifiAuth) { switch (wifiAuth) { case WIFI_AUTH_OPEN: return &quot;[OPEN]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WEP: return &quot;[WEP]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA_PSK: return &quot;[WPA_PSK]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA2_PSK: return &quot;[WPA2_PSK]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA_WPA2_PSK: return &quot;[WPA_WPA2_PSK]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA2_ENTERPRISE: return &quot;[WPA2_ENTERPRISE]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA3_PSK: return &quot;[WPA3_PSK]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WPA2_WPA3_PSK: return &quot;[WPA2_WPA3_PSK]&quot;; case WIFI_AUTH_WAPI_PSK: return &quot;[WAPI_PSK]&quot;; default: return &quot;[UNDEFINED]&quot;; } -pejacoby</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11990#p11990</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11990#p11990</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-01-02T02:23:17</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Need advice on building a full spectrum wifi wardriving rig: Howdy! I'm a long time lurker but noob War Driving Grey Hat Shenanigans causing script kiddy if you will and I'm recieving my first WiFi Pineapple monday and I was wondering if anyone could/would give me any advice on how best to utilize it along with my phone and pc. I know that I can hook up the pineapple to my phone so it'll have GPS attatched to the data, and as I plan on doing my War Driving while riding the bus to no particular place I was wanting advice/tips/fun things to do with my new hardware -baker.techie</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11981#p11981</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11981#p11981</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-27T14:56:11</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Car antenna mount position suggestions?: The 7dB directional antenna with a magnetic base can be mounted on the roof of the vehicle for optimal performance and signal reception. Quick Draw -polinkuer12</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11973#p11973</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11973#p11973</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-24T03:47:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Incentivization of infrequently visited tiles: I use an app called &quot;Fog of World&quot; to keep track of where I have previously been. It can be set to use a &quot;fog of war&quot; opaqueness effect to areas of the map that haven't been &quot;discovered&quot;. It's been fun riding around places I still haven't been to in over 15 years of living in my city! I use it on my iPhone (https://itunes.apple.com/app/fog-of-world/id505367096) as there are no wardriving apps for iOS, but it's also available on the Google Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/deta ... fogofworld -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11959#p11959</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11959#p11959</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-09T04:59:02</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Wigle Wifi Wardriving for Android: The benevolent bobzilla has released version 2.82 of Wigle Wifi Wardriving for Android. Changelog entry: * 2.81 - 2.82 (11/28/2023) Bluetooth is now in text-to-speech Roaming Consortium ID's added to local DB and file upload (thanks MarkG!) Added GNSS full tracking option (impacts battery, use with power source) Upload file at 1.6 version with UTF-8 support Distance now shown on list view Refactor DB search fragments Silence notification sounds Various bug fixes Thanks for your past and continuing hard work. I often think about all the old android phones that would be e-waste if they weren't part of someone's wardriving setup, so I really appreciate the compatibility with older models which are naturally easier to find in electronic graveyards and dormant collections. -computerb0y</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11958#p11958</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11958#p11958</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-12-09T04:30:58</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: File Formats: KML vs CSV vs Magic8Ball vs SQLite: KML commonly used for visualizing spatial data such as maps, 3D models, and other geospatial information. CSV is a plain text file that separates values with commas and lines with newlines. CSV files can be easily opened and edited in a text editor or spreadsheet program. getting over it SQLite is commonly used in mobile apps, web browsers, and other applications that require a lightweight, file-based database system. -DeshaunBruen</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11936#p11936</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11936#p11936</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-26T10:35:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Need advice on building a full spectrum wifi wardriving rig: Does Vistumbler allow for this? Why can't I just plug in two USB Wifi adapters and let Vistumbler do the rest? -pretenda</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11909#p11909</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11909#p11909</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-08T00:47:32</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Hak5 WiFi Coconut: Yah I'm super curious on this also. How can I get Vistumbler to get more APs with Hak5 technology? Is it just as easy as plug it in and drive away? -pretenda</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11908#p11908</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11908#p11908</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-08T00:01:22</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: File Formats: KML vs CSV vs Magic8Ball vs SQLite: Kml is keyhole markup language it's kinda like xml it's the format that Googlemaps uses Csv comma separated values is kinda the standard for transferring data between different databases and spreadsheets. You can view this one alot of different ways as is in a text editor in most spreadsheet programs excel ,Google sheets ,libre office calc idk what apple uses but that to or it can be uploaded natively into many SQL databases Magic8ball idk I'll look it up ok wiggle made kinda location anomyzor so exact location and exact time are not displayed I'm not 100%on this Sqlite3 least I assume it's 3 is a on disk or embedded db so there is no server it's just a file like another but you can use SQL language to search it and do other things -Space-$hoot088</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11901#p11901</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11901#p11901</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-11-02T11:04:03</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: My RPi Setup: Looks like the wardriving mode docs for Kismet moved - https://www.kismetwireless.net/docs/rea ... /wardrive/ is the new locationNearly a year on, hows the rig and your goals coming along? -HolidayGuy</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11877#p11877</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=11877#p11877</guid>
        <pubDate>2023-09-25T14:52:17</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>