<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>WiGLE News (via bkil-bot)</title>
      <item>
        <title>Re: Wigle Database: [quote=TZz222zZT post_id=12127 time=1709882428 user_id=340020] Its my understanding that &quot;first seen&quot; takes priority. They timestamp &quot;first seen&quot; details on the the first upload whenever. [/quote] I'm pretty sure the first seen name is the first upload of the BSSID online. Not the date of the scan. Otherwise you would be able to get your account deleted over stupid stats on a scoreboard that most people don't care about. The local DB is just that...local. I don't understand the Samsung question. Make sure to disable the wifi scan restriction in developer options. Tap the build number in about phone 10 times to enable the menu. I have an old phone hanging by its micro usb cable from my rearview mirror and plugged into the car. Another goes in a pouch in my bike bag with a battery. To login on the mobile you have to use the qr code available on the api tab of the hamburger on the web. -i_do_dew</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12192#p12192</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12192#p12192</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-04-21T21:10:08</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Wigle Database: Its my understanding that &quot;first seen&quot; takes priority. They timestamp &quot;first seen&quot; details on the the first upload whenever that upload might occur. Thats what shows aswell in the DB but all I know is they also store subsequent uploads but the first seen &quot;first seen&quot; which is the primary reference point for the database. Hopefully thats what you meant. Have any tips for someone new to Samsung Galaxy btw?hah. Im used to Motorola. Im curious given we started arpund the same time, how much time do you put into wardriving if you dont mind me asking. Thanks! tz222zt -TZz222zZT</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12127#p12127</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12127#p12127</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-08T07:20:28</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Wigle Database: How does the wigle database process files? Is this first seen or first uploaded? What takes priority? -toothpaste</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12126#p12126</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=12126#p12126</guid>
        <pubDate>2024-03-08T04:23:12</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Vs 2.59 Distances on maps: There are a lot of different ways folks use the application, but we've been focusing on making that view more self-contained for drivers and pedestrians who want to use the app from the Map screen - adding distance travelled means not having to switch to the dashboard. This change is intended to work in conjunction with the show-route functionality when making sure an area has been covered successfully. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10700#p10700</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10700#p10700</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-11-27T21:36:33</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Vs 2.59 Distances on maps: Thanks -Citro1</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10699#p10699</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10699#p10699</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-11-27T20:50:23</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Vs 2.59 Distances on maps: that distance travelled since the application has been launched, not distance to any particular network! Cheers, -Ark -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10698#p10698</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10698#p10698</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-11-25T17:27:28</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Vs 2.59 Distances on maps: Hello, What distance to which network is meant? For example, my map says 9.9ft -Citro1</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10697#p10697</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10697#p10697</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-11-25T15:42:56</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Golang API wrapper v0.1.0 WiGoLE: awesome! can't wait to see what people build with it! cheers! -ark -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10539#p10539</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10539#p10539</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-04-07T00:02:40</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Golang API wrapper v0.1.0 WiGoLE: I've created a wrapper for the API in Golang for anyone interested in using the API programmatically. Currently, everything should be implemented properly except for /api/v2/file/*. Check it out here: https://gitlab.com/MicahParks/wigole See the examples here: https://gitlab.com/MicahParks/wigole/-/ ... r/examples -botsarehots</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10538#p10538</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10538#p10538</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-04-05T17:28:11</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Settings? We've heard of them.: aw, thanks! no stress, but we're happy to post if you have time. the problem is that the bounds for the image map will change in each language. honestly, if you have spare time, please help fix our translations in WiGLE Wireless for Android - there's a lot of Google translate in there! thanks! -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10478#p10478</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10478#p10478</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-31T20:08:16</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Settings? We've heard of them.: I'll see what I can do for Russian and French, although I don't promise a full translation, as that's something that will either take time or a full time job. -OliVDB</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10476#p10476</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10476#p10476</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-31T19:21:19</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Settings? We've heard of them.: her you go: https://wigle.net/wiwi_settings - the main settings panel annotated. Now, to translate it into the 31 other languages we support... anyone got free time? -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10456#p10456</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10456#p10456</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-08T17:45:05</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Android Pie and WiGLE - news articles about scan-throttling: I have a preference for Motorola phones: Cheap. Here's a page describing which Moto phones will be getting Android Pie. What with the scan-throttling behavior of Pie, I figure I'm going to have to collect a group of Android wardriving-capable phones which are guaranteed NOT to &quot;upgrade&quot; to Pie. I just bought a used Moto G5 Plus, and will run it today. I want to get at least one more phone, since I have learned that when running two phones simultaneously, I tend to get an additional 50% more Wifis. I also intend to post the WiFi scan rate of each phone I try. Jim Bell https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/Moto-E5-Mo ... -p/4174913 ------------------------------------------------------------- &quot;Motorola lists all devices receiving Android Pie 9 &quot;‎08-15-2018 12:16 PM Article at AndroidPolice about Android Pie 9.0 and Motorola commitment to updates (pay attention to the last paragraph). After reading, go to the site and check the comment section to see the reaction of users &quot;EDIT: Now we discovered Motorola's schedule: updates after 1 year just to top devices. Medium or low end devices have support only for 12 months, or no support at all (support I mean receiving a new version of Android, not only just security patches). In regarding to the E5, a phone released only a few months, you all will be delighted to discover you won't receive a single update at all... _________________________________ &quot; While Android Pie rolls out to phones from Google and Essential, most OEMs haven't announced which devices will receive the update. HTC revealed a few days ago which of its phones are being updated, and now it's Motorola's turn. &quot;Motorola's long-term software support has deteriorated quite a bit over the past few years, so it shouldn't come as a surprise that the list of Moto phones receiving Android Pie is short. In fact, only eight phones will get the update: moto z3 moto z3 play moto z2 force edition moto z2 play moto x4 moto g6 plus moto g6 moto g6 play &quot;The list notably doesn't include any Moto E phones, even the E5 line that launched a few months ago. The entire Moto G5 family is also missing, even the G5S and G5S Plus - which launched one year ago. Source: Motorola -32894156</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10455#p10455</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10455#p10455</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-07T21:25:41</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Settings? We've heard of them.: if you're an english speaker, these two crazy folks did a talk about us at def con a few years ago - it details a lot of stuff about the app: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fSsTgazmHCw -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10453#p10453</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10453#p10453</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-05T01:16:08</pubDate>
      </item><item>
        <title>Re: Settings? We've heard of them.: that's a good point! the app has grown organically over the years - and it continues to change with each release (including the settings page). Even as a maintainer, sometimes I see the settings page in other languages and go through some cognitive dissonance. does anyone know of a good, dynamic documentation system for mobile apps? we are a small team, and we maintain WiGLE in our free time as a hobby - this means that maintaining docs and tutorials in our already limited time would decrease the number of bugfixes and enhancements we'd have time to work on. -arkasha</title>
        <link>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10452#p10452</link>
        <guid>https://wigle.net/phpbb/viewtopic.php?p=10452#p10452</guid>
        <pubDate>2020-01-05T01:13:51</pubDate>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>